<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> 
<crossway-bible>
	<book title="2 Chronicles" num="13">
		<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14026001">
		</marker>
		<chapter num="26">
			<heading
				>
				Uzziah Reigns in Judah
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="1">
				And all the people of Judah took Uzziah, who was sixteen years old, and made him king instead of his father Amaziah.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14026002">
			</marker>
			<verse num="2">
				He built Eloth and restored it to Judah, after the king slept with his fathers.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14026003">
			</marker>
			<verse num="3">
				Uzziah was 
				<crossref let="e" cid="c14026003.1">
				</crossref>
				sixteen years old when he began to reign, and he reigned fifty-two years in Jerusalem. His mother's name was Jecoliah of Jerusalem.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14026004">
			</marker>
			<verse num="4">
				And he did what was right in the eyes of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				, according to all that his father Amaziah had done.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14026005">
			</marker>
			<verse num="5">
				He set himself to seek God 
				<crossref let="f" cid="c14026005.1">
				</crossref>
				in the days of Zechariah, 
				<crossref let="g" cid="c14026005.2">
				</crossref>
				who instructed him in the fear of God, and as long as he sought the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				, God made him prosper.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14026006">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="6">
				He went out and 
				<crossref let="h" cid="c14026006.1">
				</crossref>
				made war against the Philistines and broke through the wall of Gath and the wall of Jabneh and the wall of Ashdod, and he built cities in the territory of Ashdod and elsewhere among the Philistines.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14026007">
			</marker>
			<verse num="7">
				God helped him 
				<crossref let="i" cid="c14026007.1">
				</crossref>
				against the Philistines and against the Arabians who lived in Gurbaal and against the 
				<crossref let="j" cid="c14026007.2">
				</crossref>
				Meunites.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14026008">
			</marker>
			<verse num="8">
				The Ammonites 
				<crossref let="k" cid="c14026008.1">
				</crossref>
				paid tribute to Uzziah, and his fame spread even to the border of Egypt, for he became very strong.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14026009">
			</marker>
			<verse num="9">
				Moreover, Uzziah built towers in Jerusalem at 
				<crossref let="l" cid="c14026009.1">
				</crossref>
				the Corner Gate and at 
				<crossref let="m" cid="c14026009.2">
				</crossref>
				the Valley Gate and at 
				<crossref let="n" cid="c14026009.3">
				</crossref>
				the Angle, and fortified them.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14026010">
			</marker>
			<verse num="10">
				And he built towers in the wilderness and 
				<crossref let="o" cid="c14026010.1">
				</crossref>
				cut out many cisterns, for he had large herds, both in the Shephelah and in the plain, and he had farmers and vinedressers in the hills and in the fertile lands, for he loved the soil.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14026011">
			</marker>
			<verse num="11">
				Moreover, Uzziah had an army of soldiers, fit for war, in divisions according to the numbers in the muster made by Jeiel the secretary and Maaseiah the officer, under the direction of Hananiah, one of the king's commanders.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14026012">
			</marker>
			<verse num="12">
				The whole number of the heads of fathers' houses of mighty men of valor was 2,600.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14026013">
			</marker>
			<verse num="13">
				Under their command was an army of 
				<crossref let="p" cid="c14026013.1">
				</crossref>
				307,500, who could make war with mighty power, to help the king against the enemy.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14026014">
			</marker>
			<verse num="14">
				And Uzziah prepared for all the army shields, spears, helmets, 
				<crossref let="q" cid="c14026014.1">
				</crossref>
				coats of mail, bows, and stones for slinging.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14026015">
			</marker>
			<verse num="15">
				In Jerusalem he made engines, invented by skillful men, to be on the towers and the corners, to shoot arrows and great stones. And his fame spread far, for he was marvelously helped, till he was strong.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14026016">
			</marker>
			<heading
				>
				Uzziah's Pride and Punishment
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="16">
				But when 
				<crossref let="r" cid="c14026016.1">
				</crossref>
				he was strong, 
				<crossref let="s" cid="c14026016.2">
				</crossref>
				he grew proud, to his destruction. For he was unfaithful to the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 his God and entered the temple of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 to burn incense on the altar of incense.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14026017">
			</marker>
			<verse num="17">
				But 
				<crossref let="t" cid="c14026017.1">
				</crossref>
				Azariah the priest went in after him, with eighty priests of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 who were men of valor,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14026018">
			</marker>
			<verse num="18">
				and they withstood King Uzziah and said to him, 
				<crossref let="u" cid="c14026018.1">
				</crossref>
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				It is not for you, Uzziah, to burn incense to the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				, 
				<crossref let="v" cid="c14026018.2">
				</crossref>
				but for the priests, the sons of Aaron, who are consecrated to burn incense. Go out of the sanctuary, for you have done wrong, and it will bring you no honor from the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 God.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14026019">
			</marker>
			<verse num="19">
				Then Uzziah was angry. Now he had a censer in his hand to burn incense, and when he became angry with the priests, 
				<crossref let="w" cid="c14026019.1">
				</crossref>
				leprosy
				<note nid="n14026019.1">
				</note>
				 broke out on his forehead in the presence of the priests in the house of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				, by the altar of incense.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14026020">
			</marker>
			<verse num="20">
				And Azariah the chief priest and all the priests looked at him, and behold, he was leprous in his forehead! And they rushed him out quickly, and he himself hurried to go out, because the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 had struck him.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14026021">
			</marker>
			<verse num="21">
				<crossref let="x" cid="c14026021.1">
				</crossref>
				And King Uzziah was a leper to the day of his death, and being a leper lived 
				<crossref let="y" cid="c14026021.2">
				</crossref>
				in a separate house, for he was excluded from the house of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				. And Jotham his son was over the king's household, governing the people of the land.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14026022">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="22">
				Now the rest of the acts of Uzziah, from first to last, 
				<crossref let="z" cid="c14026022.1">
				</crossref>
				Isaiah the prophet the son of Amoz wrote.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14026023">
			</marker>
			<verse num="23">
				And Uzziah slept with his fathers, and they buried him with his fathers in the burial field that belonged to the kings, for they said, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				He is a leper.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				 And Jotham his son reigned in his place.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
		</chapter>
	</book>
</crossway-bible>


