<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> 
<crossway-bible>
	<book title="1 Chronicles" num="12">
		<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13026001">
		</marker>
		<chapter num="26">
			<heading
				>
				Divisions of the Gatekeepers
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="1">
				As for the divisions of the gatekeepers: of the Korahites, Meshelemiah the son of Kore, of the sons of Asaph.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13026002">
			</marker>
			<verse num="2">
				And Meshelemiah had sons: 
				<crossref let="g" cid="c13026002.1">
				</crossref>
				Zechariah the firstborn, Jediael the second, Zebadiah the third, Jathniel the fourth,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13026003">
			</marker>
			<verse num="3">
				Elam the fifth, Jehohanan the sixth, Eliehoenai the seventh.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13026004">
			</marker>
			<verse num="4">
				And 
				<crossref let="h" cid="c13026004.1">
				</crossref>
				Obed-edom had sons: Shemaiah the firstborn, Jehozabad the second, Joah the third, Sachar the fourth, Nethanel the fifth,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13026005">
			</marker>
			<verse num="5">
				Ammiel the sixth, Issachar the seventh, Peullethai the eighth, 
				<crossref let="i" cid="c13026005.1">
				</crossref>
				for God blessed him.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13026006">
			</marker>
			<verse num="6">
				Also to his son Shemaiah were sons born who were rulers in their fathers' houses, for they were men of great ability.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13026007">
			</marker>
			<verse num="7">
				The sons of Shemaiah: Othni, Rephael, Obed and Elzabad, whose brothers were able men, Elihu and Semachiah.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13026008">
			</marker>
			<verse num="8">
				All these were of the sons of Obed-edom with their sons and brothers, able men qualified for the service; sixty-two of Obed-edom.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13026009">
			</marker>
			<verse num="9">
				And Meshelemiah had sons and brothers, able men, eighteen.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13026010">
			</marker>
			<verse num="10">
				And 
				<crossref let="j" cid="c13026010.1">
				</crossref>
				Hosah, of the sons of Merari, had sons: Shimri the chief (for though he was not the firstborn, his father made him chief),
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13026011">
			</marker>
			<verse num="11">
				Hilkiah the second, Tebaliah the third, Zechariah the fourth: all the sons and brothers of Hosah were thirteen.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13026012">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="12">
				These divisions of the gatekeepers, corresponding to their chief men, had duties, just as their brothers did, ministering in the house of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13026013">
			</marker>
			<verse num="13">
				And they cast lots by fathers' houses, 
				<crossref let="k" cid="c13026013.1">
				</crossref>
				small and great alike, for their gates.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13026014">
			</marker>
			<verse num="14">
				The lot for the east fell to Shelemiah. They cast lots also for his son Zechariah, a shrewd counselor, and his lot came out for the north.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13026015">
			</marker>
			<verse num="15">
				Obed-edom's came out for the south, and to his sons was allotted 
				<crossref let="l" cid="c13026015.1">
				</crossref>
				the gatehouse.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13026016">
			</marker>
			<verse num="16">
				For Shuppim and 
				<crossref let="j" cid="c13026016.1">
				</crossref>
				Hosah it came out for the west, at the gate of Shallecheth on the road that goes up. Watch corresponded to watch.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13026017">
			</marker>
			<verse num="17">
				On the east there were six each day,
				<note nid="n13026017.1">
				</note>
				 on the north four each day, on the south four each day, as well as two and two at the gatehouse.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13026018">
			</marker>
			<verse num="18">
				And for the 
				<crossref let="n" cid="c13026018.1">
				</crossref>
				colonnade
				<note nid="n13026018.1">
				</note>
				 on the west there were four at the road and two at the colonnade.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13026019">
			</marker>
			<verse num="19">
				These were the divisions of the gatekeepers among the Korahites and the sons of Merari.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13026020">
			</marker>
			<heading
				>
				Treasurers and Other Officials
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="20">
				And of the Levites, Ahijah had charge of 
				<crossref let="o" cid="c13026020.1">
				</crossref>
				the treasuries of the house of God and the treasuries of the dedicated gifts.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13026021">
			</marker>
			<verse num="21">
				The sons of Ladan, the sons of the Gershonites belonging to Ladan, the heads of the fathers' houses belonging to Ladan the Gershonite: 
				<crossref let="p" cid="c13026021.1">
				</crossref>
				Jehieli.
				<note nid="n13026021.1">
				</note>
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13026022">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="22">
				<crossref let="q" cid="c13026022.1">
				</crossref>
				The sons of Jehieli, Zetham, and Joel his brother, were in charge of the treasuries of the house of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13026023">
			</marker>
			<verse num="23">
				<crossref let="r" cid="c13026023.1">
				</crossref>
				Of the Amramites, the Izharites, the Hebronites, and the Uzzielitesù
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13026024">
			</marker>
			<verse num="24">
				and 
				<crossref let="s" cid="c13026024.1">
				</crossref>
				Shebuel the son of Gershom, son of Moses, was chief officer in charge of the treasuries.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13026025">
			</marker>
			<verse num="25">
				His brothers: from 
				<crossref let="t" cid="c13026025.1">
				</crossref>
				Eliezer were his son Rehabiah, and his son 
				<crossref let="u" cid="c13026025.2">
				</crossref>
				Jeshaiah, and his son Joram, and his son Zichri, and his son 
				<crossref let="v" cid="c13026025.3">
				</crossref>
				Shelomoth.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13026026">
			</marker>
			<verse num="26">
				This Shelomoth and his brothers were in charge of all the treasuries of the dedicated gifts that David the king and the heads of the fathers' houses and the officers of the thousands and the hundreds and the commanders of the army 
				<crossref let="w" cid="c13026026.1">
				</crossref>
				had dedicated.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13026027">
			</marker>
			<verse num="27">
				From spoil won in battles they dedicated gifts for the maintenance of the house of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13026028">
			</marker>
			<verse num="28">
				Also all that 
				<crossref let="x" cid="c13026028.1">
				</crossref>
				Samuel the seer and Saul the son of Kish and Abner the son of Ner and Joab the son of Zeruiah had dedicatedùall dedicated gifts were in the care of 
				<crossref let="v" cid="c13026028.2">
				</crossref>
				Shelomoth
				<note nid="n13026028.1">
				</note>
				 and his brothers.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13026029">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="29">
				Of the Izharites, Chenaniah and his sons were appointed to 
				<crossref let="y" cid="c13026029.1">
				</crossref>
				external duties for Israel, 
				<crossref let="z" cid="c13026029.2">
				</crossref>
				as officers and judges.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13026030">
			</marker>
			<verse num="30">
				Of the Hebronites, 
				<crossref let="a" cid="c13026030.1">
				</crossref>
				Hashabiah and his brothers, 1,700 men of ability, had the oversight of Israel westward of the Jordan for all the work of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 and for the service of the king.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13026031">
			</marker>
			<verse num="31">
				Of the Hebronites, 
				<crossref let="b" cid="c13026031.1">
				</crossref>
				Jerijah was chief of the Hebronites of whatever genealogy or fathers' houses. (In the fortieth year of David's reign search was made and men of great ability among them were found at 
				<crossref let="c" cid="c13026031.2">
				</crossref>
				Jazer in Gilead.)
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13026032">
			</marker>
			<verse num="32">
				King David appointed him and his brothers, 2,700 men of ability, heads of fathers' houses, to have the oversight of the Reubenites, the Gadites and the half-tribe of the Manassites for everything pertaining to God and for 
				<crossref let="d" cid="c13026032.1">
				</crossref>
				the affairs of the king.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
		</chapter>
	</book>
</crossway-bible>


