<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> 
<crossway-bible>
	<book title="2 Chronicles" num="13">
		<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14035001">
		</marker>
		<chapter num="35">
			<heading
				>
				Josiah Keeps the Passover
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="1">
				<crossref let="g" cid="c14035001.1">
				</crossref>
				Josiah kept a Passover to the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 in Jerusalem. And they slaughtered the Passover lamb 
				<crossref let="h" cid="c14035001.2">
				</crossref>
				on the fourteenth day of the first month.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14035002">
			</marker>
			<verse num="2">
				He appointed the priests to their offices 
				<crossref let="i" cid="c14035002.1">
				</crossref>
				and encouraged them in the service of the house of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14035003">
			</marker>
			<verse num="3">
				And he said to the Levites 
				<crossref let="j" cid="c14035003.1">
				</crossref>
				who taught all Israel and who were holy to the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Put the holy ark in the house that Solomon the son of David, king of Israel, built. You need not carry it on your shoulders. Now serve the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 your God and his people Israel.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14035004">
			</marker>
			<verse num="4">
				Prepare yourselves 
				<crossref let="k" cid="c14035004.1">
				</crossref>
				according to your fathers' houses by your divisions, 
				<crossref let="l" cid="c14035004.2">
				</crossref>
				as prescribed in the writing of David king of Israel 
				<crossref let="m" cid="c14035004.3">
				</crossref>
				and the document of Solomon his son.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14035005">
			</marker>
			<verse num="5">
				And 
				<crossref let="n" cid="c14035005.1">
				</crossref>
				stand in the Holy Place 
				<crossref let="o" cid="c14035005.2">
				</crossref>
				according to the groupings of the fathers' houses of your brothers the lay people, and according to the division of the Levites by fathers' household.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14035006">
			</marker>
			<verse num="6">
				And slaughter the Passover lamb, and 
				<crossref let="p" cid="c14035006.1">
				</crossref>
				consecrate yourselves, and prepare for your brothers, to do according to the word of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 by Moses.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14035007">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="7">
				Then Josiah contributed to the lay people, as Passover offerings for all who were present, lambs and young goats from the flock to the number of 30,000, and 3,000 bulls; 
				<crossref let="q" cid="c14035007.1">
				</crossref>
				these were from the king's possessions.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14035008">
			</marker>
			<verse num="8">
				And his officials contributed willingly to the people, to the priests, and to the Levites. 
				<crossref let="r" cid="c14035008.1">
				</crossref>
				Hilkiah, Zechariah, and Jehiel, the chief officers of the house of God, gave to the priests for the Passover offerings 2,600 Passover lambs and 300 bulls.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14035009">
			</marker>
			<verse num="9">
				Conaniah also, and Shemaiah and Nethanel his brothers, and Hashabiah and Jeiel and Jozabad, the chiefs of the Levites, gave to the Levites for the Passover offerings 5,000 lambs and young goats and 500 bulls.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14035010">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="10">
				When the service had been prepared for, the priests 
				<crossref let="s" cid="c14035010.1">
				</crossref>
				stood in their place, 
				<crossref let="t" cid="c14035010.2">
				</crossref>
				and the Levites in their divisions according to the king's command.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14035011">
			</marker>
			<verse num="11">
				<crossref let="u" cid="c14035011.1">
				</crossref>
				And they slaughtered the Passover lamb, and the priests 
				<crossref let="v" cid="c14035011.2">
				</crossref>
				threw the blood that they received from them 
				<crossref let="w" cid="c14035011.3">
				</crossref>
				while the Levites flayed the sacrifices.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14035012">
			</marker>
			<verse num="12">
				And they set aside the burnt offerings that they might distribute them according to the groupings of the fathers' houses of the lay people, to offer to the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				, as it is written in the Book of Moses. And so they did with the bulls.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14035013">
			</marker>
			<verse num="13">
				<crossref let="x" cid="c14035013.1">
				</crossref>
				And they roasted the Passover lamb with fire according to the rule; and they 
				<crossref let="y" cid="c14035013.2">
				</crossref>
				boiled the holy offerings in pots, in cauldrons, and in pans, and carried them quickly to all the lay people.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14035014">
			</marker>
			<verse num="14">
				And afterward they prepared for themselves and for the priests, because the priests, the sons of Aaron, were offering the burnt offerings and the fat parts until night; so the Levites prepared for themselves and for the priests, the sons of Aaron.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14035015">
			</marker>
			<verse num="15">
				The singers, the sons of Asaph, were in their place 
				<crossref let="z" cid="c14035015.1">
				</crossref>
				according to the command of David, and Asaph, and Heman, and Jeduthun the king's 
				<crossref let="a" cid="c14035015.2">
				</crossref>
				seer; 
				<crossref let="b" cid="c14035015.3">
				</crossref>
				and the gatekeepers were at each gate. They did not need to depart from their service, for their brothers the Levites prepared for them.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14035016">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="16">
				So all the service of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 was prepared that day, to keep the Passover and to offer burnt offerings on the altar of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				, according to the command of King Josiah.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14035017">
			</marker>
			<verse num="17">
				And the people of Israel who were present kept the Passover at that time, 
				<crossref let="c" cid="c14035017.1">
				</crossref>
				and the Feast of Unleavened Bread seven days.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14035018">
			</marker>
			<verse num="18">
				<crossref let="d" cid="c14035018.1">
				</crossref>
				No Passover like it had been kept in Israel since the days of Samuel the prophet. None of the kings of Israel had kept such a Passover as was kept by Josiah, and the priests and the Levites, and all Judah and Israel who were present, and the inhabitants of Jerusalem.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14035019">
			</marker>
			<verse num="19">
				In the eighteenth year of the reign of Josiah this Passover was kept.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14035020">
			</marker>
			<heading
				>
				Josiah Killed in Battle
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="20">
				<crossref let="e" cid="c14035020.1">
				</crossref>
				After all this, when Josiah had prepared the temple, Neco king of Egypt went up to fight at 
				<crossref let="f" cid="c14035020.2">
				</crossref>
				Carchemish on the Euphrates, and Josiah went out to meet him.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14035021">
			</marker>
			<verse num="21">
				But he sent envoys to him, saying, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				What have we to do with each other, king of Judah? I am not coming against you this day, but against the house with which I am at war. And God has commanded me to hurry. Cease opposing God, who is with me, lest he destroy you.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14035022">
			</marker>
			<verse num="22">
				Nevertheless, Josiah did not turn away from him, but 
				<crossref let="g" cid="c14035022.1">
				</crossref>
				disguised himself in order to fight with him. He did not listen to the words of Neco from the mouth of God, but came to fight in the plain of 
				<crossref let="h" cid="c14035022.2">
				</crossref>
				Megiddo.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14035023">
			</marker>
			<verse num="23">
				And the archers shot King Josiah. And the king said to his servants, 
				<crossref let="i" cid="c14035023.1">
				</crossref>
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Take me away, for I am badly wounded.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14035024">
			</marker>
			<verse num="24">
				So his servants took him out of the chariot and carried him in his second chariot and brought him to Jerusalem. And he died and was buried in the tombs of his fathers. 
				<crossref let="j" cid="c14035024.1">
				</crossref>
				All Judah and Jerusalem mourned for Josiah.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14035025">
			</marker>
			<verse num="25">
				<crossref let="k" cid="c14035025.1">
				</crossref>
				Jeremiah also uttered a lament for Josiah; and all 
				<crossref let="l" cid="c14035025.2">
				</crossref>
				the singing men and singing women have spoken of Josiah in their laments to this day. They made these a rule in Israel; behold, they are written in the Laments.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14035026">
			</marker>
			<verse num="26">
				Now the rest of the acts of Josiah, and his good deeds according to what is written in the Law of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14035027">
			</marker>
			<verse num="27">
				and his acts, first and last, behold, they are written in the Book of the Kings of Israel and Judah.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
		</chapter>
	</book>
</crossway-bible>


