<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> 
<crossway-bible>
	<book title="1 Chronicles" num="12">
		<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13017001">
		</marker>
		<chapter num="17">
			<heading>
				The 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				's Covenant with David
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="1">
				<crossref let="t" cid="c13017001.1">
				</crossref>
				Now when David lived in his house, David said to Nathan the prophet, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Behold, I dwell in a house of cedar, but the ark of the covenant of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 is under a tent.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13017002">
			</marker>
			<verse num="2">
				And Nathan said to David, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Do all that is in your heart, for God is with you.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13017003">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="3">
				But that same night the word of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 came to Nathan,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13017004">
			</marker>
			<verse num="4">
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Go and tell my servant David, 
				<q class="begin-single" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Thus says the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				: 
				<crossref let="u" cid="c13017004.1">
				</crossref>
				It is not you who will build me a house to dwell in.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13017005">
			</marker>
			<verse num="5">
				For I have not lived in a house since the day I brought up Israel to this day, 
				<crossref let="v" cid="c13017005.1">
				</crossref>
				but I have gone from tent to tent and from dwelling to dwelling.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13017006">
			</marker>
			<verse num="6">
				In all places where I have moved with all Israel, did I speak a word with any of the judges of Israel, whom I commanded to shepherd my people, saying, 
				<q class="begin-inner-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Why have you not built me a house of cedar?
				<q class="end-inner-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				<q class="end-single" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13017007">
			</marker>
			<verse num="7">
				Now, therefore, thus shall you say to my servant David, 
				<q class="begin-single" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Thus says the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 of hosts, I took you from the pasture, from following the sheep, to be prince over my people Israel,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13017008">
			</marker>
			<verse num="8">
				and I have been with you wherever you have gone and have cut off all your enemies from before you. And I will make for you a name, like the name of the great ones of the earth.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13017009">
			</marker>
			<verse num="9">
				And I will appoint a place for my people Israel and will plant them, that they may dwell in their own place and be disturbed no more. And violent men shall waste them no more, as formerly,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13017010">
			</marker>
			<verse num="10">
				from the time that I appointed judges over my people Israel. And I 
				<crossref let="w" cid="c13017010.1">
				</crossref>
				will subdue all your enemies. Moreover, I declare to you that the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 will build you a house.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13017011">
			</marker>
			<verse num="11">
				When your days are fulfilled to walk with your fathers, I will raise up your offspring after you, one of your own sons, and I will establish his kingdom.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13017012">
			</marker>
			<verse num="12">
				He shall build a house for me, and I will establish his throne forever.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13017013">
			</marker>
			<verse num="13">
				<crossref let="x" cid="c13017013.1">
				</crossref>
				I will be to him a father, and he shall be to me a son. I will not take my steadfast love from him, 
				<crossref let="y" cid="c13017013.2">
				</crossref>
				as I took it from him who was before you,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13017014">
			</marker>
			<verse num="14">
				but I will confirm him in my house and in my kingdom forever, and his throne shall be established forever.
				<q class="end-single" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13017015">
			</marker>
			<verse num="15">
				In accordance with all these words, and in accordance with all this vision, Nathan spoke to David.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13017016">
			</marker>
			<heading>
				David's Prayer
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="16">
				Then King David went in and sat before the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 and said, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Who am I, O 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 God, and what is my house, that you have brought me thus far?
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13017017">
			</marker>
			<verse num="17">
				And this was a small thing in your eyes, O God. You have also spoken of your servant's house for a great while to come, and have shown me future generations,
				<note nid="n13017017.1">
				</note>
				 O 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 God!
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13017018">
			</marker>
			<verse num="18">
				And what more can David say to you for honoring your servant? For you know your servant.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13017019">
			</marker>
			<verse num="19">
				<crossref let="z" cid="c13017019.1">
				</crossref>
				For your servant's sake, O 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				, and according to your own heart, you have done all this greatness, in making known all these great things.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13017020">
			</marker>
			<verse num="20">
				There is none like you, O 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				, and there is no God besides you, according to all that we have heard with our ears.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13017021">
			</marker>
			<verse num="21">
				And who is like your people Israel, the one
				<note nid="n13017021.1">
				</note>
				 nation on earth whom God went to redeem to be his people, making for yourself a name for great and awesome things, in driving out nations before your people whom you redeemed from Egypt?
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13017022">
			</marker>
			<verse num="22">
				And you made your people Israel to be your people forever, and you, O 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				, became their God.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13017023">
			</marker>
			<verse num="23">
				And now, O 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				, let the word that you have spoken concerning your servant and concerning his house be established forever, and do as you have spoken,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13017024">
			</marker>
			<verse num="24">
				and your name will be established and magnified forever, saying, 
				<q class="begin-single" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				The 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 of hosts, the God of Israel, is Israel's God,
				<q class="end-single" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				 and the house of your servant David will be established before you.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13017025">
			</marker>
			<verse num="25">
				For you, my God, have revealed to your servant that you will build a house for him. Therefore your servant has found courage to pray before you.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13017026">
			</marker>
			<verse num="26">
				And now, O 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				, you are God, and you have promised this good thing to your servant.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13017027">
			</marker>
			<verse num="27">
				Now you have been pleased to bless the house of your servant, that it may continue forever before you, for it is you, O 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				, who have blessed, and it is blessed forever.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph>
			</end-paragraph>
		</chapter>
	</book>
</crossway-bible>


