<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> 
<crossway-bible>
	<book title="2 Chronicles" num="13">
		<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14032001">
		</marker>
		<chapter num="32">
			<heading
				>
				Sennacherib Invades Judah
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="1">
				<crossref let="i" cid="c14032001.1">
				</crossref>
				After these things and these acts of faithfulness, Sennacherib king of Assyria came and invaded Judah and encamped against the fortified cities, thinking to win them for himself.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14032002">
			</marker>
			<verse num="2">
				And when Hezekiah saw that Sennacherib had come and intended to fight against Jerusalem,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14032003">
			</marker>
			<verse num="3">
				he planned with his officers and his mighty men to stop the water of the springs that were outside the city; and they helped him.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14032004">
			</marker>
			<verse num="4">
				A great many people were gathered, and they stopped all the springs and 
				<crossref let="j" cid="c14032004.1">
				</crossref>
				the brook that flowed through the land, saying, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Why should the kings of Assyria come and find much water?
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14032005">
			</marker>
			<verse num="5">
				He set to work resolutely and built up 
				<crossref let="k" cid="c14032005.1">
				</crossref>
				all the wall that was broken down and raised towers upon it,
				<note nid="n14032005.1">
				</note>
				 and outside it he built another wall, and he strengthened the 
				<crossref let="l" cid="c14032005.2">
				</crossref>
				Millo in the city of David. He also made weapons and shields in abundance.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14032006">
			</marker>
			<verse num="6">
				And he set combat commanders over the people and gathered them together to him in the square at the gate of the city and spoke 
				<crossref let="m" cid="c14032006.1">
				</crossref>
				encouragingly to them, saying,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14032007">
			</marker>
			<verse num="7">
				<crossref let="n" cid="c14032007.1">
				</crossref>
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Be strong and courageous. 
				<crossref let="o" cid="c14032007.2">
				</crossref>
				Do not be afraid or dismayed before the king of Assyria and all the horde that is with him, 
				<crossref let="p" cid="c14032007.3">
				</crossref>
				for there are more with us than with him.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14032008">
			</marker>
			<verse num="8">
				With him is 
				<crossref let="q" cid="c14032008.1">
				</crossref>
				an arm of flesh, 
				<crossref let="r" cid="c14032008.2">
				</crossref>
				but with us is the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 our God, to help us and to fight our battles.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				 And the people took confidence from the words of Hezekiah king of Judah.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14032009">
			</marker>
			<heading
				>
				Sennacherib Blasphemes
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="9">
				After this, Sennacherib king of Assyria, who was besieging Lachish with all his forces, sent his servants to Jerusalem to Hezekiah king of Judah and to all the people of Judah who were in Jerusalem, saying,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14032010">
			</marker>
			<verse num="10">
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Thus says Sennacherib king of Assyria, 
				<q class="begin-single" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				On what are you trusting, that you endure the siege in Jerusalem?
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14032011">
			</marker>
			<verse num="11">
				Is not Hezekiah misleading you, that he may give you over to die by famine and by thirst, when he tells you, 
				<q class="begin-inner-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				The 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 our God will deliver us from the hand of the king of Assyria
				<q class="end-inner-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				?
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14032012">
			</marker>
			<verse num="12">
				<crossref let="s" cid="c14032012.1">
				</crossref>
				Has not this same Hezekiah taken away his high places and his altars and commanded Judah and Jerusalem, 
				<q class="begin-inner-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Before one altar you shall worship, and on it you shall burn your sacrifices
				<q class="end-inner-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				?
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14032013">
			</marker>
			<verse num="13">
				Do you not know what I and my fathers have done to all the peoples of other lands? Were the gods of the nations of those lands at all able to deliver their lands out of my hand?
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14032014">
			</marker>
			<verse num="14">
				Who among all the gods of those nations that my fathers devoted to destruction was able to deliver his people from my hand, that your God should be able to deliver you from my hand?
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14032015">
			</marker>
			<verse num="15">
				Now, therefore, do not let Hezekiah deceive you or mislead you in this fashion, and do not believe him, for no god of any nation or kingdom has been able to deliver his people from my hand or from the hand of my fathers. How much less will your God deliver you out of my hand!
				<q class="end-single" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14032016">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="16">
				And his servants said still more against the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 God and against his servant Hezekiah.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14032017">
			</marker>
			<verse num="17">
				And he wrote letters to cast contempt on the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				, the God of Israel, and to speak against him, saying, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Like the gods of the nations of the lands who have not delivered their people from my hands, so the God of Hezekiah will not deliver his people from my hand.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14032018">
			</marker>
			<verse num="18">
				And they shouted it with a loud voice in the language of Judah to the people of Jerusalem who were on the wall, to frighten and terrify them, in order that they might take the city.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14032019">
			</marker>
			<verse num="19">
				And they spoke of the God of Jerusalem as they spoke of the gods of the peoples of the earth, which are the work of men's hands.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14032020">
			</marker>
			<heading
				>
				The 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 Delivers Jerusalem
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="20">
				Then Hezekiah the king and Isaiah the prophet, the son of Amoz, prayed because of this and cried to heaven.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14032021">
			</marker>
			<verse num="21">
				And the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 sent an angel, who cut off all the mighty warriors and commanders and officers in the camp of the king of Assyria. So he returned with 
				<crossref let="t" cid="c14032021.1">
				</crossref>
				shame of face to his own land. And when he came into the house of his god, some of his own sons struck him down there with the sword.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14032022">
			</marker>
			<verse num="22">
				So the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 saved Hezekiah and the inhabitants of Jerusalem from the hand of Sennacherib king of Assyria and from the hand of all his enemies, and he provided for them on every side.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14032023">
			</marker>
			<verse num="23">
				And many 
				<crossref let="u" cid="c14032023.1">
				</crossref>
				brought gifts to the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 to Jerusalem and precious things to Hezekiah king of Judah, so that he was exalted in the sight of all nations from that time onward.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14032024">
			</marker>
			<heading
				>
				Hezekiah's Pride and Achievements
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="24">
				<crossref let="v" cid="c14032024.1">
				</crossref>
				In those days Hezekiah became sick and was at the point of death, and he prayed to the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				, and he answered him and gave him a sign.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14032025">
			</marker>
			<verse num="25">
				But Hezekiah 
				<crossref let="w" cid="c14032025.1">
				</crossref>
				did not make return according to the benefit done to him, for 
				<crossref let="x" cid="c14032025.2">
				</crossref>
				his heart was proud. Therefore 
				<crossref let="y" cid="c14032025.3">
				</crossref>
				wrath came upon him and Judah and Jerusalem.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14032026">
			</marker>
			<verse num="26">
				But Hezekiah 
				<crossref let="z" cid="c14032026.1">
				</crossref>
				humbled himself for the pride of his heart, both he and the inhabitants of Jerusalem, so that the wrath of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 did not come upon them in the days of Hezekiah.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14032027">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="27">
				And Hezekiah had very great riches and honor, and he made for himself treasuries for silver, for gold, for precious stones, for spices, for shields, and for all kinds of 
				<crossref let="a" cid="c14032027.1">
				</crossref>
				costly vessels;
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14032028">
			</marker>
			<verse num="28">
				storehouses also for the yield of grain, wine, and oil; and stalls for all kinds of cattle, and sheepfolds.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14032029">
			</marker>
			<verse num="29">
				He likewise provided cities for himself, and flocks and herds in abundance, for God had given him very great possessions.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14032030">
			</marker>
			<verse num="30">
				This same Hezekiah 
				<crossref let="b" cid="c14032030.1">
				</crossref>
				closed the upper outlet of the waters of 
				<crossref let="c" cid="c14032030.2">
				</crossref>
				Gihon and directed them down to the west side of the city of David. And Hezekiah prospered in all his works.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14032031">
			</marker>
			<verse num="31">
				And so in the matter of the envoys of the princes of Babylon, 
				<crossref let="d" cid="c14032031.1">
				</crossref>
				who had been sent to him to inquire about 
				<crossref let="e" cid="c14032031.2">
				</crossref>
				the sign that had been done in the land, God left him to himself, 
				<crossref let="f" cid="c14032031.3">
				</crossref>
				in order to test him and to know all that was in his heart.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14032032">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="32">
				Now the rest of the acts of Hezekiah and his good deeds, behold, they are written 
				<crossref let="g" cid="c14032032.1">
				</crossref>
				in the vision of Isaiah the prophet the son of Amoz, 
				<crossref let="h" cid="c14032032.2">
				</crossref>
				in the Book of the Kings of Judah and Israel.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14032033">
			</marker>
			<verse num="33">
				And Hezekiah slept with his fathers, and they buried him in the 
				<crossref let="i" cid="c14032033.1">
				</crossref>
				upper part of the tombs of the sons of David, and all Judah and the inhabitants of Jerusalem did him honor at his death. And Manasseh his son reigned in his place.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
		</chapter>
	</book>
</crossway-bible>


