<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> 
<crossway-bible>
	<book title="2 Chronicles" num="13">
		<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14027001">
		</marker>
		<chapter num="27">
			<heading
				>
				Jotham Reigns in Judah
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="1">
				<crossref let="a" cid="c14027001.1">
				</crossref>
				Jotham was twenty-five years old when he began to reign, and he reigned sixteen years in Jerusalem. His mother's name was Jerushah the daughter of Zadok.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14027002">
			</marker>
			<verse num="2">
				And he did what was right in the eyes of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 according to all that his father Uzziah had done, 
				<crossref let="b" cid="c14027002.1">
				</crossref>
				except he did not enter the temple of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				. But the people still followed corrupt practices.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14027003">
			</marker>
			<verse num="3">
				He built the upper gate of the house of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 and did much building on the wall of 
				<crossref let="c" cid="c14027003.1">
				</crossref>
				Ophel.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14027004">
			</marker>
			<verse num="4">
				Moreover, he built cities in the hill country of Judah, and forts and towers on the wooded hills.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14027005">
			</marker>
			<verse num="5">
				He fought with the king of the Ammonites and prevailed against them. And the Ammonites gave him that year 100 talents
				<note nid="n14027005.1">
				</note>
				 of silver, and 10,000 cors
				<note nid="n14027005.2">
				</note>
				 of wheat and 10,000 of barley. The Ammonites paid him the same amount in the second and the third years.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14027006">
			</marker>
			<verse num="6">
				So Jotham became mighty, because he ordered his ways before the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 his God.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14027007">
			</marker>
			<verse num="7">
				<crossref let="d" cid="c14027007.1">
				</crossref>
				Now the rest of the acts of Jotham, and all his wars and his ways, behold, they are written in the Book of the Kings of Israel and Judah.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14027008">
			</marker>
			<verse num="8">
				He was 
				<crossref let="e" cid="c14027008.1">
				</crossref>
				twenty-five years old when he began to reign, and he reigned sixteen years in Jerusalem.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14027009">
			</marker>
			<verse num="9">
				And Jotham slept with his fathers, and they buried him in the city of David, and Ahaz his son reigned in his place.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
		</chapter>
	</book>
</crossway-bible>


