<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> 
<crossway-bible>
	<book title="1 Chronicles" num="12">
		<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13025001">
		</marker>
		<chapter num="25">
			<heading
				>
				David Organizes the Musicians
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="1">
				David and the chiefs of the service also set apart for the service the sons of 
				<crossref let="y" cid="c13025001.1">
				</crossref>
				Asaph, and of 
				<crossref let="z" cid="c13025001.2">
				</crossref>
				Heman, and of 
				<crossref let="a" cid="c13025001.3">
				</crossref>
				Jeduthun, who 
				<crossref let="b" cid="c13025001.4">
				</crossref>
				prophesied with lyres, with 
				<crossref let="c" cid="c13025001.5">
				</crossref>
				harps, and with cymbals. The list of those who did the work and of their duties was:
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13025002">
			</marker>
			<verse num="2">
				Of the sons of Asaph: Zaccur, Joseph, Nethaniah, and Asharelah, sons of Asaph, under the direction of Asaph, who 
				<crossref let="b" cid="c13025002.1">
				</crossref>
				prophesied under the direction of the king.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13025003">
			</marker>
			<verse num="3">
				Of Jeduthun, the sons of Jeduthun: Gedaliah, Zeri, Jeshaiah, Shimei,
				<note nid="n13025003.1">
				</note>
				 Hashabiah, and Mattithiah, six, under the direction of their father Jeduthun, 
				<crossref let="b" cid="c13025003.1">
				</crossref>
				who prophesied with the lyre in thanksgiving and praise to the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13025004">
			</marker>
			<verse num="4">
				Of Heman, the sons of Heman: Bukkiah, Mattaniah, Uzziel, Shebuel and Jerimoth, Hananiah, Hanani, Eliathah, Giddalti, and Romamti-ezer, Joshbekashah, Mallothi, Hothir, Mahazioth.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13025005">
			</marker>
			<verse num="5">
				All these were the sons of Heman 
				<crossref let="d" cid="c13025005.1">
				</crossref>
				the king's seer, according to the promise of God to exalt him, for God had given Heman fourteen sons and three daughters.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13025006">
			</marker>
			<verse num="6">
				They were all under the direction of their father in the music in the house of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 with cymbals, 
				<crossref let="c" cid="c13025006.1">
				</crossref>
				harps, and lyres for the service of the house of God. Asaph, Jeduthun, and Heman were under the order of the king.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13025007">
			</marker>
			<verse num="7">
				The number of them along with their brothers, who were trained in singing to the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				, all who were skillful, was 
				<crossref let="e" cid="c13025007.1">
				</crossref>
				288.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13025008">
			</marker>
			<verse num="8">
				And they cast lots for their duties, 
				<crossref let="f" cid="c13025008.1">
				</crossref>
				small and great, teacher and pupil alike.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13025009">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="9">
				The first lot fell for Asaph to Joseph; the second to Gedaliah, to him and his brothers and his sons, twelve;
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13025010">
			</marker>
			<verse num="10">
				the third to Zaccur, his sons and his brothers, twelve;
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13025011">
			</marker>
			<verse num="11">
				the fourth to Izri, his sons and his brothers, twelve;
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13025012">
			</marker>
			<verse num="12">
				the fifth to Nethaniah, his sons and his brothers, twelve;
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13025013">
			</marker>
			<verse num="13">
				the sixth to Bukkiah, his sons and his brothers, twelve;
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13025014">
			</marker>
			<verse num="14">
				the seventh to Jesharelah, his sons and his brothers, twelve;
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13025015">
			</marker>
			<verse num="15">
				the eighth to Jeshaiah, his sons and his brothers, twelve;
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13025016">
			</marker>
			<verse num="16">
				the ninth to Mattaniah, his sons and his brothers, twelve;
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13025017">
			</marker>
			<verse num="17">
				the tenth to Shimei, his sons and his brothers, twelve;
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13025018">
			</marker>
			<verse num="18">
				the eleventh to Azarel, his sons and his brothers, twelve;
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13025019">
			</marker>
			<verse num="19">
				the twelfth to Hashabiah, his sons and his brothers, twelve;
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13025020">
			</marker>
			<verse num="20">
				to the thirteenth, Shubael, his sons and his brothers, twelve;
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13025021">
			</marker>
			<verse num="21">
				to the fourteenth, Mattithiah, his sons and his brothers, twelve;
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13025022">
			</marker>
			<verse num="22">
				to the fifteenth, to Jeremoth, his sons and his brothers, twelve;
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13025023">
			</marker>
			<verse num="23">
				to the sixteenth, to Hananiah, his sons and his brothers, twelve;
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13025024">
			</marker>
			<verse num="24">
				to the seventeenth, to Joshbekashah, his sons and his brothers, twelve;
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13025025">
			</marker>
			<verse num="25">
				to the eighteenth, to Hanani, his sons and his brothers, twelve;
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13025026">
			</marker>
			<verse num="26">
				to the nineteenth, to Mallothi, his sons and his brothers, twelve;
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13025027">
			</marker>
			<verse num="27">
				to the twentieth, to Eliathah, his sons and his brothers, twelve;
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13025028">
			</marker>
			<verse num="28">
				to the twenty-first, to Hothir, his sons and his brothers, twelve;
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13025029">
			</marker>
			<verse num="29">
				to the twenty-second, to Giddalti, his sons and his brothers, twelve;
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13025030">
			</marker>
			<verse num="30">
				to the twenty-third, to Mahazioth, his sons and his brothers, twelve;
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13025031">
			</marker>
			<verse num="31">
				to the twenty-fourth, to Romamti-ezer, his sons and his brothers, twelve.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
		</chapter>
	</book>
</crossway-bible>


