<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> 
<crossway-bible>
	<book title="1 Chronicles" num="12">
		<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13020001">
		</marker>
		<chapter num="20">
			<heading>
				The Capture of Rabbah
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="1">
				<crossref let="y" cid="c13020001.1">
				</crossref>
				In the spring of the year, the time when kings go out to battle, Joab led out the army and ravaged the country of the Ammonites and came and besieged Rabbah. But David remained at Jerusalem. And 
				<crossref let="z" cid="c13020001.2">
				</crossref>
				Joab struck down Rabbah and overthrew it.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13020002">
			</marker>
			<verse num="2">
				<crossref let="a" cid="c13020002.1">
				</crossref>
				And David took the crown of their king from his head. He found that it weighed a talent
				<note nid="n13020002.1">
				</note>
				 of gold, and in it was a precious stone. And it was placed on David's head. And he brought out the spoil of the city, a very great amount.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13020003">
			</marker>
			<verse num="3">
				And he brought out the people who were in it and set them to labor
				<note nid="n13020003.1">
				</note>
				<crossref let="b" cid="c13020003.1">
				</crossref>
				with saws and iron picks and axes.
				<note nid="n13020003.2">
				</note>
				 And thus David did to all the cities of the Ammonites. Then David and all the people returned to Jerusalem.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13020004">
			</marker>
			<heading>
				Philistine Giants Killed
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="4">
				<crossref let="c" cid="c13020004.1">
				</crossref>
				And after this there arose war with the Philistines at Gezer. Then Sibbecai the Hushathite struck down Sippai, who was one of the descendants of the giants, and the Philistines were subdued.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13020005">
			</marker>
			<verse num="5">
				And there was again war with the Philistines, and Elhanan the son of 
				<crossref let="d" cid="c13020005.1">
				</crossref>
				Jair struck down Lahmi 
				<crossref let="d" cid="c13020005.2">
				</crossref>
				the brother of Goliath the Gittite, the shaft of whose spear was like a weaver's beam.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13020006">
			</marker>
			<verse num="6">
				And there was again war at Gath, where there was a man of great stature, who had six fingers on each hand and six toes on each foot, twenty-four in number, and he also was descended from the giants.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13020007">
			</marker>
			<verse num="7">
				And when he taunted Israel, Jonathan the son of 
				<crossref let="e" cid="c13020007.1">
				</crossref>
				Shimea, David's brother, struck him down.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13020008">
			</marker>
			<verse num="8">
				These were descended from the giants in Gath, and they fell by the hand of David and by the hand of his servants.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph>
			</end-paragraph>
		</chapter>
	</book>
</crossway-bible>


