<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> 
<crossway-bible>
	<book title="2 Chronicles" num="13">
		<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14034001">
		</marker>
		<chapter num="34">
			<heading
				>
				Josiah Reigns in Judah
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="1">
				<crossref let="m" cid="c14034001.1">
				</crossref>
				Josiah was eight years old when he began to reign, and he reigned thirty-one years in Jerusalem.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14034002">
			</marker>
			<verse num="2">
				And he did what was right in the eyes of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				, and walked in the ways of David his father; and he did not turn aside to the right hand or to the left.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14034003">
			</marker>
			<verse num="3">
				For in the eighth year of his reign, while he was yet a boy, he began to seek the God of David his father, and in the twelfth year he began to purge Judah and Jerusalem of the high places, the 
				<crossref let="n" cid="c14034003.1">
				</crossref>
				Asherim, and the carved and the metal images.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14034004">
			</marker>
			<verse num="4">
				And they chopped down the altars of the Baals in his presence, and he cut down the 
				<crossref let="o" cid="c14034004.1">
				</crossref>
				incense altars that stood above them. And he broke in pieces the 
				<crossref let="n" cid="c14034004.2">
				</crossref>
				Asherim and the carved and the metal images, and he made dust of them and 
				<crossref let="o" cid="c14034004.3">
				</crossref>
				scattered it over the graves of those who had sacrificed to them.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14034005">
			</marker>
			<verse num="5">
				<crossref let="p" cid="c14034005.1">
				</crossref>
				He also burned the bones of the priests on their altars and cleansed Judah and Jerusalem.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14034006">
			</marker>
			<verse num="6">
				And in the 
				<crossref let="q" cid="c14034006.1">
				</crossref>
				cities of Manasseh, Ephraim, and Simeon, and as far as Naphtali, in their ruins
				<note nid="n14034006.1">
				</note>
				 all around,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14034007">
			</marker>
			<verse num="7">
				he broke down the altars and beat the 
				<crossref let="n" cid="c14034007.1">
				</crossref>
				Asherim and the images 
				<crossref let="r" cid="c14034007.2">
				</crossref>
				into powder and cut down all the incense altars throughout all the land of Israel. Then he returned to Jerusalem.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14034008">
			</marker>
			<heading
				>
				The Book of the Law Found
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="8">
				<crossref let="s" cid="c14034008.1">
				</crossref>
				Now in the eighteenth year of his reign, when he had cleansed the land and the house, he sent Shaphan the son of Azaliah, and Maaseiah the 
				<crossref let="t" cid="c14034008.2">
				</crossref>
				governor of the city, and Joah the son of Joahaz, 
				<crossref let="u" cid="c14034008.3">
				</crossref>
				the recorder, to repair the house of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 his God.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14034009">
			</marker>
			<verse num="9">
				They came to 
				<crossref let="v" cid="c14034009.1">
				</crossref>
				Hilkiah the high priest and gave him the money that had been brought into the house of God, which the Levites, the keepers of the threshold, had collected from 
				<crossref let="q" cid="c14034009.2">
				</crossref>
				Manasseh and Ephraim and from all the remnant of Israel and from all Judah and Benjamin and from the inhabitants of Jerusalem.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14034010">
			</marker>
			<verse num="10">
				And they gave it to the workmen who were working in the house of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				. And the workmen who were working in the house of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 gave it for repairing and restoring the house.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14034011">
			</marker>
			<verse num="11">
				They gave it to the carpenters and the builders to buy quarried stone, and timber for binders and 
				<crossref let="w" cid="c14034011.1">
				</crossref>
				beams for the buildings that the kings of Judah had let go to ruin.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14034012">
			</marker>
			<verse num="12">
				And the men did the work faithfully. Over them were set Jahath and Obadiah the Levites, of the sons of Merari, and Zechariah and Meshullam, of the sons of the Kohathites, to have oversight. 
				<crossref let="x" cid="c14034012.1">
				</crossref>
				The Levites, all who were skillful with instruments of music,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14034013">
			</marker>
			<verse num="13">
				were over 
				<crossref let="y" cid="c14034013.1">
				</crossref>
				the burden-bearers and directed all who did work in every kind of service, and some of the Levites were scribes and officials and gatekeepers.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14034014">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="14">
				While they were bringing out the money that had been brought into the house of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				, 
				<crossref let="v" cid="c14034014.1">
				</crossref>
				Hilkiah the priest found the Book of the Law of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 given through Moses.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14034015">
			</marker>
			<verse num="15">
				Then Hilkiah answered and said to Shaphan the secretary, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				I have found the Book of the Law in the house of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				 And Hilkiah gave the book to Shaphan.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14034016">
			</marker>
			<verse num="16">
				Shaphan brought the book to the king, and further reported to the king, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				All that was committed to your servants they are doing.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14034017">
			</marker>
			<verse num="17">
				They have emptied out the money that was found in the house of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 and have given it into the hand of the overseers and the workmen.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14034018">
			</marker>
			<verse num="18">
				Then Shaphan the secretary told the king, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Hilkiah the priest has given me a book.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				 And Shaphan read from it before the king.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14034019">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="19">
				And when the king heard the words of the Law, 
				<crossref let="z" cid="c14034019.1">
				</crossref>
				he tore his clothes.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14034020">
			</marker>
			<verse num="20">
				And the king commanded Hilkiah, Ahikam the son of Shaphan, Abdon the son of Micah, Shaphan the secretary, and Asaiah the king's servant, saying,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14034021">
			</marker>
			<verse num="21">
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Go, inquire of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 for me and for those who are left in Israel and in Judah, concerning the words of the book that has been found. For great is 
				<crossref let="a" cid="c14034021.1">
				</crossref>
				the wrath of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 that is poured out on us, because our fathers have not kept the word of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				, to do according to all that is written in this book.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14034022">
			</marker>
			<heading
				>
				Huldah Prophesies Disaster
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="22">
				So Hilkiah and those whom the king had sent
				<note nid="n14034022.1">
				</note>
				 went to Huldah the prophetess, the wife of Shallum the son of Tokhath, son of Hasrah, keeper of the wardrobe (now she lived in Jerusalem in the Second Quarter) and spoke to her to that effect.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14034023">
			</marker>
			<verse num="23">
				And she said to them, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Thus says the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				, the God of Israel: 
				<q class="begin-single" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Tell the man who sent you to me,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14034024">
			</marker>
			<verse num="24">
				Thus says the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				, Behold, I will bring disaster upon this place and upon its inhabitants, all the curses that are written in the book that was read before the king of Judah.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14034025">
			</marker>
			<verse num="25">
				Because they have forsaken me and 
				<crossref let="b" cid="c14034025.1">
				</crossref>
				have made offerings to other gods, that they might provoke me to anger with all the works of their hands, therefore 
				<crossref let="a" cid="c14034025.2">
				</crossref>
				my wrath will be poured out on this place and will not be quenched.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14034026">
			</marker>
			<verse num="26">
				But to the king of Judah, who sent you to inquire of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				, thus shall you say to him, Thus says the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				, the God of Israel: Regarding the words that you have heard,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14034027">
			</marker>
			<verse num="27">
				because your heart was tender and you humbled yourself before God when you heard his words against this place and its inhabitants, and you have humbled yourself before me and have torn your clothes and wept before me, I also have heard you, declares the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14034028">
			</marker>
			<verse num="28">
				Behold, I will gather you to your fathers, and you shall be gathered to your grave in peace, and your eyes shall not see all the disaster that I will bring upon this place and its inhabitants.
				<q class="end-single" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				 And they brought back word to the king.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14034029">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="29">
				<crossref let="c" cid="c14034029.1">
				</crossref>
				Then the king sent and gathered together all the elders of Judah and Jerusalem.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14034030">
			</marker>
			<verse num="30">
				And the king went up to the house of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				, with all the men of Judah and the inhabitants of Jerusalem and the priests and the Levites, all the people both great and small. And he read in their hearing all the words of the Book of the Covenant that had been found in the house of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14034031">
			</marker>
			<verse num="31">
				And the king 
				<crossref let="d" cid="c14034031.1">
				</crossref>
				stood in his place 
				<crossref let="e" cid="c14034031.2">
				</crossref>
				and made a covenant before the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				, to walk after the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 and to keep his commandments and his testimonies and his statutes, with all his heart and all his soul, to perform the words of the covenant that were written in this book.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14034032">
			</marker>
			<verse num="32">
				Then he made all who were present in Jerusalem and in Benjamin join in it. And the inhabitants of Jerusalem did according to the covenant of God, the God of their fathers.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14034033">
			</marker>
			<verse num="33">
				And Josiah took away 
				<crossref let="f" cid="c14034033.1">
				</crossref>
				all the abominations from all the territory that belonged to the people of Israel and made all who were present in Israel serve the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 their God. All his days they did not turn away from following the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				, the God of their fathers.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
		</chapter>
	</book>
</crossway-bible>


