<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> 
<crossway-bible>
	<book title="2 Chronicles" num="13">
		<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14031001">
		</marker>
		<chapter num="31">
			<heading
				>
				Hezekiah Organizes the Priests
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="1">
				Now when all this was finished, all Israel who were present went out to the cities of Judah and 
				<crossref let="n" cid="c14031001.1">
				</crossref>
				broke in pieces the 
				<crossref let="o" cid="c14031001.2">
				</crossref>
				pillars and cut down 
				<crossref let="p" cid="c14031001.3">
				</crossref>
				the Asherim and broke down the high places and the altars throughout all Judah and Benjamin, and in Ephraim and Manasseh, until they had destroyed them all. Then all the people of Israel returned to their cities, every man to his possession.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14031002">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="2">
				And Hezekiah appointed 
				<crossref let="q" cid="c14031002.1">
				</crossref>
				the divisions of the priests and of the Levites, division by division, each according to his service, the priests and the Levites, 
				<crossref let="r" cid="c14031002.2">
				</crossref>
				for burnt offerings and peace offerings, to minister in the gates of the camp of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 and to give thanks and praise.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14031003">
			</marker>
			<verse num="3">
				<crossref let="s" cid="c14031003.1">
				</crossref>
				The contribution of the king from his own possessions was for the burnt offerings: the burnt offerings of morning and evening, and the burnt offerings for the Sabbaths, the new moons, and the appointed feasts, 
				<crossref let="t" cid="c14031003.2">
				</crossref>
				as it is written in the Law of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14031004">
			</marker>
			<verse num="4">
				And he commanded the people who lived in Jerusalem to give 
				<crossref let="u" cid="c14031004.1">
				</crossref>
				the portion due to the priests and the Levites, that they might give themselves to the Law of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14031005">
			</marker>
			<verse num="5">
				As soon as the command was spread abroad, the people of Israel gave in abundance the firstfruits of grain, wine, oil, honey, and of all the produce of the field. And they brought in abundantly 
				<crossref let="v" cid="c14031005.1">
				</crossref>
				the tithe of everything.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14031006">
			</marker>
			<verse num="6">
				And the people of Israel and Judah who lived in the cities of Judah also brought in the tithe of cattle and sheep, and 
				<crossref let="w" cid="c14031006.1">
				</crossref>
				the tithe of the dedicated things that had been dedicated to the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 their God, and laid them in heaps.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14031007">
			</marker>
			<verse num="7">
				In the third month they began to pile up the heaps, and finished them in the seventh month.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14031008">
			</marker>
			<verse num="8">
				When Hezekiah and the princes came and saw the heaps, they blessed the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 and his people Israel.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14031009">
			</marker>
			<verse num="9">
				And Hezekiah questioned the priests and the Levites about the heaps.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14031010">
			</marker>
			<verse num="10">
				Azariah the chief priest, who was 
				<crossref let="x" cid="c14031010.1">
				</crossref>
				of the house of Zadok, answered him, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Since they began to bring the contributions into the house of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				, we have eaten and had enough and have plenty left, 
				<crossref let="y" cid="c14031010.2">
				</crossref>
				for the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 has blessed his people, so that we have this large amount left.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14031011">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="11">
				Then Hezekiah commanded them to prepare 
				<crossref let="z" cid="c14031011.1">
				</crossref>
				chambers in the house of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				, and they prepared them.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14031012">
			</marker>
			<verse num="12">
				And they faithfully brought in the contributions, the tithes, and the dedicated things. The chief officer 
				<crossref let="a" cid="c14031012.1">
				</crossref>
				in charge of them was Conaniah the Levite, with 
				<crossref let="b" cid="c14031012.2">
				</crossref>
				Shimei his brother as second,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14031013">
			</marker>
			<verse num="13">
				<crossref let="b" cid="c14031013.1">
				</crossref>
				while Jehiel, Azaziah, Nahath, Asahel, Jerimoth, Jozabad, Eliel, Ismachiah, 
				<crossref let="b" cid="c14031013.2">
				</crossref>
				Mahath, and Benaiah were overseers assisting Conaniah and Shimei his brother, by the appointment of Hezekiah the king and 
				<crossref let="x" cid="c14031013.3">
				</crossref>
				Azariah the chief officer of the house of God.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14031014">
			</marker>
			<verse num="14">
				And Kore the son of Imnah the Levite, keeper of the east gate, was over the freewill offerings to God, to apportion the contribution reserved for the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 and the most holy offerings.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14031015">
			</marker>
			<verse num="15">
				<crossref let="b" cid="c14031015.1">
				</crossref>
				Eden, Miniamin, Jeshua, Shemaiah, Amariah, and Shecaniah were faithfully assisting him in 
				<crossref let="d" cid="c14031015.2">
				</crossref>
				the cities of the priests, to distribute the portions to their brothers, old and young alike, by divisions,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14031016">
			</marker>
			<verse num="16">
				except those enrolled by genealogy, males from three years old and upwardùall who entered the house of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				<crossref let="e" cid="c14031016.1">
				</crossref>
				as the duty of each day requiredùfor their service according to their offices, by their divisions.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14031017">
			</marker>
			<verse num="17">
				The enrollment of the priests was according to their fathers' houses; that of the Levites 
				<crossref let="f" cid="c14031017.1">
				</crossref>
				from twenty years old and upward was according to their offices, by their divisions.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14031018">
			</marker>
			<verse num="18">
				They were enrolled with all their little children, their wives, their sons, and their daughters, the whole assembly, for they were faithful in keeping themselves holy.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14031019">
			</marker>
			<verse num="19">
				And for the sons of Aaron, the priests, who were in the fields of common land belonging to their cities, there were men in the several cities who were 
				<crossref let="g" cid="c14031019.1">
				</crossref>
				designated by name to distribute portions to every male among the priests and to everyone among the Levites who was enrolled.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14031020">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="20">
				Thus Hezekiah did throughout all Judah, 
				<crossref let="h" cid="c14031020.1">
				</crossref>
				and he did what was good and right and faithful before the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 his God.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14031021">
			</marker>
			<verse num="21">
				And every work that he undertook in the service of the house of God and in accordance with the law and the commandments, seeking his God, he did with all his heart, and prospered.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
		</chapter>
	</book>
</crossway-bible>


