<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> 
<crossway-bible>
	<book title="2 Chronicles" num="13">
		<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14025001">
		</marker>
		<chapter num="25">
			<heading
				>
				Amaziah Reigns in Judah
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="1">
				<crossref let="i" cid="c14025001.1">
				</crossref>
				Amaziah was twenty-five years old when he began to reign, and he reigned twenty-nine years in Jerusalem. His mother's name was Jehoaddan of Jerusalem.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14025002">
			</marker>
			<verse num="2">
				And he did what was right in the eyes of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				, 
				<crossref let="j" cid="c14025002.1">
				</crossref>
				yet not with a whole heart.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14025003">
			</marker>
			<verse num="3">
				And as soon as the royal power was firmly his, he killed his servants who had struck down the king his father.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14025004">
			</marker>
			<verse num="4">
				But he did not put their children to death, according to what is written in the Law, in the Book of Moses, where the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 commanded, 
				<crossref let="k" cid="c14025004.1">
				</crossref>
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Fathers shall not die because of their children, nor children die because of their fathers, but each one shall die for his own sin.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14025005">
			</marker>
			<heading
				>
				Amaziah's Victories
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="5">
				Then Amaziah assembled the men of Judah and set them by fathers' houses under commanders of thousands and of hundreds for all Judah and Benjamin. He mustered those 
				<crossref let="l" cid="c14025005.1">
				</crossref>
				twenty years old and upward, and found that they were 
				<crossref let="m" cid="c14025005.2">
				</crossref>
				300,000 choice men, fit for war, 
				<crossref let="n" cid="c14025005.3">
				</crossref>
				able to handle spear and shield.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14025006">
			</marker>
			<verse num="6">
				He hired also 100,000 mighty men of valor from Israel for 100 talents
				<note nid="n14025006.1">
				</note>
				 of silver.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14025007">
			</marker>
			<verse num="7">
				But 
				<crossref let="o" cid="c14025007.1">
				</crossref>
				a man of God came to him and said, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				O king, do not let the army of Israel go with you, for the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 is not with Israel, with all these Ephraimites.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14025008">
			</marker>
			<verse num="8">
				But go, act, be strong for the battle. Why should you suppose that God will cast you down before the enemy? 
				<crossref let="p" cid="c14025008.1">
				</crossref>
				For God has power to help or to cast down.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14025009">
			</marker>
			<verse num="9">
				And Amaziah said to the man of God, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				But what shall we do about the hundred talents that I have given to the army of Israel?
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				 The man of God answered, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				The 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 is able to give you much more than this.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14025010">
			</marker>
			<verse num="10">
				Then Amaziah discharged the army that had come to him from Ephraim to go home again. And they became very angry with Judah and returned home in fierce anger.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14025011">
			</marker>
			<verse num="11">
				But Amaziah took courage and led out his people and went to the 
				<crossref let="q" cid="c14025011.1">
				</crossref>
				Valley of Salt and struck down 
				<crossref let="r" cid="c14025011.2">
				</crossref>
				10,000 men of Seir.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14025012">
			</marker>
			<verse num="12">
				The men of Judah captured another 10,000 alive and took them to the top of a rock and threw them down from the top of the rock, and they were all dashed to pieces.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14025013">
			</marker>
			<verse num="13">
				But the men of the army whom Amaziah sent back, not letting them go with him to battle, raided the cities of Judah, 
				<crossref let="s" cid="c14025013.1">
				</crossref>
				from Samaria to Beth-horon, and struck down 3,000 people in them and took much spoil.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14025014">
			</marker>
			<heading
				>
				Amaziah's Idolatry
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="14">
				After Amaziah came from striking down the Edomites, 
				<crossref let="t" cid="c14025014.1">
				</crossref>
				he brought the gods 
				<crossref let="r" cid="c14025014.2">
				</crossref>
				of the men of Seir and set them up as his gods and worshiped them, making offerings to them.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14025015">
			</marker>
			<verse num="15">
				Therefore the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 was angry with Amaziah and sent to him a prophet, who said to him, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Why have you sought the gods of a people 
				<crossref let="u" cid="c14025015.1">
				</crossref>
				who did not deliver their own people from your hand?
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14025016">
			</marker>
			<verse num="16">
				But as he was speaking, the king said to him, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Have we made you a royal counselor? Stop! Why should you be struck down?
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				 So the prophet stopped, but said, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				I know that 
				<crossref let="v" cid="c14025016.1">
				</crossref>
				God has determined to destroy you, because you have done this and have not listened to my counsel.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14025017">
			</marker>
			<heading
				>
				Israel Defeats Amaziah
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="17">
				<crossref let="w" cid="c14025017.1">
				</crossref>
				Then Amaziah king of Judah took counsel and sent to Joash the son of Jehoahaz, son of Jehu, king of Israel, saying, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Come, let us look one another in the face.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14025018">
			</marker>
			<verse num="18">
				And Joash the king of Israel sent word to Amaziah king of Judah, 
				<crossref let="x" cid="c14025018.1">
				</crossref>
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				A thistle on Lebanon sent to a cedar on Lebanon, saying, 
				<q class="begin-single" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Give your daughter to my son for a wife,
				<q class="end-single" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				 and a wild beast of Lebanon passed by and trampled down the thistle.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14025019">
			</marker>
			<verse num="19">
				You say, 
				<q class="begin-single" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				See, I
				<note nid="n14025019.1">
				</note>
				 have struck down Edom,
				<q class="end-single" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				 and 
				<crossref let="y" cid="c14025019.1">
				</crossref>
				your heart has lifted you up in boastfulness. But now stay at home. Why should you provoke trouble so that you fall, you and Judah with you?
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14025020">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="20">
				But Amaziah would not listen, for it was of God, in order that he might give them into the hand of their enemies, 
				<crossref let="z" cid="c14025020.1">
				</crossref>
				because they had sought the gods of Edom.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14025021">
			</marker>
			<verse num="21">
				So Joash king of Israel went up, and he and Amaziah king of Judah faced one another in battle at Beth-shemesh, which belongs to Judah.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14025022">
			</marker>
			<verse num="22">
				And Judah was defeated by Israel, and every man fled to his home.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14025023">
			</marker>
			<verse num="23">
				And Joash king of Israel captured Amaziah king of Judah, the son of Joash, son of 
				<crossref let="a" cid="c14025023.1">
				</crossref>
				Ahaziah, at Beth-shemesh, and brought him to Jerusalem and broke down the wall of Jerusalem for 400 cubits,
				<note nid="n14025023.1">
				</note>
				 from 
				<crossref let="b" cid="c14025023.2">
				</crossref>
				the Ephraim Gate to the Corner Gate.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14025024">
			</marker>
			<verse num="24">
				And he seized all the gold and silver, and all the vessels that were found in the house of God, in the care of 
				<crossref let="c" cid="c14025024.1">
				</crossref>
				Obed-edom. He seized also the treasuries of the king's house, also hostages, and he returned to Samaria.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14025025">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="25">
				<crossref let="d" cid="c14025025.1">
				</crossref>
				Amaziah the son of Joash, king of Judah, lived fifteen years after the death of Joash the son of Jehoahaz, king of Israel.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14025026">
			</marker>
			<verse num="26">
				Now the rest of the deeds of Amaziah, from first to last, are they not written in the Book of the Kings of Judah and Israel?
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14025027">
			</marker>
			<verse num="27">
				From the time when he turned away from the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 they made a conspiracy against him in Jerusalem, and he fled to Lachish. But they sent after him to Lachish and put him to death there.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v14025028">
			</marker>
			<verse num="28">
				And they brought him upon horses, and he was buried with his fathers in the city of David.
				<note nid="n14025028.1">
				</note>
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
		</chapter>
	</book>
</crossway-bible>


