<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> 
<crossway-bible>
	<book title="1 Chronicles" num="12">
		<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13010001">
		</marker>
		<chapter num="10">
			<heading>
				The Death of Saul and His Sons
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="1">
				<crossref let="z" cid="c13010001.1">
				</crossref>
				Now the Philistines fought against Israel, and the men of Israel fled before the Philistines and fell slain on Mount Gilboa.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13010002">
			</marker>
			<verse num="2">
				And the Philistines overtook Saul and his sons, and the Philistines struck down Jonathan and Abinadab and Malchi-shua, the sons of Saul.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13010003">
			</marker>
			<verse num="3">
				The battle pressed hard against Saul, and the archers found him, and he was wounded by the archers.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13010004">
			</marker>
			<verse num="4">
				Then Saul said to his armor-bearer, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Draw your sword and thrust me through with it, lest these uncircumcised come and mistreat me.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				 But his armor-bearer would not, for he feared greatly. Therefore Saul took his own sword and fell upon it.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13010005">
			</marker>
			<verse num="5">
				And when his armor-bearer saw that Saul was dead, he also fell upon his sword and died.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13010006">
			</marker>
			<verse num="6">
				Thus Saul died; he and his three sons and all his house died together.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13010007">
			</marker>
			<verse num="7">
				And when all the men of Israel who were in the valley saw that the army
				<note nid="n13010007.1">
				</note>
				 had fled and that Saul and his sons were dead, they abandoned their cities and fled, and the Philistines came and lived in them.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13010008">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="8">
				The next day, when the Philistines came to strip the slain, they found Saul and his sons fallen on Mount Gilboa.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13010009">
			</marker>
			<verse num="9">
				And they stripped him and took his head and his armor, and sent messengers throughout the land of the Philistines to carry the good news to their idols and to the people.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13010010">
			</marker>
			<verse num="10">
				And they put his armor in the temple of their gods and fastened his head in the temple of Dagon.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13010011">
			</marker>
			<verse num="11">
				But when all Jabesh-gilead heard all that the Philistines had done to Saul,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13010012">
			</marker>
			<verse num="12">
				all the valiant men arose and took away the body of Saul and the bodies of his sons, and brought them to Jabesh. And they buried their bones under the oak in Jabesh and fasted seven days.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13010013">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="13">
				So Saul died 
				<crossref let="a" cid="c13010013.1">
				</crossref>
				for his breach of faith. He broke faith with the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 in that he did not keep the command of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				, and also 
				<crossref let="b" cid="c13010013.2">
				</crossref>
				consulted a medium, seeking guidance.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13010014">
			</marker>
			<verse num="14">
				He 
				<crossref let="c" cid="c13010014.1">
				</crossref>
				did not seek guidance from the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				. Therefore the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 put him to death and 
				<crossref let="d" cid="c13010014.2">
				</crossref>
				turned the kingdom over to David the son of Jesse.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph>
			</end-paragraph>
		</chapter>
	</book>
</crossway-bible>


