<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> 
<crossway-bible>
	<book title="1 Chronicles" num="12">
		<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13019001">
		</marker>
		<chapter num="19">
			<heading>
				The Ammonites Disgrace David's Men
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="1">
				<crossref let="q" cid="c13019001.1">
				</crossref>
				Now after this Nahash the king of the Ammonites died, and his son reigned in his place.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13019002">
			</marker>
			<verse num="2">
				And David said, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				I will deal kindly with Hanun the son of Nahash, for his father dealt kindly with me.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				 So David sent messengers to console him concerning his father. And David's servants came to the land of the Ammonites to Hanun to console him.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13019003">
			</marker>
			<verse num="3">
				But the princes of the Ammonites said to Hanun, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Do you think, because David has sent comforters to you, that he is honoring your father? Have not his servants come to you to search and to overthrow and to spy out the land?
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13019004">
			</marker>
			<verse num="4">
				So Hanun took David's servants and shaved them and cut off their garments in the middle, at their hips, and sent them away;
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13019005">
			</marker>
			<verse num="5">
				and they departed. When David was told concerning the men, he sent messengers to meet them, for the men were greatly ashamed. And the king said, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Remain at Jericho until your beards have grown and then return.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13019006">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="6">
				When the Ammonites saw that they had become a stench to David, Hanun and the Ammonites sent 1,000 talents
				<note nid="n13019006.1">
				</note>
				 of silver to hire chariots and horsemen 
				<crossref let="r" cid="c13019006.1">
				</crossref>
				from Mesopotamia, from Aram-maacah, and from 
				<crossref let="s" cid="c13019006.2">
				</crossref>
				Zobah.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13019007">
			</marker>
			<verse num="7">
				They hired 32,000 chariots and the king of Maacah with his army, who came and encamped before 
				<crossref let="t" cid="c13019007.1">
				</crossref>
				Medeba. And the Ammonites were mustered from their cities and came to battle.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13019008">
			</marker>
			<verse num="8">
				When David heard of it, he sent Joab and all the army of the mighty men.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13019009">
			</marker>
			<verse num="9">
				And the Ammonites came out and drew up in battle array at the entrance of the city, and the kings who had come were by themselves in the open country.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13019010">
			</marker>
			<heading>
				Ammonites and Syrians Defeated
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="10">
				When Joab saw that the battle was set against him both in front and in the rear, he chose some of the best men of Israel and arrayed them against the Syrians.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13019011">
			</marker>
			<verse num="11">
				The rest of his men he put in the charge of 
				<crossref let="u" cid="c13019011.1">
				</crossref>
				Abishai his brother, and they were arrayed against the Ammonites.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13019012">
			</marker>
			<verse num="12">
				And he said, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				If the Syrians are too strong for me, then you shall help me, but if the Ammonites are too strong for you, then I will help you.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13019013">
			</marker>
			<verse num="13">
				Be strong, and let us use our strength for our people and for the cities of our God, and may the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 do what seems good to him.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13019014">
			</marker>
			<verse num="14">
				So Joab and the people who were with him drew near before the Syrians for battle, and they fled before him.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13019015">
			</marker>
			<verse num="15">
				And when the Ammonites saw that the Syrians fled, they likewise fled before 
				<crossref let="u" cid="c13019015.1">
				</crossref>
				Abishai, Joab's brother, and entered the city. Then Joab came to Jerusalem.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13019016">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="16">
				But when the Syrians saw that they had been defeated by Israel, they sent messengers and brought out the Syrians who were beyond the Euphrates, with 
				<crossref let="v" cid="c13019016.1">
				</crossref>
				Shophach the commander of the army of 
				<crossref let="w" cid="c13019016.2">
				</crossref>
				Hadadezer at their head.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13019017">
			</marker>
			<verse num="17">
				And when it was told to David, he gathered all Israel together and crossed the Jordan and came to them and drew up his forces against them. And when David set the battle in array against the Syrians, they fought with him.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13019018">
			</marker>
			<verse num="18">
				And the Syrians fled before Israel, and David killed of the Syrians the men of 
				<crossref let="x" cid="c13019018.1">
				</crossref>
				7,000 chariots and 40,000 
				<crossref let="x" cid="c13019018.2">
				</crossref>
				foot soldiers, and put to death also 
				<crossref let="v" cid="c13019018.3">
				</crossref>
				Shophach the commander of their army.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v13019019">
			</marker>
			<verse num="19">
				And when the servants of 
				<crossref let="w" cid="c13019019.1">
				</crossref>
				Hadadezer saw that they had been defeated by Israel, they made peace with David and became subject to him. So the Syrians were not willing to save the Ammonites anymore.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph>
			</end-paragraph>
		</chapter>
	</book>
</crossway-bible>


