<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> 
<crossway-bible>
	<book title="Daniel" num="26">
		<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v27011001">
		</marker>
		<chapter num="11">
			<heading
				>
				The Kings of the South and the North
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="1">
				<q class="continue-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				And as for me, 
				<crossref let="u" cid="c27011001.1">
				</crossref>
				in the first year of 
				<crossref let="u" cid="c27011001.2">
				</crossref>
				Darius the Mede, I stood up to confirm and strengthen him.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v27011002">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="2">
				<q class="continue-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				And now I will show you 
				<crossref let="v" cid="c27011002.1">
				</crossref>
				the truth. Behold, three more kings shall arise in Persia, and a fourth shall be far richer than all of them. And when he has become strong through his riches, he shall stir up all against the kingdom of Greece.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v27011003">
			</marker>
			<verse num="3">
				Then 
				<crossref let="w" cid="c27011003.1">
				</crossref>
				a mighty king shall arise, who shall rule with great dominion and 
				<crossref let="x" cid="c27011003.2">
				</crossref>
				do as he wills.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v27011004">
			</marker>
			<verse num="4">
				And as soon as he has arisen, 
				<crossref let="y" cid="c27011004.1">
				</crossref>
				his kingdom shall be broken and divided 
				<crossref let="y" cid="c27011004.2">
				</crossref>
				toward the 
				<crossref let="z" cid="c27011004.3">
				</crossref>
				four winds of heaven, but 
				<crossref let="a" cid="c27011004.4">
				</crossref>
				not to his posterity, nor according to the authority with which he ruled, for his kingdom shall be plucked up and go to others besides these.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v27011005">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="5">
				<q class="continue-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Then the king of the south shall be strong, but one of his princes shall be stronger than he 
				<crossref let="b" cid="c27011005.1">
				</crossref>
				and shall rule, and his authority shall be a great authority.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v27011006">
			</marker>
			<verse num="6">
				After some years 
				<crossref let="c" cid="c27011006.1">
				</crossref>
				they shall make an alliance, and the daughter of the king of the south shall come to the king of the north to make an agreement. But she shall not retain the strength of her arm, and he and his arm shall not endure, but she shall be given up, and her attendants, he who fathered her, and he who supported
				<note nid="n27011006.1">
				</note>
				 her in those times.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v27011007">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="7">
				<q class="continue-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				And from a branch from her roots one shall arise in his place. He shall come against the army and enter the 
				<crossref let="d" cid="c27011007.1">
				</crossref>
				fortress of the king of the north, and he shall deal with them and shall prevail.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v27011008">
			</marker>
			<verse num="8">
				He shall also carry off to Egypt their gods with their metal images and their precious 
				<crossref let="e" cid="c27011008.1">
				</crossref>
				vessels of silver and gold, and for some years he shall refrain from attacking the king of the north.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v27011009">
			</marker>
			<verse num="9">
				Then the latter shall come into the realm of the king of the south but shall return to his own land.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v27011010">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="10">
				<q class="continue-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				His sons shall wage war and assemble a multitude of great forces, which shall keep coming 
				<crossref let="f" cid="c27011010.1">
				</crossref>
				and overflow and pass through, and again shall carry the war as far as his 
				<crossref let="d" cid="c27011010.2">
				</crossref>
				fortress.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v27011011">
			</marker>
			<verse num="11">
				Then the king of the south, 
				<crossref let="g" cid="c27011011.1">
				</crossref>
				moved with rage, shall come out and fight against the king of the north. 
				<crossref let="h" cid="c27011011.2">
				</crossref>
				And he shall raise a great multitude, but it shall be given into his hand.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v27011012">
			</marker>
			<verse num="12">
				And when the multitude is taken away, his heart shall be exalted, and he shall cast down tens of thousands, but he shall not prevail.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v27011013">
			</marker>
			<verse num="13">
				For the king of the north shall again 
				<crossref let="i" cid="c27011013.1">
				</crossref>
				raise a multitude, greater than the first. And 
				<crossref let="j" cid="c27011013.2">
				</crossref>
				after some years
				<note nid="n27011013.1">
				</note>
				 he shall come on with a great army and abundant supplies.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v27011014">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="14">
				<q class="continue-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				In those times many shall rise against the king of the south, and the violent among your own people shall lift themselves up in order to fulfill the vision, but 
				<crossref let="k" cid="c27011014.1">
				</crossref>
				they shall fail.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v27011015">
			</marker>
			<verse num="15">
				Then the king of the north shall come and 
				<crossref let="l" cid="c27011015.1">
				</crossref>
				throw up siegeworks and take a well-fortified city. And the forces of the south shall not stand, or even his best troops, for there shall be no strength to stand.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v27011016">
			</marker>
			<verse num="16">
				But he who comes against him shall 
				<crossref let="m" cid="c27011016.1">
				</crossref>
				do as he wills, and 
				<crossref let="n" cid="c27011016.2">
				</crossref>
				none shall stand before him. And he shall stand in 
				<crossref let="o" cid="c27011016.3">
				</crossref>
				the glorious land, with destruction in his hand.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v27011017">
			</marker>
			<verse num="17">
				He shall 
				<crossref let="p" cid="c27011017.1">
				</crossref>
				set his face to come with the strength of his whole kingdom, and he shall bring terms of an agreement and perform them. He shall give him the daughter of women to destroy the kingdom,
				<note nid="n27011017.1">
				</note>
				 but it shall not stand or be to his advantage.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v27011018">
			</marker>
			<verse num="18">
				Afterward he shall turn his face to the coastlands and shall capture many of them, but a commander shall put an end to his insolence. Indeed,
				<note nid="n27011018.1">
				</note>
				 he 
				<crossref let="q" cid="c27011018.1">
				</crossref>
				shall turn his insolence back upon him.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v27011019">
			</marker>
			<verse num="19">
				Then he shall turn his face back toward the 
				<crossref let="r" cid="c27011019.1">
				</crossref>
				fortresses of his own land, but he shall 
				<crossref let="s" cid="c27011019.2">
				</crossref>
				stumble and fall, 
				<crossref let="t" cid="c27011019.3">
				</crossref>
				and shall not be found.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v27011020">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="20">
				<q class="continue-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Then shall arise in his place one who shall send an 
				<crossref let="u" cid="c27011020.1">
				</crossref>
				exactor of tribute for the glory of the kingdom. But within a few days he shall be broken, neither in anger nor in battle.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v27011021">
			</marker>
			<verse num="21">
				In his place shall arise a contemptible person to whom royal majesty has not been given. 
				<crossref let="v" cid="c27011021.1">
				</crossref>
				He shall come in without warning and obtain the kingdom 
				<crossref let="w" cid="c27011021.2">
				</crossref>
				by flatteries.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v27011022">
			</marker>
			<verse num="22">
				Armies shall be 
				<crossref let="x" cid="c27011022.1">
				</crossref>
				utterly swept away before him and broken, even the prince of the covenant.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v27011023">
			</marker>
			<verse num="23">
				And from the time that an alliance is made with him he shall act deceitfully, and he shall become strong with a small people.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v27011024">
			</marker>
			<verse num="24">
				<crossref let="y" cid="c27011024.1">
				</crossref>
				Without warning he shall come into 
				<crossref let="z" cid="c27011024.2">
				</crossref>
				the richest parts
				<note nid="n27011024.1">
				</note>
				 of the province, and he shall do what neither his fathers nor his fathers' fathers have done, scattering among them plunder, spoil, and goods. He shall devise plans against strongholds, but only for a time.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v27011025">
			</marker>
			<verse num="25">
				And he shall stir up his power and his heart against 
				<crossref let="a" cid="c27011025.1">
				</crossref>
				the king of the south with a great army. And the king of the south shall wage war with an exceedingly great and mighty army, but he shall not stand, for plots shall be devised against him.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v27011026">
			</marker>
			<verse num="26">
				Even those who eat his food shall break him. His army shall be 
				<crossref let="b" cid="c27011026.1">
				</crossref>
				swept away, and many shall fall down slain.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v27011027">
			</marker>
			<verse num="27">
				And as for the two kings, their hearts shall be bent on doing evil. They shall speak lies at the same table, but to no avail, for 
				<crossref let="c" cid="c27011027.1">
				</crossref>
				the end is yet to be at the time appointed.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v27011028">
			</marker>
			<verse num="28">
				And he shall return to his land with great wealth, but his heart shall be set against the holy covenant. And he shall work his will and return to his own land.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v27011029">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="29">
				<q class="continue-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				At the time appointed he shall return and come into the south, but it shall not be this time as it was before.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v27011030">
			</marker>
			<verse num="30">
				For ships of 
				<crossref let="d" cid="c27011030.1">
				</crossref>
				Kittim shall come against him, and he shall be afraid and withdraw, and shall turn back and 
				<crossref let="e" cid="c27011030.2">
				</crossref>
				be enraged and 
				<crossref let="e" cid="c27011030.3">
				</crossref>
				take action against the holy covenant. He shall turn back and pay attention to those who forsake the holy covenant.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v27011031">
			</marker>
			<verse num="31">
				Forces from him shall appear and 
				<crossref let="f" cid="c27011031.1">
				</crossref>
				profane the temple and fortress, and shall take away the regular burnt offering. And 
				<crossref let="g" cid="c27011031.2">
				</crossref>
				they shall set up the abomination that makes desolate.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v27011032">
			</marker>
			<verse num="32">
				He shall seduce with flattery those who violate the covenant, but the people who know their God shall stand firm and take action.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v27011033">
			</marker>
			<verse num="33">
				<crossref let="h" cid="c27011033.1">
				</crossref>
				And the wise among the people shall make many understand, though for some days they shall stumble by sword and flame, by captivity and plunder.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v27011034">
			</marker>
			<verse num="34">
				When they stumble, they shall receive a little help. And many shall join themselves to them with flattery,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v27011035">
			</marker>
			<verse num="35">
				and some of the wise shall stumble, so that they may be refined, 
				<crossref let="i" cid="c27011035.1">
				</crossref>
				purified, and 
				<crossref let="j" cid="c27011035.2">
				</crossref>
				made white, until 
				<crossref let="k" cid="c27011035.3">
				</crossref>
				the time of the end, 
				<crossref let="k" cid="c27011035.4">
				</crossref>
				for it still awaits the appointed time.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v27011036">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="36">
				<q class="continue-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				And the king shall 
				<crossref let="l" cid="c27011036.1">
				</crossref>
				do as he wills. 
				<crossref let="m" cid="c27011036.2">
				</crossref>
				He shall exalt himself and magnify himself above every god, 
				<crossref let="n" cid="c27011036.3">
				</crossref>
				and shall speak astonishing things against 
				<crossref let="o" cid="c27011036.4">
				</crossref>
				the God of gods. 
				<crossref let="p" cid="c27011036.5">
				</crossref>
				He shall prosper 
				<crossref let="q" cid="c27011036.6">
				</crossref>
				till the indignation is accomplished; for what is decreed shall be done.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v27011037">
			</marker>
			<verse num="37">
				He shall pay no attention to the gods of his fathers, or to the one beloved by women. He shall not pay attention to any other god, for 
				<crossref let="m" cid="c27011037.1">
				</crossref>
				he shall magnify himself above all.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v27011038">
			</marker>
			<verse num="38">
				He shall honor the god of fortresses instead of these. A god whom his fathers did not know he shall honor 
				<crossref let="r" cid="c27011038.1">
				</crossref>
				with gold and silver, with precious stones and costly gifts.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v27011039">
			</marker>
			<verse num="39">
				He shall deal with the strongest fortresses with the help of a foreign god. Those who acknowledge him he shall load with honor. He shall make them rulers over many and 
				<crossref let="s" cid="c27011039.1">
				</crossref>
				shall divide the land for a price.
				<note nid="n27011039.1">
				</note>
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v27011040">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="40">
				<crossref let="t" cid="c27011040.1">
				</crossref>
				<q class="continue-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				At the time of the end, the king of the south shall attack
				<note nid="n27011040.1">
				</note>
				 him, but the king of the north shall rush upon him 
				<crossref let="u" cid="c27011040.2">
				</crossref>
				like a whirlwind, with chariots and horsemen, and with many ships. And he shall come into countries and 
				<crossref let="v" cid="c27011040.3">
				</crossref>
				shall overflow and pass through.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v27011041">
			</marker>
			<verse num="41">
				He shall come into 
				<crossref let="w" cid="c27011041.1">
				</crossref>
				the glorious land. And tens of thousands shall fall, but these shall be delivered out of his hand: 
				<crossref let="x" cid="c27011041.2">
				</crossref>
				Edom and 
				<crossref let="x" cid="c27011041.3">
				</crossref>
				Moab and the main part of the 
				<crossref let="x" cid="c27011041.4">
				</crossref>
				Ammonites.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v27011042">
			</marker>
			<verse num="42">
				He shall stretch out his hand against the countries, and the land of Egypt shall not escape.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v27011043">
			</marker>
			<verse num="43">
				He shall become ruler of the treasures of gold and of silver, and all the precious things of Egypt, and the 
				<crossref let="y" cid="c27011043.1">
				</crossref>
				Libyans and the 
				<crossref let="z" cid="c27011043.2">
				</crossref>
				Cushites shall follow in his train.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v27011044">
			</marker>
			<verse num="44">
				But news from the east and the north shall alarm him, and he shall go out with great fury to destroy and devote many to destruction.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v27011045">
			</marker>
			<verse num="45">
				And he shall pitch his palatial tents between the sea and the glorious holy mountain. Yet he shall come to his end, with none to help him.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
		</chapter>
	</book>
</crossway-bible>


