<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> 
<crossway-bible>
	<book title="Deuteronomy" num="4">
		<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v05020001">
		</marker>
		<chapter num="20">
			<heading
				>
				Laws Concerning Warfare
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="1">
				<q class="continue-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				When you go out to war against your enemies, and see 
				<crossref let="i" cid="c05020001.1">
				</crossref>
				horses and chariots and an army larger than your own, you shall not be afraid of them, for the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 your God is 
				<crossref let="j" cid="c05020001.2">
				</crossref>
				with you, who brought you up out of the land of Egypt.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v05020002">
			</marker>
			<verse num="2">
				And when you draw near to the battle, 
				<crossref let="k" cid="c05020002.1">
				</crossref>
				the priest shall come forward and speak to the people
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v05020003">
			</marker>
			<verse num="3">
				and shall say to them, 
				<q class="begin-single" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Hear, O Israel, today you are drawing near for battle against your enemies: let not your heart faint. Do not fear or panic or be in dread of them,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v05020004">
			</marker>
			<verse num="4">
				for the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 your God is he who goes with you 
				<crossref let="l" cid="c05020004.1">
				</crossref>
				to fight for you against your enemies, to give you the victory.
				<q class="end-single" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v05020005">
			</marker>
			<verse num="5">
				Then the officers shall speak to the people, saying, 
				<q class="begin-single" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Is there any man who has built a new house and has not dedicated it? Let him go back to his house, lest he die in the battle and another man dedicate it.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v05020006">
			</marker>
			<verse num="6">
				And is there any man who has planted a vineyard and has not 
				<crossref let="m" cid="c05020006.1">
				</crossref>
				enjoyed its fruit? Let him go back to his house, lest he die in the battle and another man enjoy its fruit.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v05020007">
			</marker>
			<verse num="7">
				<crossref let="n" cid="c05020007.1">
				</crossref>
				And is there any man who has betrothed a wife and has not taken her? Let him go back to his house, lest he die in the battle and another man take her.
				<q class="end-single" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v05020008">
			</marker>
			<verse num="8">
				And the officers shall speak further to the people, and say, 
				<crossref let="o" cid="c05020008.1">
				</crossref>
				<q class="begin-single" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Is there any man who is fearful and fainthearted? Let him go back to his house, lest he make the heart of his fellows melt like his own.
				<q class="end-single" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v05020009">
			</marker>
			<verse num="9">
				And when the officers have finished speaking to the people, then commanders shall be appointed at the head of the people.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v05020010">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="10">
				<q class="continue-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				When you draw near to a city to fight against it, 
				<crossref let="p" cid="c05020010.1">
				</crossref>
				offer terms of peace to it.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v05020011">
			</marker>
			<verse num="11">
				And if it responds to you peaceably and it opens to you, then all the people who are found in it shall do forced labor for you and shall serve you.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v05020012">
			</marker>
			<verse num="12">
				But if it makes no peace with you, but makes war against you, then you shall besiege it.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v05020013">
			</marker>
			<verse num="13">
				And when the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 your God gives it into your hand, 
				<crossref let="q" cid="c05020013.1">
				</crossref>
				you shall put all its males to the sword,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v05020014">
			</marker>
			<verse num="14">
				<crossref let="r" cid="c05020014.1">
				</crossref>
				but the women and the little ones, the livestock, and everything else in the city, all its spoil, you 
				<crossref let="s" cid="c05020014.2">
				</crossref>
				shall take as plunder for yourselves. And 
				<crossref let="t" cid="c05020014.3">
				</crossref>
				you shall enjoy the spoil of your enemies, which the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 your God has given you.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v05020015">
			</marker>
			<verse num="15">
				Thus you shall do to all the cities that are very far from you, which are not cities of the nations here.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v05020016">
			</marker>
			<verse num="16">
				But 
				<crossref let="u" cid="c05020016.1">
				</crossref>
				in the cities of these peoples that the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 your God is giving you for an inheritance, you shall save alive nothing that breathes,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v05020017">
			</marker>
			<verse num="17">
				but 
				<crossref let="v" cid="c05020017.1">
				</crossref>
				you shall devote them to complete destruction,
				<note nid="n05020017.1">
				</note>
				 the Hittites and the Amorites, the Canaanites and the Perizzites, the Hivites and the Jebusites, as the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 your God has commanded,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v05020018">
			</marker>
			<verse num="18">
				that 
				<crossref let="w" cid="c05020018.1">
				</crossref>
				they may not teach you to do according to all their abominable practices that they have done for their gods, and so you 
				<crossref let="x" cid="c05020018.2">
				</crossref>
				sin against the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 your God.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v05020019">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="19">
				<q class="continue-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				When you besiege a city for a long time, making war against it in order to take it, 
				<crossref let="y" cid="c05020019.1">
				</crossref>
				you shall not destroy its trees by wielding an axe against them. You may eat from them, but you shall not cut them down. Are the trees in the field human, that they should be besieged by you?
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v05020020">
			</marker>
			<verse num="20">
				Only the trees that you know are not trees for food you may destroy and cut down, that you may build siegeworks against the city that makes war with you, until it falls.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
		</chapter>
	</book>
</crossway-bible>


