<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> 
<crossway-bible>
	<book title="Esther" num="16">
		<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17002001">
		</marker>
		<chapter num="2">
			<heading
				>
				Esther Chosen Queen
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="1">
				After these things, 
				<crossref let="t" cid="c17002001.1">
				</crossref>
				when the anger of King Ahasuerus had abated, he remembered Vashti 
				<crossref let="u" cid="c17002001.2">
				</crossref>
				and what she had done and what had been decreed against her.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17002002">
			</marker>
			<verse num="2">
				Then the king's young men who attended him said, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Let beautiful young virgins be sought out for the king.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17002003">
			</marker>
			<verse num="3">
				And let the king appoint officers in all the provinces of his kingdom to gather all the beautiful young virgins to the harem in Susa the capital, under custody of 
				<crossref let="v" cid="c17002003.1">
				</crossref>
				Hegai, the king's eunuch, who is in charge of the women. 
				<crossref let="w" cid="c17002003.2">
				</crossref>
				Let their cosmetics be given them.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17002004">
			</marker>
			<verse num="4">
				And let the young woman who pleases the king be queen instead of Vashti.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				 This pleased the king, and he did so.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17002005">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="5">
				Now there was a Jew in Susa the citadel whose name was 
				<crossref let="x" cid="c17002005.1">
				</crossref>
				Mordecai, the son of Jair, son of Shimei, son of Kish, a Benjaminite,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17002006">
			</marker>
			<verse num="6">
				<crossref let="y" cid="c17002006.1">
				</crossref>
				who had been carried away from Jerusalem among the captives carried away with Jeconiah king of Judah, whom Nebuchadnezzar king of Babylon had carried away.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17002007">
			</marker>
			<verse num="7">
				He was bringing up Hadassah, that is Esther, 
				<crossref let="z" cid="c17002007.1">
				</crossref>
				the daughter of his uncle, for she had neither father nor mother. The young woman had a beautiful figure and was lovely to look at, and when her father and her mother died, Mordecai took her as his own daughter.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17002008">
			</marker>
			<verse num="8">
				So when the king's order and his edict were proclaimed, and 
				<crossref let="a" cid="c17002008.1">
				</crossref>
				when many young women were gathered in Susa the citadel in custody of 
				<crossref let="b" cid="c17002008.2">
				</crossref>
				Hegai, Esther also was taken into the king's palace and put in custody of Hegai, who had charge of the women.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17002009">
			</marker>
			<verse num="9">
				And the young woman pleased him and won his favor. And he quickly provided her 
				<crossref let="c" cid="c17002009.1">
				</crossref>
				with her cosmetics and her portion of food, and with seven chosen young women from the king's palace, and advanced her and her young women to the best place in the harem.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17002010">
			</marker>
			<verse num="10">
				<crossref let="d" cid="c17002010.1">
				</crossref>
				Esther had not made known her people or kindred, for Mordecai had commanded her not to make it known.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17002011">
			</marker>
			<verse num="11">
				And every day Mordecai walked in front of the court of the harem to learn how Esther was and what was happening to her.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17002012">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="12">
				Now when the turn came for each young woman to go in to King Ahasuerus, after being twelve months under the regulations for the women, since this was the regular period of their beautifying, six months with oil of myrrh and six months with spices and ointments for womenù
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17002013">
			</marker>
			<verse num="13">
				when the young woman went in to the king in this way, she was given whatever she desired to take with her from the harem to the king's palace.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17002014">
			</marker>
			<verse num="14">
				In the evening she would go in, and in the morning she would return to the second harem in custody of Shaashgaz, the king's eunuch, who was in charge of the concubines. She would not go in to the king again, unless the king delighted in her and she was summoned by name.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17002015">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="15">
				When the turn came for Esther 
				<crossref let="e" cid="c17002015.1">
				</crossref>
				the daughter of Abihail the uncle of Mordecai, who had taken her as his own daughter, to go in to the king, she asked for nothing except what 
				<crossref let="f" cid="c17002015.2">
				</crossref>
				Hegai the king's eunuch, who had charge of the women, advised. Now Esther was winning favor in the eyes of all who saw her.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17002016">
			</marker>
			<verse num="16">
				And when Esther was taken to King Ahasuerus, into his royal palace, in the tenth month, which is the month of Tebeth, in the seventh year of his reign,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17002017">
			</marker>
			<verse num="17">
				the king loved Esther more than all the women, and she won grace and favor in his sight more than all the virgins, so that he set 
				<crossref let="g" cid="c17002017.1">
				</crossref>
				the royal crown
				<note nid="n17002017.1">
				</note>
				 on her head and made her queen instead of Vashti.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17002018">
			</marker>
			<verse num="18">
				Then the king 
				<crossref let="h" cid="c17002018.1">
				</crossref>
				gave a great feast for all his officials and servants; it was Esther's feast. He also granted a remission of taxes to the provinces and gave gifts with royal generosity.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17002019">
			</marker>
			<heading
				>
				Mordecai Discovers a Plot
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="19">
				Now when the virgins were gathered together 
				<crossref let="i" cid="c17002019.1">
				</crossref>
				the second time, Mordecai was sitting 
				<crossref let="j" cid="c17002019.2">
				</crossref>
				at the king's gate.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17002020">
			</marker>
			<verse num="20">
				<crossref let="k" cid="c17002020.1">
				</crossref>
				Esther had not made known her kindred or her people, as Mordecai had commanded her, for Esther obeyed Mordecai just 
				<crossref let="l" cid="c17002020.2">
				</crossref>
				as when she was brought up by him.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17002021">
			</marker>
			<verse num="21">
				In those days, as Mordecai was sitting at the king's gate, 
				<crossref let="m" cid="c17002021.1">
				</crossref>
				Bigthan and 
				<crossref let="n" cid="c17002021.2">
				</crossref>
				Teresh, two of the king's eunuchs, who guarded the threshold, became angry and sought to lay hands on King Ahasuerus.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17002022">
			</marker>
			<verse num="22">
				And this came to the knowledge of Mordecai, 
				<crossref let="o" cid="c17002022.1">
				</crossref>
				and he told it to Queen Esther, and Esther told the king in the name of Mordecai.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17002023">
			</marker>
			<verse num="23">
				When the affair was investigated and found to be so, the men were both hanged on the gallows.
				<note nid="n17002023.1">
				</note>
				 And it was recorded in 
				<crossref let="p" cid="c17002023.1">
				</crossref>
				the book of the chronicles in the presence of the king.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
		</chapter>
	</book>
</crossway-bible>


