<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> 
<crossway-bible>
	<book title="Esther" num="17">
		<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17001001">
		</marker>
		<chapter num="1">
			<heading
				>
				The King's Banquets
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="1">
				Now in the days of Ahasuerus, the Ahasuerus who reigned 
				<crossref let="a" cid="c17001001.1">
				</crossref>
				from India to Ethiopia over 
				<crossref let="b" cid="c17001001.2">
				</crossref>
				127 provinces,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17001002">
			</marker>
			<verse num="2">
				in those days when King Ahasuerus 
				<crossref let="c" cid="c17001002.1">
				</crossref>
				sat on his royal throne in 
				<crossref let="d" cid="c17001002.2">
				</crossref>
				Susa, the capital,
				<note nid="n17001002.1">
				</note>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17001003">
			</marker>
			<verse num="3">
				in the third year of his reign 
				<crossref let="e" cid="c17001003.1">
				</crossref>
				he gave a feast for all his officials and servants. The army of Persia and Media and the nobles and governors of the provinces were before him,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17001004">
			</marker>
			<verse num="4">
				while he showed the riches of his royal glory and the splendor and pomp of his greatness for many days, 180 days.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17001005">
			</marker>
			<verse num="5">
				And when these days were completed, the king gave for all the people present in Susa, the citadel, both great and small, a feast lasting for seven days in the court of 
				<crossref let="f" cid="c17001005.1">
				</crossref>
				the garden of the king's palace.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17001006">
			</marker>
			<verse num="6">
				There were white cotton curtains and violet hangings fastened with cords of fine linen and purple to silver rods
				<note nid="n17001006.1">
				</note>
				 and marble pillars, and also 
				<crossref let="g" cid="c17001006.1">
				</crossref>
				couches of gold and silver on a mosaic pavement of porphyry, marble, mother-of-pearl and precious stones.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17001007">
			</marker>
			<verse num="7">
				Drinks were served in golden vessels, vessels of different kinds, and the royal wine was lavished according to the bounty of the king.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17001008">
			</marker>
			<verse num="8">
				And drinking was according to this edict: 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				There is no compulsion.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				 For the king had given orders to all the staff of his palace to do as each man desired.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17001009">
			</marker>
			<verse num="9">
				Queen Vashti also gave a feast for the women in the palace that belonged to King Ahasuerus.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17001010">
			</marker>
			<heading
				>
				Queen Vashti's Refusal
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="10">
				On the seventh day, 
				<crossref let="h" cid="c17001010.1">
				</crossref>
				when the heart of the king was merry with wine, he commanded Mehuman, Biztha, 
				<crossref let="i" cid="c17001010.2">
				</crossref>
				Harbona, 
				<crossref let="j" cid="c17001010.3">
				</crossref>
				Bigtha and Abagtha, Zethar and Carkas, the seven eunuchs who served in the presence of King Ahasuerus,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17001011">
			</marker>
			<verse num="11">
				to bring Queen Vashti before the king with 
				<crossref let="k" cid="c17001011.1">
				</crossref>
				her royal crown,
				<note nid="n17001011.1">
				</note>
				 in order to show the peoples and the princes her beauty, for she was lovely to look at.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17001012">
			</marker>
			<verse num="12">
				But Queen Vashti refused to come at the king's command delivered by the eunuchs. At this the king became enraged, and his anger burned within him.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17001013">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="13">
				Then the king said to 
				<crossref let="l" cid="c17001013.1">
				</crossref>
				the wise men 
				<crossref let="m" cid="c17001013.2">
				</crossref>
				who knew the times (for this was the king's procedure toward all who were versed in law and judgment,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17001014">
			</marker>
			<verse num="14">
				the men next to him being Carshena, Shethar, Admatha, Tarshish, Meres, Marsena, and 
				<crossref let="n" cid="c17001014.1">
				</crossref>
				Memucan, 
				<crossref let="o" cid="c17001014.2">
				</crossref>
				the seven princes of Persia and Media, 
				<crossref let="p" cid="c17001014.3">
				</crossref>
				who saw the king's face, and sat first in the kingdom):
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17001015">
			</marker>
			<verse num="15">
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				According to the law, what is to be done to Queen Vashti, because she has not performed the command of King Ahasuerus delivered by the eunuchs?
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17001016">
			</marker>
			<verse num="16">
				Then Memucan said in the presence of the king and the officials, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Not only against the king has Queen Vashti done wrong, but also against all the officials and all the peoples who are in all the provinces of King Ahasuerus.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17001017">
			</marker>
			<verse num="17">
				For the queen's behavior will be made known to all women, causing them to look at their husbands with contempt, since they will say, 
				<q class="begin-single" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				King Ahasuerus commanded Queen Vashti to be brought before him, and she did not come.
				<q class="end-single" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17001018">
			</marker>
			<verse num="18">
				This very day the noble women of Persia and Media who have heard of the queen's behavior will say the same to all the king's officials, and there will be contempt and wrath in plenty.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17001019">
			</marker>
			<verse num="19">
				If it please the king, let a royal order go out from him, and let it be written among the laws of the Persians and the Medes so 
				<crossref let="q" cid="c17001019.1">
				</crossref>
				that it may not be repealed, that Vashti is never again to come before King Ahasuerus. And let the king give her royal position to another who is better than she.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17001020">
			</marker>
			<verse num="20">
				So when the decree made by the king is proclaimed throughout all his kingdom, for it is vast, 
				<crossref let="r" cid="c17001020.1">
				</crossref>
				all women will give honor to their husbands, high and low alike.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17001021">
			</marker>
			<verse num="21">
				This advice pleased the king and the princes, and the king did as Memucan proposed.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17001022">
			</marker>
			<verse num="22">
				He sent letters to all the royal provinces, 
				<crossref let="s" cid="c17001022.1">
				</crossref>
				to every province in its own script and to every people in its own language, that every man be master in his own household and speak according to the language of his people.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
		</chapter>
	</book>
</crossway-bible>


