<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> 
<crossway-bible>
	<book title="Esther" num="16">
		<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17009001">
		</marker>
		<chapter num="9">
			<heading
				>
				The Jews Destroy Their Enemies
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="1">
				<crossref let="s" cid="c17009001.1">
				</crossref>
				Now in the twelfth month, which is the month of Adar, 
				<crossref let="t" cid="c17009001.2">
				</crossref>
				on the thirteenth day of the same, 
				<crossref let="u" cid="c17009001.3">
				</crossref>
				when the king's command and edict were about to be carried out, 
				<crossref let="j" cid="c17009001.4">
				</crossref>
				on the very day when the enemies of the Jews hoped to gain the mastery over them, the reverse occurred: the Jews gained mastery over those who hated them.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17009002">
			</marker>
			<verse num="2">
				<crossref let="v" cid="c17009002.1">
				</crossref>
				The Jews gathered in their cities throughout all the provinces of King Ahasuerus to lay hands on those who sought their harm. And no one could stand against them, 
				<crossref let="w" cid="c17009002.2">
				</crossref>
				for the fear of them had fallen on all peoples.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17009003">
			</marker>
			<verse num="3">
				All the officials of the provinces and 
				<crossref let="x" cid="c17009003.1">
				</crossref>
				the satraps and the governors and the royal agents also helped the Jews, for the fear of Mordecai had fallen on them.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17009004">
			</marker>
			<verse num="4">
				For Mordecai was great in the king's house, and his fame spread throughout all the provinces, for the man Mordecai grew 
				<crossref let="y" cid="c17009004.1">
				</crossref>
				more and more powerful.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17009005">
			</marker>
			<verse num="5">
				The Jews struck all their enemies with the sword, killing and destroying them, and did as they pleased to those who hated them.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17009006">
			</marker>
			<verse num="6">
				In Susa the citadel itself the Jews killed and destroyed 500 men,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17009007">
			</marker>
			<verse num="7">
				and also killed Parshandatha and Dalphon and Aspatha
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17009008">
			</marker>
			<verse num="8">
				and Poratha and Adalia and Aridatha
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17009009">
			</marker>
			<verse num="9">
				and Parmashta and Arisai and Aridai and Vaizatha,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17009010">
			</marker>
			<verse num="10">
				<crossref let="z" cid="c17009010.1">
				</crossref>
				the ten sons of Haman the son of Hammedatha, 
				<crossref let="a" cid="c17009010.2">
				</crossref>
				the enemy of the Jews, 
				<crossref let="b" cid="c17009010.3">
				</crossref>
				but they laid no hand on the plunder.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17009011">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="11">
				That very day the number of those killed in Susa the citadel was reported to the king.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17009012">
			</marker>
			<verse num="12">
				And the king said to Queen Esther, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				In Susa the citadel the Jews have killed and destroyed 500 men and also the ten sons of Haman. What then have they done in the rest of the king's provinces! 
				<crossref let="c" cid="c17009012.1">
				</crossref>
				Now what is your wish? It shall be granted you. And what further is your request? It shall be fulfilled.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17009013">
			</marker>
			<verse num="13">
				And Esther said, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				If it please the king, let the Jews who are in Susa be allowed 
				<crossref let="d" cid="c17009013.1">
				</crossref>
				tomorrow also to do according to this day's edict. And let the ten sons of Haman be hanged on the gallows.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				<note nid="n17009013.1">
				</note>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17009014">
			</marker>
			<verse num="14">
				So the king commanded this to be done. A decree was issued in Susa, and the ten sons of Haman were hanged.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17009015">
			</marker>
			<verse num="15">
				The Jews who were in Susa gathered also on the fourteenth day of the month of Adar and they killed 300 men in Susa, but they laid no hands on the plunder.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17009016">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="16">
				<crossref let="e" cid="c17009016.1">
				</crossref>
				Now the rest of the Jews who were in the king's provinces also 
				<crossref let="f" cid="c17009016.2">
				</crossref>
				gathered to defend their lives, and got relief from their enemies and killed 75,000 of those who hated them, but they laid no hands on the plunder.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17009017">
			</marker>
			<verse num="17">
				This was 
				<crossref let="g" cid="c17009017.1">
				</crossref>
				on the thirteenth day of the month of Adar, and on the fourteenth day they rested and made that a day of feasting and gladness.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17009018">
			</marker>
			<verse num="18">
				But the Jews who were in Susa gathered 
				<crossref let="g" cid="c17009018.1">
				</crossref>
				on the thirteenth day and on the fourteenth, and rested 
				<crossref let="h" cid="c17009018.2">
				</crossref>
				on the fifteenth day, making that a day of feasting and gladness.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17009019">
			</marker>
			<verse num="19">
				Therefore the Jews of the villages, who live in 
				<crossref let="i" cid="c17009019.1">
				</crossref>
				the rural towns, hold the fourteenth day of the month of Adar as a day for gladness and feasting, as 
				<crossref let="j" cid="c17009019.2">
				</crossref>
				a holiday, and 
				<crossref let="k" cid="c17009019.3">
				</crossref>
				as a day on which they send gifts of food to one another.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17009020">
			</marker>
			<heading
				>
				The Feast of Purim Inaugurated
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="20">
				And Mordecai recorded these things and sent letters to all the Jews who were in all the provinces of King Ahasuerus, both near and far,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17009021">
			</marker>
			<verse num="21">
				obliging them to keep the fourteenth day of the month Adar and also the fifteenth day of the same, year by year,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17009022">
			</marker>
			<verse num="22">
				as the days on which the Jews got relief from their enemies, and as the month that had been turned for them from sorrow into gladness and from mourning into 
				<crossref let="j" cid="c17009022.1">
				</crossref>
				a holiday; that they should make them days of feasting and gladness, days for sending gifts of food to one another and gifts to the poor.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17009023">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="23">
				So the Jews accepted what they had started to do, and what Mordecai had written to them.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17009024">
			</marker>
			<verse num="24">
				For Haman the Agagite, the son of Hammedatha, 
				<crossref let="l" cid="c17009024.1">
				</crossref>
				the enemy of all the Jews, 
				<crossref let="m" cid="c17009024.2">
				</crossref>
				had plotted against the Jews to destroy them, and 
				<crossref let="n" cid="c17009024.3">
				</crossref>
				had cast Pur (that is, cast lots), to crush and to destroy them.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17009025">
			</marker>
			<verse num="25">
				But when it came before the king, he gave orders in writing 
				<crossref let="o" cid="c17009025.1">
				</crossref>
				that his evil plan that he had devised against the Jews 
				<crossref let="p" cid="c17009025.2">
				</crossref>
				should return on his own head, and that he and his sons should be hanged on the gallows.
				<note nid="n17009025.1">
				</note>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17009026">
			</marker>
			<verse num="26">
				Therefore they called these days Purim, after the term 
				<crossref let="n" cid="c17009026.1">
				</crossref>
				Pur. Therefore, because of all that was written in 
				<crossref let="q" cid="c17009026.2">
				</crossref>
				this letter, and of what they had faced in this matter, and of what had happened to them,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17009027">
			</marker>
			<verse num="27">
				the Jews firmly obligated themselves and their offspring and 
				<crossref let="r" cid="c17009027.1">
				</crossref>
				all who joined them, that without fail they would keep 
				<crossref let="s" cid="c17009027.2">
				</crossref>
				these two days according to what was written and at the time appointed every year,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17009028">
			</marker>
			<verse num="28">
				that these days should be remembered and kept throughout every generation, in every clan, province, and city, and that these days of Purim should never fall into disuse among the Jews, nor should the commemoration of these days cease among their descendants.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17009029">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="29">
				Then Queen Esther, 
				<crossref let="t" cid="c17009029.1">
				</crossref>
				the daughter of Abihail, and Mordecai the Jew gave full written authority, confirming 
				<crossref let="u" cid="c17009029.2">
				</crossref>
				this second letter about Purim.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17009030">
			</marker>
			<verse num="30">
				Letters were sent to all the Jews, 
				<crossref let="v" cid="c17009030.1">
				</crossref>
				to the 127 provinces of the kingdom of Ahasuerus, in words of peace and truth,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17009031">
			</marker>
			<verse num="31">
				that these days of Purim should be observed at their appointed seasons, as Mordecai the Jew and Queen Esther obligated them, and as they had obligated themselves and their offspring, with regard to 
				<crossref let="w" cid="c17009031.1">
				</crossref>
				their fasts and their lamenting.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v17009032">
			</marker>
			<verse num="32">
				The command of Queen Esther confirmed these practices of 
				<crossref let="x" cid="c17009032.1">
				</crossref>
				Purim, and it was recorded in writing.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
		</chapter>
	</book>
</crossway-bible>


