<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> 
<crossway-bible>
	<book title="Exodus" num="1">
		<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02028001">
		</marker>
		<chapter num="28">
			<heading
				>
				The Priests' Garments
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="1">
				<q class="continue-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Then bring near to you 
				<crossref let="x" cid="c02028001.1">
				</crossref>
				Aaron your brother, and his sons with him, from among the people of Israel, to serve me as priestsùAaron and Aaron's sons, 
				<crossref let="y" cid="c02028001.2">
				</crossref>
				Nadab and Abihu, Eleazar and Ithamar.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02028002">
			</marker>
			<verse num="2">
				<crossref let="z" cid="c02028002.1">
				</crossref>
				And you shall make holy garments for Aaron your brother, for glory and for beauty.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02028003">
			</marker>
			<verse num="3">
				You shall speak to all the 
				<crossref let="a" cid="c02028003.1">
				</crossref>
				skillful, whom I have filled with a spirit of skill, that they make Aaron's garments to consecrate him for my priesthood.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02028004">
			</marker>
			<verse num="4">
				These are the garments that they shall make: a 
				<crossref let="b" cid="c02028004.1">
				</crossref>
				breastpiece, an 
				<crossref let="c" cid="c02028004.2">
				</crossref>
				ephod, 
				<crossref let="d" cid="c02028004.3">
				</crossref>
				a robe, 
				<crossref let="e" cid="c02028004.4">
				</crossref>
				a coat of checker work, 
				<crossref let="e" cid="c02028004.5">
				</crossref>
				a turban, and 
				<crossref let="e" cid="c02028004.6">
				</crossref>
				a sash. They shall make holy garments for Aaron your brother and his sons to serve me as priests.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02028005">
			</marker>
			<verse num="5">
				They shall receive 
				<crossref let="f" cid="c02028005.1">
				</crossref>
				gold, blue and purple and scarlet yarns, and fine twined linen.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02028006">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="6">
				<crossref let="g" cid="c02028006.1">
				</crossref>
				<q class="continue-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				And they shall make the ephod of gold, of blue and purple and scarlet yarns, and of fine twined linen, skillfully worked.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02028007">
			</marker>
			<verse num="7">
				It shall have two shoulder pieces attached to its two edges, so that it may be joined together.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02028008">
			</marker>
			<verse num="8">
				And the 
				<crossref let="h" cid="c02028008.1">
				</crossref>
				skillfully woven band on it shall be made like it and be of one piece with it, of gold, blue and purple and scarlet yarns, and fine twined linen.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02028009">
			</marker>
			<verse num="9">
				You shall take two onyx stones, and engrave on them the names of the sons of Israel,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02028010">
			</marker>
			<verse num="10">
				six of their names on the one stone, and the names of the remaining six on the other stone, in the order of their birth.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02028011">
			</marker>
			<verse num="11">
				As a jeweler engraves signets, so shall you engrave the two stones with the names of the sons of Israel. You shall enclose them in settings of gold filigree.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02028012">
			</marker>
			<verse num="12">
				And you shall set the two stones on the shoulder pieces of the ephod, as stones of remembrance for the sons of Israel. And 
				<crossref let="i" cid="c02028012.1">
				</crossref>
				Aaron shall bear their names before the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 on his two shoulders 
				<crossref let="j" cid="c02028012.2">
				</crossref>
				for remembrance.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02028013">
			</marker>
			<verse num="13">
				You shall make settings of gold filigree,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02028014">
			</marker>
			<verse num="14">
				and two chains of pure gold, twisted like cords; and you shall attach the corded chains to the settings.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02028015">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="15">
				<crossref let="k" cid="c02028015.1">
				</crossref>
				<q class="continue-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				You shall make a breastpiece of judgment, in skilled work. In the style of the ephod you shall make itùof gold, blue and purple and scarlet yarns, and fine twined linen shall you make it.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02028016">
			</marker>
			<verse num="16">
				It shall be square and doubled, a span
				<note nid="n02028016.1">
				</note>
				 its length and a span its breadth.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02028017">
			</marker>
			<verse num="17">
				<crossref let="l" cid="c02028017.1">
				</crossref>
				You shall set in it four rows of stones. A row of sardius,
				<note nid="n02028017.1">
				</note>
				 topaz, and carbuncle shall be the first row;
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02028018">
			</marker>
			<verse num="18">
				and the second row an emerald, a sapphire, and a diamond;
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02028019">
			</marker>
			<verse num="19">
				and the third row a jacinth, an agate, and an amethyst;
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02028020">
			</marker>
			<verse num="20">
				and the fourth row a beryl, an onyx, and a jasper. They shall be set in gold filigree.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02028021">
			</marker>
			<verse num="21">
				There shall be twelve stones with their names according to the names of the sons of Israel. They shall be like signets, each engraved with its name, for the twelve tribes.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02028022">
			</marker>
			<verse num="22">
				You shall make for the breastpiece twisted chains like cords, of pure gold.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02028023">
			</marker>
			<verse num="23">
				And you shall make for the breastpiece two rings of gold, and put the two rings on the two edges of the breastpiece.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02028024">
			</marker>
			<verse num="24">
				And you shall put the two cords of gold in the two rings at the edges of the breastpiece.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02028025">
			</marker>
			<verse num="25">
				The two ends of the two cords you shall attach to the two settings of filigree, and so attach it in front to the shoulder pieces of the ephod.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02028026">
			</marker>
			<verse num="26">
				You shall make two rings of gold, and put them at the two ends of the breastpiece, on its inside edge next to the ephod.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02028027">
			</marker>
			<verse num="27">
				And you shall make two rings of gold, and attach them in front to the lower part of the two shoulder pieces of the ephod, at its seam above the 
				<crossref let="m" cid="c02028027.1">
				</crossref>
				skillfully woven band of the ephod.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02028028">
			</marker>
			<verse num="28">
				And they shall bind the breastpiece by its rings to the rings of the ephod with a lace of blue, so that it may lie on the skillfully woven band of the ephod, so that the breastpiece shall not come loose from the ephod.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02028029">
			</marker>
			<verse num="29">
				<crossref let="n" cid="c02028029.1">
				</crossref>
				So Aaron shall bear the names of the sons of Israel in the breastpiece of judgment on his heart, when he goes into the Holy Place, to bring them to regular 
				<crossref let="o" cid="c02028029.2">
				</crossref>
				remembrance before the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02028030">
			</marker>
			<verse num="30">
				And in the breastpiece of judgment 
				<crossref let="p" cid="c02028030.1">
				</crossref>
				you shall put the Urim and the Thummim, and they shall be on Aaron's heart, when he goes in before the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				. Thus Aaron shall bear the judgment of the people of Israel on his heart before the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 regularly.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02028031">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="31">
				<crossref let="q" cid="c02028031.1">
				</crossref>
				<q class="continue-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				You shall make the robe of the ephod all of blue.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02028032">
			</marker>
			<verse num="32">
				It shall have an opening for the head in the middle of it, with a woven binding around the opening, like the opening in a garment,
				<note nid="n02028032.1">
				</note>
				 so that it may not tear.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02028033">
			</marker>
			<verse num="33">
				On its hem you shall make pomegranates of blue and purple and scarlet yarns, around its hem, with bells of gold between them,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02028034">
			</marker>
			<verse num="34">
				a golden bell and a pomegranate, a golden bell and a pomegranate, around the hem of the robe.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02028035">
			</marker>
			<verse num="35">
				And it shall be on Aaron when he ministers, and its sound shall be heard when he goes into the Holy Place before the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				, and when he comes out, so that he does not die.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02028036">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="36">
				<q class="continue-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				You shall make 
				<crossref let="r" cid="c02028036.1">
				</crossref>
				a plate of pure gold and engrave on it, like the engraving of a signet, 
				<crossref let="s" cid="c02028036.2">
				</crossref>
				<q class="begin-single" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Holy to the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				.
				<q class="end-single" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02028037">
			</marker>
			<verse num="37">
				And you shall fasten it on the turban by a cord of blue. It shall be on the front of the turban.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02028038">
			</marker>
			<verse num="38">
				It shall be on Aaron's forehead, and Aaron shall 
				<crossref let="t" cid="c02028038.1">
				</crossref>
				bear any guilt from the holy things that the people of Israel consecrate as their holy gifts. It shall regularly be on his forehead, that they may be accepted before the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02028039">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="39">
				<q class="continue-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				You shall weave the coat in checker work of fine linen, and you shall make a turban of fine linen, and you shall make a sash embroidered with needlework.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02028040">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="40">
				<crossref let="u" cid="c02028040.1">
				</crossref>
				<q class="continue-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				For Aaron's sons you shall make coats and sashes and caps. You shall make them 
				<crossref let="v" cid="c02028040.2">
				</crossref>
				for glory and beauty.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02028041">
			</marker>
			<verse num="41">
				And you shall put them on Aaron your brother, and on his sons with him, and shall 
				<crossref let="w" cid="c02028041.1">
				</crossref>
				anoint them and ordain them and 
				<crossref let="x" cid="c02028041.2">
				</crossref>
				consecrate them, that they may serve me as priests.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02028042">
			</marker>
			<verse num="42">
				You shall make for them 
				<crossref let="y" cid="c02028042.1">
				</crossref>
				linen undergarments to cover their naked flesh. They shall reach from the hips to the thighs;
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02028043">
			</marker>
			<verse num="43">
				and they shall be on Aaron and on his sons when they go into the tent of meeting or when they come near the altar to minister in the Holy Place, lest they 
				<crossref let="z" cid="c02028043.1">
				</crossref>
				bear guilt and die. 
				<crossref let="a" cid="c02028043.2">
				</crossref>
				This shall be a statute forever for him and for his offspring after him.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
		</chapter>
	</book>
</crossway-bible>


