<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> 
<crossway-bible>
	<book title="Exodus" num="1">
		<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02027001">
		</marker>
		<chapter num="27">
			<heading
				>
				The Bronze Altar
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="1">
				<q class="continue-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				You shall make the 
				<crossref let="n" cid="c02027001.1">
				</crossref>
				altar of acacia wood, five cubits
				<note nid="n02027001.1">
				</note>
				 long and five cubits broad. The altar shall be square, and its height shall be three cubits.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02027002">
			</marker>
			<verse num="2">
				And you shall make 
				<crossref let="o" cid="c02027002.1">
				</crossref>
				horns for it on its four corners; its horns shall be of one piece with it, and 
				<crossref let="p" cid="c02027002.2">
				</crossref>
				you shall overlay it with bronze.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02027003">
			</marker>
			<verse num="3">
				You shall make pots for it to receive its ashes, and shovels and basins and 
				<crossref let="q" cid="c02027003.1">
				</crossref>
				forks and fire pans. You shall make all its utensils of bronze.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02027004">
			</marker>
			<verse num="4">
				You shall also make for it a grating, a network of bronze, and on the net you shall make four bronze rings at its four corners.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02027005">
			</marker>
			<verse num="5">
				And you shall set it under the ledge of the altar so that the net extends halfway down the altar.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02027006">
			</marker>
			<verse num="6">
				And you shall make poles for the altar, poles of acacia wood, and overlay them with bronze.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02027007">
			</marker>
			<verse num="7">
				And the poles shall be put through the rings, so that the poles are on the two sides of the altar when it is carried.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02027008">
			</marker>
			<verse num="8">
				You shall make it hollow, with boards. 
				<crossref let="r" cid="c02027008.1">
				</crossref>
				As it has been shown you on the mountain, so shall it be made.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02027009">
			</marker>
			<heading
				>
				The Court of the Tabernacle
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="9">
				<crossref let="s" cid="c02027009.1">
				</crossref>
				<q class="continue-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				You shall make the court of the tabernacle. On the south side the court shall have hangings of fine twined linen a hundred cubits long for one side.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02027010">
			</marker>
			<verse num="10">
				Its twenty pillars and their twenty bases shall be of bronze, but the hooks of the pillars and their fillets shall be of silver.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02027011">
			</marker>
			<verse num="11">
				And likewise for its length on the north side there shall be hangings a hundred cubits long, its pillars twenty and their bases twenty, of bronze, but the hooks of the pillars and their fillets shall be of silver.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02027012">
			</marker>
			<verse num="12">
				And for the breadth of the court on the west side there shall be hangings for fifty cubits, with ten pillars and ten bases.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02027013">
			</marker>
			<verse num="13">
				The breadth of the court on the front to the east shall be fifty cubits.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02027014">
			</marker>
			<verse num="14">
				The hangings for the one side of the gate shall be fifteen cubits, with their three pillars and three bases.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02027015">
			</marker>
			<verse num="15">
				On the other side the hangings shall be fifteen cubits, with their three pillars and three bases.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02027016">
			</marker>
			<verse num="16">
				For the gate of the court there shall be 
				<crossref let="t" cid="c02027016.1">
				</crossref>
				a screen twenty cubits long, of blue and purple and scarlet yarns and fine twined linen, embroidered with needlework. It shall have four pillars and with them four bases.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02027017">
			</marker>
			<verse num="17">
				All the pillars around the court shall be filleted with silver. Their hooks shall be of silver, and their bases of bronze.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02027018">
			</marker>
			<verse num="18">
				The length of the court shall be a hundred cubits, the breadth fifty, and the height five cubits, with hangings of fine twined linen and bases of bronze.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02027019">
			</marker>
			<verse num="19">
				All the utensils of the tabernacle for every use, and all its pegs and all the pegs of the court, shall be of bronze.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02027020">
			</marker>
			<heading
				>
				Oil for the Lamp
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="20">
				<crossref let="u" cid="c02027020.1">
				</crossref>
				<q class="continue-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				You shall command the people of Israel that they bring to you pure beaten olive oil for the light, that a lamp may regularly be set up to burn.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02027021">
			</marker>
			<verse num="21">
				<crossref let="v" cid="c02027021.1">
				</crossref>
				In the tent of meeting, 
				<crossref let="w" cid="c02027021.2">
				</crossref>
				outside the veil that is before the testimony, Aaron and his sons shall tend it from evening to morning before the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				. It shall be a statute forever to be observed throughout their generations by the people of Israel.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
		</chapter>
	</book>
</crossway-bible>


