<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> 
<crossway-bible>
	<book title="Exodus" num="1">
		<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02038001">
		</marker>
		<chapter num="38">
			<heading
				>
				Making the Altar of Burnt Offering
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="1">
				<crossref let="z" cid="c02038001.1">
				</crossref>
				He made the altar of burnt offering of acacia wood. Five cubits
				<note nid="n02038001.1">
				</note>
				 was its length, and five cubits its breadth. It was square, and three cubits was its height.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02038002">
			</marker>
			<verse num="2">
				He made horns for it on its four corners. Its horns were of one piece with it, and he overlaid it with bronze.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02038003">
			</marker>
			<verse num="3">
				And he made all the utensils of the altar, the pots, the shovels, the basins, the forks, and the fire pans. He made all its utensils of bronze.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02038004">
			</marker>
			<verse num="4">
				And he made for the altar a grating, a network of bronze, under its ledge, extending halfway down.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02038005">
			</marker>
			<verse num="5">
				He cast four rings on the four corners of the bronze grating as holders for the poles.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02038006">
			</marker>
			<verse num="6">
				He made the poles of acacia wood and overlaid them with bronze.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02038007">
			</marker>
			<verse num="7">
				And he put the poles through the rings on the sides of the altar to carry it with them. He made it hollow, with boards.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02038008">
			</marker>
			<heading
				>
				Making the Bronze Basin
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="8">
				<crossref let="a" cid="c02038008.1">
				</crossref>
				He made the basin of bronze and its stand of bronze, from the mirrors of the 
				<crossref let="b" cid="c02038008.2">
				</crossref>
				ministering women who ministered in the entrance of the tent of meeting.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02038009">
			</marker>
			<heading
				>
				Making the Court
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="9">
				<crossref let="c" cid="c02038009.1">
				</crossref>
				And he made the court. For the south side the hangings of the court were of fine twined linen, a hundred cubits;
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02038010">
			</marker>
			<verse num="10">
				their twenty pillars and their twenty bases were of bronze, but the hooks of the pillars and their fillets were of silver.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02038011">
			</marker>
			<verse num="11">
				And for the north side there were hangings of a hundred cubits, their twenty pillars, their twenty bases were of bronze, but the hooks of the pillars and their fillets were of silver.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02038012">
			</marker>
			<verse num="12">
				And for the west side were hangings of fifty cubits, their ten pillars, and their ten bases; the hooks of the pillars and their fillets were of silver.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02038013">
			</marker>
			<verse num="13">
				And for the front to the east, fifty cubits.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02038014">
			</marker>
			<verse num="14">
				The hangings for one side of the gate were fifteen cubits, with their three pillars and three bases.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02038015">
			</marker>
			<verse num="15">
				And so for the other side. On both sides of the gate of the court were hangings of fifteen cubits, with their three pillars and their three bases.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02038016">
			</marker>
			<verse num="16">
				All the hangings around the court were of fine twined linen.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02038017">
			</marker>
			<verse num="17">
				And the bases for the pillars were of bronze, but the hooks of the pillars and their fillets were of silver. The overlaying of their capitals was also of silver, and all the pillars of the court were filleted with silver.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02038018">
			</marker>
			<verse num="18">
				And the screen for the gate of the court was embroidered with needlework in blue and purple and scarlet yarns and fine twined linen. It was twenty cubits long and five cubits high in its breadth, corresponding to the hangings of the court.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02038019">
			</marker>
			<verse num="19">
				And their pillars were four in number. Their four bases were of bronze, their hooks of silver, and the overlaying of their capitals and their fillets of silver.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02038020">
			</marker>
			<verse num="20">
				And all the pegs for the tabernacle and for the court all around were of bronze.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02038021">
			</marker>
			<heading
				>
				Materials for the Tabernacle
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="21">
				These are the records of the tabernacle, 
				<crossref let="d" cid="c02038021.1">
				</crossref>
				the tabernacle of the testimony, as they were recorded at the commandment of Moses, the responsibility of the Levites 
				<crossref let="e" cid="c02038021.2">
				</crossref>
				under the direction of Ithamar the son of Aaron the priest.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02038022">
			</marker>
			<verse num="22">
				<crossref let="f" cid="c02038022.1">
				</crossref>
				Bezalel the son of Uri, son of Hur, of the tribe of Judah, made all that the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 commanded Moses;
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02038023">
			</marker>
			<verse num="23">
				and with him was 
				<crossref let="f" cid="c02038023.1">
				</crossref>
				Oholiab the son of Ahisamach, of the tribe of Dan, an engraver and designer and embroiderer in blue and purple and scarlet yarns and fine twined linen.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02038024">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="24">
				All the gold that was used for the work, in all the construction of the sanctuary, the gold from the offering, was twenty-nine talents and 730 shekels,
				<note nid="n02038024.1">
				</note>
				 by 
				<crossref let="g" cid="c02038024.1">
				</crossref>
				the shekel of the sanctuary.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02038025">
			</marker>
			<verse num="25">
				The silver from those of the congregation who were recorded was a hundred talents and 1,775 shekels, by the shekel of the sanctuary:
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02038026">
			</marker>
			<verse num="26">
				a 
				<crossref let="g" cid="c02038026.1">
				</crossref>
				beka
				<note nid="n02038026.1">
				</note>
				 a head (that is, half a shekel, by the shekel of the sanctuary), for everyone who was listed in the records, from twenty years old and upward, for 
				<crossref let="h" cid="c02038026.2">
				</crossref>
				603,550 men.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02038027">
			</marker>
			<verse num="27">
				The hundred talents of silver were for casting the 
				<crossref let="i" cid="c02038027.1">
				</crossref>
				bases of the sanctuary and the bases of the veil; a hundred bases for the hundred talents, a talent a base.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02038028">
			</marker>
			<verse num="28">
				And of the 1,775 shekels he made hooks for the pillars and overlaid their capitals and made fillets for them.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02038029">
			</marker>
			<verse num="29">
				The bronze that was offered was seventy talents and 2,400 shekels;
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02038030">
			</marker>
			<verse num="30">
				with it he made the 
				<crossref let="j" cid="c02038030.1">
				</crossref>
				bases for the entrance of the tent of meeting, 
				<crossref let="k" cid="c02038030.2">
				</crossref>
				the bronze altar and the bronze grating for it and all the utensils of the altar,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v02038031">
			</marker>
			<verse num="31">
				the 
				<crossref let="l" cid="c02038031.1">
				</crossref>
				bases around the court, and the 
				<crossref let="m" cid="c02038031.2">
				</crossref>
				bases of the gate of the court, all the 
				<crossref let="n" cid="c02038031.3">
				</crossref>
				pegs of the tabernacle, and all the pegs around the court.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
		</chapter>
	</book>
</crossway-bible>


