<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> 
<crossway-bible>
	<book title="Genesis" num="0">
		<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v01008001">
		</marker>
		<chapter num="8">
			<heading
				>
				The Flood Subsides
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="1">
				But God 
				<crossref let="d" cid="c01008001.1">
				</crossref>
				remembered Noah and all the beasts and all the livestock that were with him in the ark. And 
				<crossref let="e" cid="c01008001.2">
				</crossref>
				God made a wind blow over the earth, and the waters subsided.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v01008002">
			</marker>
			<verse num="2">
				<crossref let="f" cid="c01008002.1">
				</crossref>
				The fountains of the deep and 
				<crossref let="f" cid="c01008002.2">
				</crossref>
				the windows of the heavens were closed, the rain from the heavens was restrained,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v01008003">
			</marker>
			<verse num="3">
				and the waters receded from the earth continually. At the end 
				<crossref let="g" cid="c01008003.1">
				</crossref>
				of 150 days the waters had abated,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v01008004">
			</marker>
			<verse num="4">
				and in the seventh month, on the seventeenth day of the month, the ark came to rest on the mountains of 
				<crossref let="h" cid="c01008004.1">
				</crossref>
				Ararat.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v01008005">
			</marker>
			<verse num="5">
				And the waters continued to abate until the tenth month; in the tenth month, on the first day of the month, the tops of the mountains were seen.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v01008006">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="6">
				At the end of forty days Noah opened the window of the ark that he had made
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v01008007">
			</marker>
			<verse num="7">
				and sent forth a raven. It went to and fro until the waters were dried up from the earth.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v01008008">
			</marker>
			<verse num="8">
				Then he sent forth a dove from him, to see if the waters had subsided from the face of the ground.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v01008009">
			</marker>
			<verse num="9">
				But the dove found no place to set her foot, and she returned to him to the ark, for the waters were still on the face of the whole earth. So he put out his hand and took her and brought her into the ark with him.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v01008010">
			</marker>
			<verse num="10">
				He waited another seven days, and again he sent forth the dove out of the ark.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v01008011">
			</marker>
			<verse num="11">
				And the dove came back to him in the evening, and behold, in her mouth was a freshly plucked olive leaf. So Noah knew that the waters had subsided from the earth.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v01008012">
			</marker>
			<verse num="12">
				Then he waited another seven days and sent forth the dove, and she did not return to him anymore.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v01008013">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="13">
				In the six hundred and first year, in the first month, the first day of the month, the waters were dried from off the earth. And Noah removed the covering of the ark and looked, and behold, the face of the ground was dry.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v01008014">
			</marker>
			<verse num="14">
				In the second month, on the twenty-seventh day of the month, the earth had dried out.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v01008015">
			</marker>
			<verse num="15">
				Then God said to Noah,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v01008016">
			</marker>
			<verse num="16">
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Go out from the ark, 
				<crossref let="i" cid="c01008016.1">
				</crossref>
				you and your wife, and your sons and your sons' wives with you.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v01008017">
			</marker>
			<verse num="17">
				Bring out with you every living thing that is with you of all fleshùbirds and animals and every creeping thing that creeps on the earthùthat they may swarm on the earth, and 
				<crossref let="j" cid="c01008017.1">
				</crossref>
				be fruitful and multiply on the earth.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v01008018">
			</marker>
			<verse num="18">
				So Noah went out, and his sons and his wife and his sons' wives with him.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v01008019">
			</marker>
			<verse num="19">
				Every beast, every creeping thing, and every bird, everything that moves on the earth, went out by families from the ark.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v01008020">
			</marker>
			<heading
				>
				God's Covenant with Noah
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="20">
				Then Noah built an altar to the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 and took some of every clean animal and some of every clean bird and offered burnt offerings on the altar.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v01008021">
			</marker>
			<verse num="21">
				And when the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 smelled 
				<crossref let="k" cid="c01008021.1">
				</crossref>
				the pleasing aroma, the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 said in his heart, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				I will never again 
				<crossref let="l" cid="c01008021.2">
				</crossref>
				curse
				<note nid="n01008021.1">
				</note>
				 the ground because of man, for 
				<crossref let="m" cid="c01008021.3">
				</crossref>
				the intention of man's heart is evil from his youth. 
				<crossref let="n" cid="c01008021.4">
				</crossref>
				Neither will I ever again strike down every living creature as I have done.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v01008022">
			</marker>
			<verse num="22">
				<crossref let="o" cid="c01008022.1">
				</crossref>
				While the earth remains, seedtime and harvest, cold and heat, summer and winter, 
				<crossref let="p" cid="c01008022.2">
				</crossref>
				day and night, shall not cease.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
		</chapter>
	</book>
</crossway-bible>


