<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> 
<crossway-bible>
	<book title="Jeremiah" num="23">
		<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v24052001">
		</marker>
		<chapter num="52">
			<heading
				>
				The Fall of Jerusalem Recounted
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="1">
				<crossref let="c" cid="c24052001.1">
				</crossref>
				Zedekiah was twenty-one years old when he became king; and he reigned eleven years in Jerusalem. His mother's name was Hamutal the daughter of Jeremiah of Libnah.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v24052002">
			</marker>
			<verse num="2">
				And he did what was evil in the sight of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				, 
				<crossref let="d" cid="c24052002.1">
				</crossref>
				according to all that Jehoiakim had done.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v24052003">
			</marker>
			<verse num="3">
				For because of the anger of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 things came to the point in Jerusalem and Judah that he cast them out from his presence.

				<end-paragraph
					>
				</end-paragraph>
				<begin-paragraph
					>
				</begin-paragraph>
				And Zedekiah rebelled against the king of Babylon.

			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v24052004">
			</marker>
			<verse num="4">
				<crossref let="e" cid="c24052004.1">
				</crossref>
				And in the ninth year of his reign, in the tenth month, on the tenth day of the month, Nebuchadnezzar king of Babylon came with all his army against Jerusalem, and laid siege to it. And they built siegeworks all around it.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v24052005">
			</marker>
			<verse num="5">
				So the city was besieged till the eleventh year of King Zedekiah.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v24052006">
			</marker>
			<verse num="6">
				On the ninth day of the fourth month the famine was so severe in the city that there was no food for the people of the land.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v24052007">
			</marker>
			<verse num="7">
				Then a breach was made in the city, and all the men of war fled and went out from the city by night by the way of a gate between the two walls, by the king's garden, while the Chaldeans were around the city. And they went in the direction of the Arabah.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v24052008">
			</marker>
			<verse num="8">
				But the army of the Chaldeans pursued the king and overtook Zedekiah in the plains of Jericho. And all his army was scattered from him.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v24052009">
			</marker>
			<verse num="9">
				Then they captured the king and brought him up to the king of Babylon at Riblah in the land of Hamath, and he passed sentence on him.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v24052010">
			</marker>
			<verse num="10">
				The king of Babylon slaughtered the sons of Zedekiah before his eyes, and also slaughtered all the officials of Judah at 
				<crossref let="f" cid="c24052010.1">
				</crossref>
				Riblah.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v24052011">
			</marker>
			<verse num="11">
				<crossref let="g" cid="c24052011.1">
				</crossref>
				He put out the eyes of Zedekiah, and bound him in chains, and the king of Babylon took him to Babylon, and put him in prison 
				<crossref let="g" cid="c24052011.2">
				</crossref>
				till the day of his death.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v24052012">
			</marker>
			<heading
				>
				The Temple Burned
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="12">
				<crossref let="h" cid="c24052012.1">
				</crossref>
				In the fifth month, on 
				<crossref let="i" cid="c24052012.2">
				</crossref>
				the tenth day of the monthùthat was 
				<crossref let="j" cid="c24052012.3">
				</crossref>
				the nineteenth year of King Nebuchadnezzar, king of BabylonùNebuzaradan the captain of the bodyguard, who 
				<crossref let="k" cid="c24052012.4">
				</crossref>
				served the king of Babylon, entered Jerusalem.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v24052013">
			</marker>
			<verse num="13">
				And he burned the house of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				, and the king's house and all the houses of Jerusalem; every great house he burned down.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v24052014">
			</marker>
			<verse num="14">
				And all the army of the Chaldeans, who were with the captain of the guard, broke down all the walls around Jerusalem.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v24052015">
			</marker>
			<verse num="15">
				And Nebuzaradan the captain of the guard carried away captive some of the poorest of the people and the rest of the people who were left in the city and 
				<crossref let="l" cid="c24052015.1">
				</crossref>
				the deserters who had deserted to the king of Babylon, together with the rest of the artisans.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v24052016">
			</marker>
			<verse num="16">
				But Nebuzaradan the captain of the guard left some of the poorest of the land to be vinedressers and plowmen.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v24052017">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="17">
				And the 
				<crossref let="m" cid="c24052017.1">
				</crossref>
				pillars of bronze that were in the house of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				, and the stands and the 
				<crossref let="n" cid="c24052017.2">
				</crossref>
				bronze sea that were in the house of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				, the Chaldeans broke in pieces, and 
				<crossref let="o" cid="c24052017.3">
				</crossref>
				carried all the bronze to Babylon.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v24052018">
			</marker>
			<verse num="18">
				And they took away 
				<crossref let="p" cid="c24052018.1">
				</crossref>
				the pots and the shovels and the snuffers and the basins and the dishes for incense and all the vessels of bronze used in the temple service;
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v24052019">
			</marker>
			<verse num="19">
				<crossref let="q" cid="c24052019.1">
				</crossref>
				also the small bowls and the fire pans and the basins and the pots and 
				<crossref let="r" cid="c24052019.2">
				</crossref>
				the lampstands and 
				<crossref let="s" cid="c24052019.3">
				</crossref>
				the dishes for incense 
				<crossref let="s" cid="c24052019.4">
				</crossref>
				and the bowls for drink offerings. What was of gold the captain of the guard took away as gold, and what was of silver, as silver.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v24052020">
			</marker>
			<verse num="20">
				As for the two pillars, the one sea, 
				<crossref let="t" cid="c24052020.1">
				</crossref>
				the twelve bronze bulls that were under the sea,
				<note nid="n24052020.1">
				</note>
				 and the stands, which Solomon the king had made for the house of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				, the bronze of all these things was beyond weight.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v24052021">
			</marker>
			<verse num="21">
				As for the pillars, the height of the one pillar was eighteen cubits,
				<note nid="n24052021.1">
				</note>
				<crossref let="u" cid="c24052021.1">
				</crossref>
				its circumference was twelve cubits, and its thickness was four fingers, and it was hollow.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v24052022">
			</marker>
			<verse num="22">
				On it was a capital of bronze. The height of the one capital was 
				<crossref let="v" cid="c24052022.1">
				</crossref>
				five cubits. A network and pomegranates, all of bronze, were around the capital. And the second pillar had the same, with pomegranates.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v24052023">
			</marker>
			<verse num="23">
				There were ninety-six pomegranates on the sides; all the pomegranates were a hundred upon the network all around.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v24052024">
			</marker>
			<heading
				>
				The People Exiled to Babylon
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="24">
				And the captain of the guard took 
				<crossref let="w" cid="c24052024.1">
				</crossref>
				Seraiah the chief priest, and 
				<crossref let="x" cid="c24052024.2">
				</crossref>
				Zephaniah the second priest, and the three keepers of the threshold;
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v24052025">
			</marker>
			<verse num="25">
				and from the city he took an officer who had been in command of the men of war, and 
				<crossref let="y" cid="c24052025.1">
				</crossref>
				seven men of the king's council, who were found in the city; and the secretary of the commander of the army who mustered the people of the land; and sixty men of the people of the land, who were found in the midst of the city.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v24052026">
			</marker>
			<verse num="26">
				And Nebuzaradan the captain of the guard took them and brought them to the king of Babylon at 
				<crossref let="z" cid="c24052026.1">
				</crossref>
				Riblah.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v24052027">
			</marker>
			<verse num="27">
				And the king of Babylon struck them down, and put them to death at 
				<crossref let="z" cid="c24052027.1">
				</crossref>
				Riblah in the land of Hamath. So Judah was taken into exile out of its land.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v24052028">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="28">
				This is the number of the people whom Nebuchadnezzar carried away captive: 
				<crossref let="a" cid="c24052028.1">
				</crossref>
				in the seventh year, 3,023 Judeans;
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v24052029">
			</marker>
			<verse num="29">
				<crossref let="b" cid="c24052029.1">
				</crossref>
				in the eighteenth year of Nebuchadnezzar he carried away captive from Jerusalem 832 persons;
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v24052030">
			</marker>
			<verse num="30">
				in the twenty-third year of Nebuchadnezzar, Nebuzaradan the captain of the guard carried away captive of the Judeans 745 persons; all the persons were 4,600.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v24052031">
			</marker>
			<heading
				>
				Jehoiachin Released from Prison
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="31">
				<crossref let="c" cid="c24052031.1">
				</crossref>
				And in the thirty-seventh year of the exile of Jehoiachin king of Judah, in the twelfth month, on the twenty-fifth day of the month, Evil-merodach king of Babylon, in the year that he became king, graciously freed
				<note nid="n24052031.1">
				</note>
				<crossref let="d" cid="c24052031.2">
				</crossref>
				Jehoiachin king of Judah and brought him out of prison.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v24052032">
			</marker>
			<verse num="32">
				And he spoke kindly to him, and gave him a seat above the seats of 
				<crossref let="e" cid="c24052032.1">
				</crossref>
				the kings who were with him in Babylon.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v24052033">
			</marker>
			<verse num="33">
				So Jehoiachin put off his prison garments. And every day of his life he dined regularly at the king's table,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v24052034">
			</marker>
			<verse num="34">
				and for his allowance, a regular allowance was given him by the king according to his daily need, until the day of his death, as long as he lived.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
		</chapter>
	</book>
</crossway-bible>


