<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> 
<crossway-bible>
	<book title="Joshua" num="5">
		<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06008001">
		</marker>
		<chapter num="8">
			<heading
				>
				The Fall of Ai
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="1">
				And the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 said to Joshua, 
				<crossref let="f" cid="c06008001.1">
				</crossref>
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Do not fear and do not be dismayed. Take all the fighting men with you, and arise, go up to Ai. See, 
				<crossref let="g" cid="c06008001.2">
				</crossref>
				I have given into your hand the king of Ai, and his people, his city, and his land.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06008002">
			</marker>
			<verse num="2">
				And you shall do to Ai and its king as you did 
				<crossref let="h" cid="c06008002.1">
				</crossref>
				to Jericho and its king. Only 
				<crossref let="i" cid="c06008002.2">
				</crossref>
				its spoil and its livestock you shall take as plunder for yourselves. Lay an ambush against the city, behind it.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06008003">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="3">
				So Joshua and all the fighting men arose to go up to Ai. And Joshua chose 30,000 mighty men of valor and sent them out by night.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06008004">
			</marker>
			<verse num="4">
				And he commanded them, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Behold, 
				<crossref let="j" cid="c06008004.1">
				</crossref>
				you shall lie in ambush against the city, behind it. Do not go very far from the city, but all of you remain ready.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06008005">
			</marker>
			<verse num="5">
				And I and all the people who are with me will approach the city. And when they come out against us 
				<crossref let="k" cid="c06008005.1">
				</crossref>
				just as before, we shall flee before them.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06008006">
			</marker>
			<verse num="6">
				And they will come out after us, until we have 
				<crossref let="l" cid="c06008006.1">
				</crossref>
				drawn them away from the city. For they will say, 
				<q class="begin-single" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				They are fleeing from us, just as before.
				<q class="end-single" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				 So we will flee before them.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06008007">
			</marker>
			<verse num="7">
				Then you shall rise up from the ambush and seize the city, for the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 your God will give it into your hand.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06008008">
			</marker>
			<verse num="8">
				And as soon as you have taken the city, you shall set the city on fire. You shall do according to the word of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				. 
				<crossref let="m" cid="c06008008.1">
				</crossref>
				See, I have commanded you.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06008009">
			</marker>
			<verse num="9">
				So Joshua sent them out. And they went to the place of ambush and lay between Bethel and Ai, to the west of Ai, but Joshua spent that night among the people.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06008010">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="10">
				Joshua arose early in the morning and mustered the people and went up, he and the elders of Israel, before the people to Ai.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06008011">
			</marker>
			<verse num="11">
				And 
				<crossref let="n" cid="c06008011.1">
				</crossref>
				all the fighting men who were with him went up and drew near before the city and encamped on the north side of Ai, with a ravine between them and Ai.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06008012">
			</marker>
			<verse num="12">
				He took about 5,000 men and set them in ambush between Bethel and Ai, to the west of the city.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06008013">
			</marker>
			<verse num="13">
				So they stationed the forces, the main encampment that was north of the city and its rear guard west of the city. But Joshua spent that night in the valley.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06008014">
			</marker>
			<verse num="14">
				And as soon as the king of Ai saw this, he and all his people, the men of the city, hurried and went out early to the appointed place
				<note nid="n06008014.1">
				</note>
				 toward 
				<crossref let="o" cid="c06008014.1">
				</crossref>
				the Arabah to meet Israel in battle. 
				<crossref let="p" cid="c06008014.2">
				</crossref>
				But he did not know that there was an ambush against him behind the city.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06008015">
			</marker>
			<verse num="15">
				And Joshua and all Israel 
				<crossref let="q" cid="c06008015.1">
				</crossref>
				pretended to be beaten before them and fled in the direction of the wilderness.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06008016">
			</marker>
			<verse num="16">
				So all the people who were in the city were called together to pursue them, and as they pursued Joshua they 
				<crossref let="r" cid="c06008016.1">
				</crossref>
				were drawn away from the city.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06008017">
			</marker>
			<verse num="17">
				Not a man was left in Ai or Bethel who did not go out after Israel. They left the city open and pursued Israel.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06008018">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="18">
				Then the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 said to Joshua, 
				<crossref let="s" cid="c06008018.1">
				</crossref>
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Stretch out the javelin that is in your hand toward Ai, for I will give it into your hand.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				 And Joshua stretched out the javelin that was in his hand toward the city.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06008019">
			</marker>
			<verse num="19">
				And the men in the ambush rose quickly out of their place, and as soon as he had stretched out his hand, they ran and entered the city and captured it. And they hurried to set the city on fire.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06008020">
			</marker>
			<verse num="20">
				So when the men of Ai looked back, behold, the smoke of the city went up to heaven, and they had no power to flee this way or that, for the people who fled to the wilderness turned back against the pursuers.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06008021">
			</marker>
			<verse num="21">
				And when Joshua and all Israel saw that the ambush had captured the city, and that the smoke of the city went up, then they turned back and struck down the men of Ai.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06008022">
			</marker>
			<verse num="22">
				And the others came out from the city against them, so they were in the midst of Israel, some on this side, and some on that side. And Israel struck them down, until there was 
				<crossref let="t" cid="c06008022.1">
				</crossref>
				left none that survived or escaped.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06008023">
			</marker>
			<verse num="23">
				But the king of Ai they took alive, and brought him near to Joshua.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06008024">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="24">
				When Israel had finished killing all the inhabitants of Ai in the open wilderness where they pursued them, and all of them to the very last had fallen by the edge of the sword, all Israel returned to Ai and struck it down with the edge of the sword.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06008025">
			</marker>
			<verse num="25">
				And all who fell that day, both men and women, were 12,000, all the people of Ai.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06008026">
			</marker>
			<verse num="26">
				But Joshua did not draw back his hand with which he 
				<crossref let="u" cid="c06008026.1">
				</crossref>
				stretched out the javelin until he had devoted all the inhabitants of Ai to destruction.
				<note nid="n06008026.1">
				</note>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06008027">
			</marker>
			<verse num="27">
				Only the livestock and the spoil of that city Israel took as their plunder, according to the word of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 that he 
				<crossref let="v" cid="c06008027.1">
				</crossref>
				commanded Joshua.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06008028">
			</marker>
			<verse num="28">
				So Joshua burned Ai and made it forever a 
				<crossref let="w" cid="c06008028.1">
				</crossref>
				heap of ruins, as it is to this day.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06008029">
			</marker>
			<verse num="29">
				<crossref let="x" cid="c06008029.1">
				</crossref>
				And he hanged the king of Ai on a tree until evening. 
				<crossref let="y" cid="c06008029.2">
				</crossref>
				And at sunset Joshua commanded, and they took his body down from the tree and threw it at the entrance of the gate of the city and 
				<crossref let="z" cid="c06008029.3">
				</crossref>
				raised over it a great heap of stones, which stands there to this day.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06008030">
			</marker>
			<heading
				>
				Joshua Renews the Covenant
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="30">
				At that time Joshua built an altar to the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				, the God of Israel, 
				<crossref let="a" cid="c06008030.1">
				</crossref>
				on Mount Ebal,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06008031">
			</marker>
			<verse num="31">
				just as Moses the servant of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 had commanded the people of Israel, as it is written in the Book of the Law of Moses, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				an altar of uncut stones, upon which no man has wielded an iron tool.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				 And they offered on it burnt offerings to the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 and sacrificed peace offerings.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06008032">
			</marker>
			<verse num="32">
				And there, in the presence of the people of Israel, he wrote on 
				<crossref let="b" cid="c06008032.1">
				</crossref>
				the stones a copy of the law of Moses, which he had written.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06008033">
			</marker>
			<verse num="33">
				And all Israel, 
				<crossref let="c" cid="c06008033.1">
				</crossref>
				sojourner as well as native born, with their elders and officers and their judges, stood on opposite sides of the ark before the Levitical priests 
				<crossref let="d" cid="c06008033.2">
				</crossref>
				who carried the ark of the covenant of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				, half of them in front of Mount Gerizim and half of them in front of Mount Ebal, 
				<crossref let="e" cid="c06008033.3">
				</crossref>
				just as Moses the servant of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 had commanded at the first, to bless the people of Israel.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06008034">
			</marker>
			<verse num="34">
				And afterward 
				<crossref let="f" cid="c06008034.1">
				</crossref>
				he read all the words of the law, 
				<crossref let="g" cid="c06008034.2">
				</crossref>
				the blessing and the curse, according to all that is written in the Book of the Law.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06008035">
			</marker>
			<verse num="35">
				There was not a word of all that Moses commanded that Joshua did not read before all the assembly of Israel, 
				<crossref let="h" cid="c06008035.1">
				</crossref>
				and the women, and the little ones, and 
				<crossref let="i" cid="c06008035.2">
				</crossref>
				the sojourners who lived
				<note nid="n06008035.1">
				</note>
				 among them.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
		</chapter>
	</book>
</crossway-bible>


