<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> 
<crossway-bible>
	<book title="Joshua" num="5">
		<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06017001">
		</marker>
		<chapter num="17">
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="1">
				Then allotment was made to the people of Manasseh, for he was 
				<crossref let="t" cid="c06017001.1">
				</crossref>
				the firstborn of Joseph. To 
				<crossref let="u" cid="c06017001.2">
				</crossref>
				Machir the firstborn of Manasseh, the father of Gilead, 
				<crossref let="v" cid="c06017001.3">
				</crossref>
				were allotted Gilead and Bashan, because he was a man of war.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06017002">
			</marker>
			<verse num="2">
				And allotments were made 
				<crossref let="w" cid="c06017002.1">
				</crossref>
				to the rest of the people of Manasseh by their clans, Abiezer, Helek, Asriel, Shechem, Hepher, and Shemida. These were the male descendants of Manasseh the son of Joseph, by their clans.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06017003">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="3">
				Now 
				<crossref let="x" cid="c06017003.1">
				</crossref>
				Zelophehad the son of Hepher, son of Gilead, son of Machir, son of Manasseh, had no sons, but only daughters, and these are the names of his daughters: 
				<crossref let="x" cid="c06017003.2">
				</crossref>
				Mahlah, Noah, Hoglah, Milcah, and Tirzah.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06017004">
			</marker>
			<verse num="4">
				They approached 
				<crossref let="y" cid="c06017004.1">
				</crossref>
				Eleazar the priest and Joshua the son of Nun and the leaders and said, 
				<crossref let="z" cid="c06017004.2">
				</crossref>
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				The 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 commanded Moses to give us an inheritance along with our brothers.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				 So according to the mouth of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 he gave them an inheritance among the brothers of their father.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06017005">
			</marker>
			<verse num="5">
				Thus there fell to Manasseh ten portions, besides 
				<crossref let="a" cid="c06017005.1">
				</crossref>
				the land of Gilead and Bashan, which is on the other side of the Jordan,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06017006">
			</marker>
			<verse num="6">
				because the daughters of Manasseh received an inheritance along with his sons. The land of Gilead was allotted to the rest of the people of Manasseh.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06017007">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="7">
				The territory of Manasseh reached from Asher to 
				<crossref let="b" cid="c06017007.1">
				</crossref>
				Michmethath, which is east of Shechem. Then the boundary goes along southward to the inhabitants of En-tappuah.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06017008">
			</marker>
			<verse num="8">
				The land of 
				<crossref let="c" cid="c06017008.1">
				</crossref>
				Tappuah belonged to Manasseh, but the town of Tappuah on the boundary of Manasseh belonged to the people of Ephraim.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06017009">
			</marker>
			<verse num="9">
				<crossref let="c" cid="c06017009.1">
				</crossref>
				Then the boundary went down to the brook Kanah. These cities, to the south of the brook, among the cities of Manasseh, belong to Ephraim. Then the boundary of Manasseh goes on the north side of the brook and ends at the sea,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06017010">
			</marker>
			<verse num="10">
				the land to the south being Ephraim's and that to the north being Manasseh's, with the sea forming its boundary. On the north Asher is reached, and on the east Issachar.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06017011">
			</marker>
			<verse num="11">
				Also in Issachar and in Asher 
				<crossref let="d" cid="c06017011.1">
				</crossref>
				Manasseh had Beth-shean and its villages, and Ibleam and its villages, and the inhabitants of 
				<crossref let="d" cid="c06017011.2">
				</crossref>
				Dor and its villages, and the inhabitants of En-dor and its villages, and the inhabitants of 
				<crossref let="d" cid="c06017011.3">
				</crossref>
				Taanach and its villages, and the inhabitants of 
				<crossref let="d" cid="c06017011.4">
				</crossref>
				Megiddo and its villages; 
				<crossref let="e" cid="c06017011.5">
				</crossref>
				the third is Naphath.
				<note nid="n06017011.1">
				</note>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06017012">
			</marker>
			<verse num="12">
				<crossref let="f" cid="c06017012.1">
				</crossref>
				Yet the people of Manasseh could not take possession of those cities, but the Canaanites persisted in dwelling in that land.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06017013">
			</marker>
			<verse num="13">
				Now when the people of Israel grew strong, they put the Canaanites 
				<crossref let="g" cid="c06017013.1">
				</crossref>
				to forced labor, but did not utterly drive them out.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06017014">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="14">
				Then 
				<crossref let="h" cid="c06017014.1">
				</crossref>
				the people of Joseph spoke to Joshua, saying, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Why have you given me but 
				<crossref let="i" cid="c06017014.2">
				</crossref>
				one lot and one portion as an inheritance, although I am 
				<crossref let="j" cid="c06017014.3">
				</crossref>
				a numerous people, since all along the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 has blessed me?
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06017015">
			</marker>
			<verse num="15">
				And Joshua said to them, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				If you are a numerous people, go up by yourselves to the forest, and there clear ground for yourselves in the land of the Perizzites and 
				<crossref let="k" cid="c06017015.1">
				</crossref>
				the Rephaim, since 
				<crossref let="l" cid="c06017015.2">
				</crossref>
				the hill country of Ephraim is too narrow for you.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06017016">
			</marker>
			<verse num="16">
				The people of Joseph said, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				The hill country is not enough for us. Yet all the Canaanites who dwell in the plain have 
				<crossref let="m" cid="c06017016.1">
				</crossref>
				chariots of iron, both those in Beth-shean and its villages and those in 
				<crossref let="n" cid="c06017016.2">
				</crossref>
				the Valley of Jezreel.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06017017">
			</marker>
			<verse num="17">
				Then Joshua said to the house of Joseph, to Ephraim and Manasseh, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				You are a numerous people and have great power. You shall not have one allotment only,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06017018">
			</marker>
			<verse num="18">
				but the hill country shall be yours, for though it is a forest, you shall clear it and possess it to its farthest borders. For you shall drive out the Canaanites, 
				<crossref let="o" cid="c06017018.1">
				</crossref>
				though they have chariots of iron, and though they are strong.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
		</chapter>
	</book>
</crossway-bible>


