<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> 
<crossway-bible>
	<book title="Joshua" num="5">
		<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06021001">
		</marker>
		<chapter num="21">
			<heading
				>
				Cities and Pasturelands Allotted to Levi
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="1">
				Then the heads of the fathers' houses of the Levites came 
				<crossref let="u" cid="c06021001.1">
				</crossref>
				to Eleazar the priest and to Joshua the son of Nun and to the heads of the fathers' houses of the tribes of the people of Israel.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06021002">
			</marker>
			<verse num="2">
				And they said to them 
				<crossref let="v" cid="c06021002.1">
				</crossref>
				at Shiloh in the land of Canaan, 
				<crossref let="w" cid="c06021002.2">
				</crossref>
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				The 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 commanded through Moses that we be given cities to dwell in, along with their pasturelands for our livestock.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06021003">
			</marker>
			<verse num="3">
				So by command of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 the people of Israel gave to the Levites the following cities and pasturelands out of their inheritance.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06021004">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="4">
				The lot came out for the clans of the Kohathites. So those Levites who were descendants of Aaron the priest 
				<crossref let="x" cid="c06021004.1">
				</crossref>
				received by lot from the tribes of Judah, Simeon, and Benjamin, thirteen cities.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06021005">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="5">
				And the rest of the Kohathites received by lot 
				<crossref let="y" cid="c06021005.1">
				</crossref>
				from the clans of the tribe of Ephraim, from the tribe of Dan and the half-tribe of Manasseh, ten cities.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06021006">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="6">
				The 
				<crossref let="z" cid="c06021006.1">
				</crossref>
				Gershonites received by lot from the clans of the tribe of Issachar, from the tribe of Asher, from the tribe of Naphtali, and from the half-tribe of Manasseh in Bashan, thirteen cities.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06021007">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="7">
				The 
				<crossref let="a" cid="c06021007.1">
				</crossref>
				Merarites according to their clans received from the tribe of Reuben, the tribe of Gad, and the tribe of Zebulun, twelve cities.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06021008">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="8">
				These cities and their pasturelands the people of Israel 
				<crossref let="b" cid="c06021008.1">
				</crossref>
				gave by lot to the Levites, 
				<crossref let="c" cid="c06021008.2">
				</crossref>
				as the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 had commanded through Moses.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06021009">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="9">
				Out of the tribe of the people of Judah and the tribe of the people of Simeon they gave the following cities mentioned by name,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06021010">
			</marker>
			<verse num="10">
				which went to 
				<crossref let="d" cid="c06021010.1">
				</crossref>
				the descendants of Aaron, one of the clans of the Kohathites who belonged to the people of Levi; since the lot fell to them first.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06021011">
			</marker>
			<verse num="11">
				<crossref let="e" cid="c06021011.1">
				</crossref>
				They gave them 
				<crossref let="f" cid="c06021011.2">
				</crossref>
				Kiriath-arba (Arba being the father of Anak), that is Hebron, 
				<crossref let="g" cid="c06021011.3">
				</crossref>
				in the hill country of Judah, along with the pasturelands around it.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06021012">
			</marker>
			<verse num="12">
				But the fields of the city and its villages had been given to Caleb the son of Jephunneh as his possession.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06021013">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="13">
				And to the descendants of Aaron the priest they gave Hebron, 
				<crossref let="h" cid="c06021013.1">
				</crossref>
				the city of refuge for the manslayer, with its pasturelands, 
				<crossref let="i" cid="c06021013.2">
				</crossref>
				Libnah with its pasturelands,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06021014">
			</marker>
			<verse num="14">
				Jattir with its pasturelands, Eshtemoa with its pasturelands,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06021015">
			</marker>
			<verse num="15">
				Holon with its pasturelands, Debir with its pasturelands,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06021016">
			</marker>
			<verse num="16">
				Ain with its pasturelands, Juttah with its pasturelands, Beth-shemesh with its pasturelandsùnine cities out of these two tribes;
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06021017">
			</marker>
			<verse num="17">
				then out of the tribe of Benjamin, 
				<crossref let="j" cid="c06021017.1">
				</crossref>
				Gibeon with its pasturelands, Geba with its pasturelands,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06021018">
			</marker>
			<verse num="18">
				Anathoth with its pasturelands, and Almon with its pasturelandsùfour cities.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06021019">
			</marker>
			<verse num="19">
				The cities of the descendants of Aaron, the priests, were in all thirteen cities with their pasturelands.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06021020">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="20">
				<crossref let="k" cid="c06021020.1">
				</crossref>
				As to the rest of the Kohathites belonging to the Kohathite clans of the Levites, the cities allotted to them were out of the tribe of Ephraim.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06021021">
			</marker>
			<verse num="21">
				To them were given Shechem, 
				<crossref let="l" cid="c06021021.1">
				</crossref>
				the city of refuge for the manslayer, with its pasturelands in the hill country of Ephraim, Gezer with its pasturelands,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06021022">
			</marker>
			<verse num="22">
				Kibzaim with its pasturelands, Beth-horon with its pasturelandsùfour cities;
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06021023">
			</marker>
			<verse num="23">
				and out of the tribe of Dan, Elteke with its pasturelands, Gibbethon with its pasturelands,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06021024">
			</marker>
			<verse num="24">
				Aijalon with its pasturelands, Gath-rimmon with its pasturelandsùfour cities;
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06021025">
			</marker>
			<verse num="25">
				and out of the half-tribe of Manasseh, Taanach with its pasturelands, and Gath-rimmon with its pasturelandsùtwo cities.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06021026">
			</marker>
			<verse num="26">
				The cities of the clans of the rest of the Kohathites were ten in all with their pasturelands.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06021027">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="27">
				<crossref let="m" cid="c06021027.1">
				</crossref>
				And to the Gershonites, one of the clans of the Levites, were given out of the half-tribe of Manasseh, Golan in Bashan with its pasturelands, 
				<crossref let="l" cid="c06021027.2">
				</crossref>
				the city of refuge for the manslayer, and Beeshterah with its pasturelandsùtwo cities;
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06021028">
			</marker>
			<verse num="28">
				and out of the tribe of Issachar, Kishion with its pasturelands, Daberath with its pasturelands,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06021029">
			</marker>
			<verse num="29">
				Jarmuth with its pasturelands, En-gannim with its pasturelandsùfour cities;
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06021030">
			</marker>
			<verse num="30">
				and out of the tribe of Asher, Mishal with its pasturelands, Abdon with its pasturelands,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06021031">
			</marker>
			<verse num="31">
				Helkath with its pasturelands, and Rehob with its pasturelandsùfour cities;
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06021032">
			</marker>
			<verse num="32">
				and out of the tribe of Naphtali, Kedesh in Galilee with its pasturelands, 
				<crossref let="l" cid="c06021032.1">
				</crossref>
				the city of refuge for the manslayer, Hammoth-dor with its pasturelands, and Kartan with its pasturelandsùthree cities.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06021033">
			</marker>
			<verse num="33">
				The cities of the several clans of the Gershonites were in all thirteen cities with their pasturelands.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06021034">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="34">
				<crossref let="n" cid="c06021034.1">
				</crossref>
				And to the rest of the Levites, the Merarite clans, were given out of the tribe of Zebulun, Jokneam with its pasturelands, Kartah with its pasturelands,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06021035">
			</marker>
			<verse num="35">
				Dimnah with its pasturelands, Nahalal with its pasturelandsùfour cities;
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06021036">
			</marker>
			<verse num="36">
				and out of the tribe of Reuben, 
				<crossref let="o" cid="c06021036.1">
				</crossref>
				Bezer with its pasturelands, Jahaz with its pasturelands,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06021037">
			</marker>
			<verse num="37">
				Kedemoth with its pasturelands, and Mephaath with its pasturelandsùfour cities;
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06021038">
			</marker>
			<verse num="38">
				and out of the tribe of Gad, 
				<crossref let="o" cid="c06021038.1">
				</crossref>
				Ramoth in Gilead with its pasturelands, the city of refuge for the manslayer, 
				<crossref let="p" cid="c06021038.2">
				</crossref>
				Mahanaim with its pasturelands,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06021039">
			</marker>
			<verse num="39">
				<crossref let="p" cid="c06021039.1">
				</crossref>
				Heshbon with its pasturelands, Jazer with its pasturelandsùfour cities in all.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06021040">
			</marker>
			<verse num="40">
				As for the cities of the several Merarite clans, that is, the remainder of the clans of the Levites, those allotted to them were in all twelve cities.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06021041">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="41">
				<crossref let="q" cid="c06021041.1">
				</crossref>
				The cities of the Levites in the midst of the possession of the people of Israel were in all forty-eight cities with their pasturelands.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06021042">
			</marker>
			<verse num="42">
				These cities each had its pasturelands around it. So it was with all these cities.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06021043">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="43">
				<crossref let="r" cid="c06021043.1">
				</crossref>
				Thus the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 gave to Israel all the land that he swore to give to their fathers. And they took possession of it, and they settled there.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06021044">
			</marker>
			<verse num="44">
				<crossref let="s" cid="c06021044.1">
				</crossref>
				And the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 gave them rest on every side just as he had sworn to their fathers. 
				<crossref let="t" cid="c06021044.2">
				</crossref>
				Not one of all their enemies had withstood them, for 
				<crossref let="u" cid="c06021044.3">
				</crossref>
				the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 had given all their enemies into their hands.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v06021045">
			</marker>
			<verse num="45">
				<crossref let="v" cid="c06021045.1">
				</crossref>
				Not one word of all the good promises that the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 had made to the house of Israel had failed; all came to pass.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
		</chapter>
	</book>
</crossway-bible>


