<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> 
<crossway-bible>
	<book title="Judges" num="6">
		<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v07019001">
		</marker>
		<chapter num="19">
			<heading
				>
				A Levite and His Concubine
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="1">
				In those days, 
				<crossref let="x" cid="c07019001.1">
				</crossref>
				when there was no king in Israel, a certain Levite was sojourning in the remote parts of 
				<crossref let="y" cid="c07019001.2">
				</crossref>
				the hill country of Ephraim, who took to himself a concubine from 
				<crossref let="z" cid="c07019001.3">
				</crossref>
				Bethlehem in Judah.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v07019002">
			</marker>
			<verse num="2">
				And his concubine was unfaithful to
				<note nid="n07019002.1">
				</note>
				 him, and she went away from him to her father's house at Bethlehem in Judah, and was there some four months.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v07019003">
			</marker>
			<verse num="3">
				Then her husband arose and went after her, to speak kindly to her and bring her back. He had with him his servant and a couple of donkeys. And she brought him into her father's house. And when the girl's father saw him, he came with joy to meet him.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v07019004">
			</marker>
			<verse num="4">
				And his father-in-law, the girl's father, made him stay, and he remained with him three days. So they ate and drank and spent the night there.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v07019005">
			</marker>
			<verse num="5">
				And on the fourth day they arose early in the morning, and he prepared to go, but the girl's father said to his son-in-law, 
				<crossref let="a" cid="c07019005.1">
				</crossref>
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Strengthen your heart with a morsel of bread, and after that you may go.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v07019006">
			</marker>
			<verse num="6">
				So the two of them sat and ate and drank together. And the girl's father said to the man, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Be pleased to spend the night, and 
				<crossref let="b" cid="c07019006.1">
				</crossref>
				let your heart be merry.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v07019007">
			</marker>
			<verse num="7">
				And when the man rose up to go, his father-in-law pressed him, till he spent the night there again.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v07019008">
			</marker>
			<verse num="8">
				And on the fifth day he arose early in the morning to depart. And the girl's father said, 
				<crossref let="c" cid="c07019008.1">
				</crossref>
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Strengthen your heart and wait until the day declines.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				 So they ate, both of them.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v07019009">
			</marker>
			<verse num="9">
				And when the man and his concubine and his servant rose up to depart, his father-in-law, the girl's father, said to him, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Behold, now the day has waned toward evening. Please, spend the night. Behold, the day draws to its close. Lodge here and let your heart be merry, and tomorrow you shall arise early in the morning for your journey, and go home.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v07019010">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="10">
				But the man would not spend the night. He rose up and departed and arrived opposite 
				<crossref let="d" cid="c07019010.1">
				</crossref>
				Jebus (that is, Jerusalem). He had with him a couple of saddled donkeys, and his concubine was with him.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v07019011">
			</marker>
			<verse num="11">
				When they were near Jebus, the day was nearly over, and the servant said to his master, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Come now, let us turn aside to this city of the Jebusites and spend the night in it.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v07019012">
			</marker>
			<verse num="12">
				And his master said to him, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				We will not turn aside into the city of foreigners, who do not belong to the people of Israel, but we will pass on to 
				<crossref let="e" cid="c07019012.1">
				</crossref>
				Gibeah.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v07019013">
			</marker>
			<verse num="13">
				And he said to his young man, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Come and let us draw near to one of these places and spend the night at Gibeah or at 
				<crossref let="f" cid="c07019013.1">
				</crossref>
				Ramah.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v07019014">
			</marker>
			<verse num="14">
				So they passed on and went their way. And the sun went down on them near Gibeah, which belongs to Benjamin,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v07019015">
			</marker>
			<verse num="15">
				and they turned aside there, to go in and spend the night at Gibeah. And he went in and sat down in the open square of the city, 
				<crossref let="g" cid="c07019015.1">
				</crossref>
				for no one took them into his house to spend the night.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v07019016">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="16">
				And behold, an old man was coming from his work in the field at evening. The man was from 
				<crossref let="h" cid="c07019016.1">
				</crossref>
				the hill country of Ephraim, and he was sojourning in Gibeah. 
				<crossref let="i" cid="c07019016.2">
				</crossref>
				The men of the place were Benjaminites.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v07019017">
			</marker>
			<verse num="17">
				And he lifted up his eyes and saw the traveler in the open square of the city. And the old man said, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Where are you going? And where do you come from?
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v07019018">
			</marker>
			<verse num="18">
				And he said to him, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				We are passing from Bethlehem in Judah to the remote parts of the hill country of Ephraim, from which I come. I went to Bethlehem in Judah, and I am going 
				<crossref let="j" cid="c07019018.1">
				</crossref>
				to the house of the Lord,
				<note nid="n07019018.1">
				</note>
				<crossref let="g" cid="c07019018.2">
				</crossref>
				but no one has taken me into his house.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v07019019">
			</marker>
			<verse num="19">
				We have straw and feed for our donkeys, with bread and wine for me and your female servant and the young man with your servants. 
				<crossref let="k" cid="c07019019.1">
				</crossref>
				There is no lack of anything.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v07019020">
			</marker>
			<verse num="20">
				And the old man said, 
				<crossref let="l" cid="c07019020.1">
				</crossref>
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Peace be to you; I will care for all your wants. 
				<crossref let="m" cid="c07019020.2">
				</crossref>
				Only, do not spend the night in the square.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v07019021">
			</marker>
			<verse num="21">
				So he brought him into his house and gave the donkeys feed. 
				<crossref let="n" cid="c07019021.1">
				</crossref>
				And they washed their feet, and ate and drank.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v07019022">
			</marker>
			<heading
				>
				Gibeah's Crime
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="22">
				As they were 
				<crossref let="o" cid="c07019022.1">
				</crossref>
				making their hearts merry, behold, the men of the city, worthless fellows, 
				<crossref let="p" cid="c07019022.2">
				</crossref>
				surrounded the house, beating on the door. And they said to the old man, the master of the house, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Bring out the man who came into your house, that we may know him.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v07019023">
			</marker>
			<verse num="23">
				And the man, the master of the house, went out to them and said to them, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				No, my brothers, 
				<crossref let="q" cid="c07019023.1">
				</crossref>
				do not act so wickedly; since this man has come into my house, 
				<crossref let="r" cid="c07019023.2">
				</crossref>
				do not do this vile thing.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v07019024">
			</marker>
			<verse num="24">
				<crossref let="s" cid="c07019024.1">
				</crossref>
				Behold, here are my virgin daughter and his concubine. Let me bring them out now. 
				<crossref let="t" cid="c07019024.2">
				</crossref>
				Violate them and do with them what seems good to you, but against this man 
				<crossref let="r" cid="c07019024.3">
				</crossref>
				do not do this outrageous thing.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v07019025">
			</marker>
			<verse num="25">
				But the men would not listen to him. So the man seized his concubine and made her go out to them. And they knew her and abused her all night until the morning. And as the dawn began to break, they let her go.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v07019026">
			</marker>
			<verse num="26">
				And as morning appeared, the woman came and fell down at the door of the man's house where her master was, until it was light.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v07019027">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="27">
				And her master rose up in the morning, and when he opened the doors of the house and went out to go on his way, behold, there was his concubine lying at the door of the house, with her hands on the threshold.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v07019028">
			</marker>
			<verse num="28">
				He said to her, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Get up, let us be going.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				<crossref let="u" cid="c07019028.1">
				</crossref>
				But there was no answer. Then he put her on the donkey, and the man rose up and went away to his home.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v07019029">
			</marker>
			<verse num="29">
				And when he entered his house, he took a knife, and taking hold of his concubine he 
				<crossref let="v" cid="c07019029.1">
				</crossref>
				divided her, limb by limb, into twelve pieces, and sent her throughout all the territory of Israel.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v07019030">
			</marker>
			<verse num="30">
				<crossref let="w" cid="c07019030.1">
				</crossref>
				And all who saw it said, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Such a thing has never happened or been seen from the day that the people of Israel came up out of the land of Egypt until this day; 
				<crossref let="x" cid="c07019030.2">
				</crossref>
				consider it, take counsel, and speak.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
		</chapter>
	</book>
</crossway-bible>


