<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> 
<crossway-bible>
	<book title="2 Kings" num="11">
		<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12015001">
		</marker>
		<chapter num="15">
			<heading
				>
				Azariah Reigns in Judah
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="1">
				<crossref let="v" cid="c12015001.1">
				</crossref>
				In the twenty-seventh year of Jeroboam king of Israel, 
				<crossref let="w" cid="c12015001.2">
				</crossref>
				Azariah the son of Amaziah, king of Judah, began to reign.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12015002">
			</marker>
			<verse num="2">
				He was 
				<crossref let="x" cid="c12015002.1">
				</crossref>
				sixteen years old when he began to reign, and he reigned fifty-two years in Jerusalem. His mother's name was Jecoliah of Jerusalem.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12015003">
			</marker>
			<verse num="3">
				And he did what was right in the eyes of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				, according to all that his father Amaziah had done.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12015004">
			</marker>
			<verse num="4">
				<crossref let="y" cid="c12015004.1">
				</crossref>
				Nevertheless, the high places were not taken away. The people still sacrificed and made offerings on the high places.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12015005">
			</marker>
			<verse num="5">
				<crossref let="z" cid="c12015005.1">
				</crossref>
				And the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 touched the king, so that he was a leper
				<note nid="n12015005.1">
				</note>
				 to the day of his death, 
				<crossref let="a" cid="c12015005.2">
				</crossref>
				and he lived in a separate house.
				<note nid="n12015005.2">
				</note>
				 And Jotham the king's son was over the household, governing the people of the land.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12015006">
			</marker>
			<verse num="6">
				Now the rest of the acts of Azariah, and all that he did, are they not written in the Book of the Chronicles of the Kings of Judah?
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12015007">
			</marker>
			<verse num="7">
				And Azariah slept with his fathers, and they buried him with his fathers 
				<crossref let="b" cid="c12015007.1">
				</crossref>
				in the city of David, and Jotham his son reigned in his place.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12015008">
			</marker>
			<heading
				>
				Zechariah Reigns in Israel
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="8">
				In the thirty-eighth year of Azariah king of Judah, Zechariah the son of Jeroboam reigned over Israel in Samaria six months.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12015009">
			</marker>
			<verse num="9">
				And he did what was evil in the sight of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				, as his fathers had done. He did not depart from the sins of Jeroboam the son of Nebat, 
				<crossref let="c" cid="c12015009.1">
				</crossref>
				which he made Israel to sin.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12015010">
			</marker>
			<verse num="10">
				Shallum the son of Jabesh conspired against him and 
				<crossref let="d" cid="c12015010.1">
				</crossref>
				struck him down at Ibleam and put him to death and reigned in his place.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12015011">
			</marker>
			<verse num="11">
				Now the rest of the deeds of Zechariah, behold, they are written in the Book of the Chronicles of the Kings of Israel.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12015012">
			</marker>
			<verse num="12">
				(This was 
				<crossref let="e" cid="c12015012.1">
				</crossref>
				the promise of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 that he gave to Jehu, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Your sons shall sit on the throne of Israel to the fourth generation.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				 And so it came to pass.)
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12015013">
			</marker>
			<heading
				>
				Shallum Reigns in Israel
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="13">
				Shallum the son of Jabesh began to reign in the thirty-ninth year of 
				<crossref let="f" cid="c12015013.1">
				</crossref>
				Uzziah
				<note nid="n12015013.1">
				</note>
				 king of Judah, and he reigned one month in 
				<crossref let="g" cid="c12015013.2">
				</crossref>
				Samaria.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12015014">
			</marker>
			<verse num="14">
				Then Menahem the son of Gadi came up from 
				<crossref let="h" cid="c12015014.1">
				</crossref>
				Tirzah and came to Samaria, and he struck down Shallum the son of Jabesh in Samaria and put him to death and reigned in his place.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12015015">
			</marker>
			<verse num="15">
				Now the rest of the deeds of Shallum, and the conspiracy that he made, behold, they are written in the Book of the Chronicles of the Kings of Israel.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12015016">
			</marker>
			<verse num="16">
				At that time Menahem sacked Tiphsah and all who were in it and its territory from Tirzah on, because they did not open it to him. Therefore he sacked it, 
				<crossref let="i" cid="c12015016.1">
				</crossref>
				and he ripped open all the women in it who were pregnant.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12015017">
			</marker>
			<heading
				>
				Menahem Reigns in Israel
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="17">
				In the thirty-ninth year of Azariah king of Judah, Menahem the son of Gadi began to reign over Israel, and he reigned ten years in Samaria.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12015018">
			</marker>
			<verse num="18">
				And he did what was evil in the sight of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				. He did not depart all his days from all the sins of Jeroboam the son of Nebat, which he made Israel to sin.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12015019">
			</marker>
			<verse num="19">
				<crossref let="j" cid="c12015019.1">
				</crossref>
				Pul
				<note nid="n12015019.1">
				</note>
				 the king of Assyria came against the land, and Menahem gave 
				<crossref let="j" cid="c12015019.2">
				</crossref>
				Pul a thousand talents
				<note nid="n12015019.2">
				</note>
				 of silver, that he might help him 
				<crossref let="k" cid="c12015019.3">
				</crossref>
				to confirm his hold on the royal power.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12015020">
			</marker>
			<verse num="20">
				Menahem exacted the money from Israel, that is, from all the wealthy men, fifty shekels
				<note nid="n12015020.1">
				</note>
				 of silver from every man, to give to the king of Assyria. So the king of Assyria turned back and did not stay there in the land.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12015021">
			</marker>
			<verse num="21">
				Now the rest of the deeds of Menahem and all that he did, are they not written in the Book of the Chronicles of the Kings of Israel?
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12015022">
			</marker>
			<verse num="22">
				And Menahem slept with his fathers, and Pekahiah his son reigned in his place.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12015023">
			</marker>
			<heading
				>
				Pekahiah Reigns in Israel
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="23">
				In the fiftieth year of Azariah king of Judah, Pekahiah the son of Menahem began to reign over Israel in Samaria, and he reigned two years.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12015024">
			</marker>
			<verse num="24">
				And he did what was evil in the sight of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				. He did not turn away from the sins of Jeroboam the son of Nebat, 
				<crossref let="c" cid="c12015024.1">
				</crossref>
				which he made Israel to sin.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12015025">
			</marker>
			<verse num="25">
				And Pekah the son of Remaliah, his captain, conspired against him with fifty men of the people of Gilead, and struck him down in Samaria, in the citadel of the king's house with Argob and Arieh; he put him to death and reigned in his place.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12015026">
			</marker>
			<verse num="26">
				Now the rest of the deeds of Pekahiah and all that he did, behold, they are written in the Book of the Chronicles of the Kings of Israel.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12015027">
			</marker>
			<heading
				>
				Pekah Reigns in Israel
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="27">
				In the fifty-second year of Azariah king of Judah, Pekah the son of Remaliah began to reign over Israel in Samaria, and he reigned twenty years.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12015028">
			</marker>
			<verse num="28">
				And he did what was evil in the sight of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				. He did not depart from the sins of Jeroboam the son of Nebat, 
				<crossref let="l" cid="c12015028.1">
				</crossref>
				which he made Israel to sin.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12015029">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="29">
				In the days of Pekah king of Israel, 
				<crossref let="m" cid="c12015029.1">
				</crossref>
				Tiglath-pileser king of Assyria came and captured 
				<crossref let="n" cid="c12015029.2">
				</crossref>
				Ijon, 
				<crossref let="o" cid="c12015029.3">
				</crossref>
				Abel-beth-maacah, Janoah, 
				<crossref let="p" cid="c12015029.4">
				</crossref>
				Kedesh, 
				<crossref let="q" cid="c12015029.5">
				</crossref>
				Hazor, Gilead, and 
				<crossref let="r" cid="c12015029.6">
				</crossref>
				Galilee, all the land of Naphtali, and he carried the people captive to Assyria.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12015030">
			</marker>
			<verse num="30">
				Then Hoshea the son of Elah made a conspiracy against Pekah the son of Remaliah and struck him down and put him to death and reigned in his place, 
				<crossref let="s" cid="c12015030.1">
				</crossref>
				in the twentieth year of Jotham the son of Uzziah.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12015031">
			</marker>
			<verse num="31">
				Now the rest of the acts of Pekah and all that he did, behold, they are written in the Book of the Chronicles of the Kings of Israel.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12015032">
			</marker>
			<heading
				>
				Jotham Reigns in Judah
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="32">
				In the second year of Pekah the son of Remaliah, king of Israel, Jotham the son of Uzziah, king of Judah, began to reign.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12015033">
			</marker>
			<verse num="33">
				He was 
				<crossref let="t" cid="c12015033.1">
				</crossref>
				twenty-five years old when he began to reign, and he reigned sixteen years in Jerusalem. His mother's name was Jerusha the daughter of Zadok.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12015034">
			</marker>
			<verse num="34">
				And he did what was right in the eyes of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				, 
				<crossref let="u" cid="c12015034.1">
				</crossref>
				according to all that his father Uzziah had done.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12015035">
			</marker>
			<verse num="35">
				<crossref let="v" cid="c12015035.1">
				</crossref>
				Nevertheless, the high places were not removed. The people still sacrificed and made offerings on the high places. He built 
				<crossref let="w" cid="c12015035.2">
				</crossref>
				the upper gate of the house of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12015036">
			</marker>
			<verse num="36">
				Now the rest of the acts of Jotham and all that he did, are they not written in the Book of the Chronicles of the Kings of Judah?
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12015037">
			</marker>
			<verse num="37">
				In those days the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 began to send 
				<crossref let="x" cid="c12015037.1">
				</crossref>
				Rezin the king of Syria and 
				<crossref let="x" cid="c12015037.2">
				</crossref>
				Pekah the son of Remaliah against Judah.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12015038">
			</marker>
			<verse num="38">
				Jotham slept with his fathers and was buried with his fathers in the city of David his father, and Ahaz his son reigned in his place.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
		</chapter>
	</book>
</crossway-bible>


