<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> 
<crossway-bible>
	<book title="1 Kings" num="10">
		<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11006001">
		</marker>
		<chapter num="6">
			<heading
				>
				Solomon Builds the Temple
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="1">
				<crossref let="y" cid="c11006001.1">
				</crossref>
				In the four hundred and eightieth year after the people of Israel came out of the land of Egypt, in the fourth year of Solomon's reign over Israel, in the month of Ziv, which is the second month, 
				<crossref let="z" cid="c11006001.2">
				</crossref>
				he began to build the house of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11006002">
			</marker>
			<verse num="2">
				<crossref let="a" cid="c11006002.1">
				</crossref>
				The house that King Solomon built for the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 was sixty cubits
				<note nid="n11006002.1">
				</note>
				 long, twenty cubits wide, and thirty cubits high.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11006003">
			</marker>
			<verse num="3">
				The vestibule in front of the nave of the house was twenty cubits long, equal to the width of the house, and ten cubits deep in front of the house.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11006004">
			</marker>
			<verse num="4">
				And 
				<crossref let="b" cid="c11006004.1">
				</crossref>
				he made for the house windows with recessed frames.
				<note nid="n11006004.1">
				</note>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11006005">
			</marker>
			<verse num="5">
				<crossref let="c" cid="c11006005.1">
				</crossref>
				He also built a structure
				<note nid="n11006005.1">
				</note>
				 against the wall of the house, running around the walls of the house, both the nave and 
				<crossref let="d" cid="c11006005.2">
				</crossref>
				the inner sanctuary. And he made 
				<crossref let="e" cid="c11006005.3">
				</crossref>
				side chambers all around.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11006006">
			</marker>
			<verse num="6">
				The lowest story
				<note nid="n11006006.1">
				</note>
				 was five cubits broad, the middle one was six cubits broad, and the third was seven cubits broad. For around the outside of the house he made offsets on the wall in order that the supporting beams should not be inserted into the walls of the house.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11006007">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="7">
				When the house was built, 
				<crossref let="f" cid="c11006007.1">
				</crossref>
				it was with stone prepared at the quarry, so that neither hammer nor axe nor any tool of iron was heard in the house while it was being built.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11006008">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="8">
				The entrance for the lowest
				<note nid="n11006008.1">
				</note>
				 story was on the south side of the house, and one went up by stairs to the middle story, and from the middle story to the third.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11006009">
			</marker>
			<verse num="9">
				<crossref let="g" cid="c11006009.1">
				</crossref>
				So he built the house and finished it, and he made the ceiling of the house of beams and planks of cedar.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11006010">
			</marker>
			<verse num="10">
				He built the structure against the whole house, five cubits high, and it was joined to the house with timbers of cedar.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11006011">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="11">
				Now the word of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 came to Solomon,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11006012">
			</marker>
			<verse num="12">
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Concerning this house that you are building, 
				<crossref let="h" cid="c11006012.1">
				</crossref>
				if you will walk in my statutes and obey my rules and keep all my commandments and walk in them, then I will establish my word with you, 
				<crossref let="i" cid="c11006012.2">
				</crossref>
				which I spoke to David your father.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11006013">
			</marker>
			<verse num="13">
				And 
				<crossref let="j" cid="c11006013.1">
				</crossref>
				I will dwell among the children of Israel 
				<crossref let="k" cid="c11006013.2">
				</crossref>
				and will not forsake my people Israel.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11006014">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="14">
				<crossref let="l" cid="c11006014.1">
				</crossref>
				So Solomon built the house and finished it.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11006015">
			</marker>
			<verse num="15">
				He lined the walls of the house on the inside with boards of cedar. From the floor of the house to the walls of the ceiling, he covered them on the inside with wood, 
				<crossref let="m" cid="c11006015.1">
				</crossref>
				and he covered the floor of the house with boards of cypress.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11006016">
			</marker>
			<verse num="16">
				<crossref let="n" cid="c11006016.1">
				</crossref>
				He built twenty cubits of the rear of the house with boards of cedar from the floor to the walls, and he built this within as an inner sanctuary, as 
				<crossref let="o" cid="c11006016.2">
				</crossref>
				the Most Holy Place.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11006017">
			</marker>
			<verse num="17">
				The house, that is, the nave in front of the inner sanctuary, was forty cubits long.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11006018">
			</marker>
			<verse num="18">
				The cedar within the house was carved in the form of 
				<crossref let="p" cid="c11006018.1">
				</crossref>
				gourds and open flowers. All was cedar; no stone was seen.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11006019">
			</marker>
			<verse num="19">
				The inner sanctuary he prepared in the innermost part of the house, to set there the ark of the covenant of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11006020">
			</marker>
			<verse num="20">
				The inner sanctuary
				<note nid="n11006020.1">
				</note>
				 was twenty cubits long, twenty cubits wide, and twenty cubits high, and he overlaid it with pure gold. He also overlaid
				<note nid="n11006020.2">
				</note>
				 an altar of cedar.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11006021">
			</marker>
			<verse num="21">
				And Solomon overlaid the inside of the house with pure gold, and he drew chains of gold across, in front of the inner sanctuary, and overlaid it with gold.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11006022">
			</marker>
			<verse num="22">
				And he overlaid the whole house with gold, until all the house was finished. 
				<crossref let="q" cid="c11006022.1">
				</crossref>
				Also the whole altar that belonged to the inner sanctuary he overlaid with gold.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11006023">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="23">
				<crossref let="r" cid="c11006023.1">
				</crossref>
				In the inner sanctuary 
				<crossref let="s" cid="c11006023.2">
				</crossref>
				he made two cherubim of olivewood, each ten cubits high.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11006024">
			</marker>
			<verse num="24">
				Five cubits was the length of one wing of the cherub, and five cubits the length of the other wing of the cherub; it was ten cubits from the tip of one wing to the tip of the other.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11006025">
			</marker>
			<verse num="25">
				The other cherub also measured ten cubits; both cherubim had the same measure and the same form.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11006026">
			</marker>
			<verse num="26">
				The height of one cherub was ten cubits, and so was that of the other cherub.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11006027">
			</marker>
			<verse num="27">
				He put the cherubim in the innermost part of the house. 
				<crossref let="t" cid="c11006027.1">
				</crossref>
				And the wings of the cherubim were spread out so that a wing of one touched the one wall, and a wing of the other cherub touched the other wall; their other wings touched each other in the middle of the house.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11006028">
			</marker>
			<verse num="28">
				And he overlaid the cherubim with gold.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11006029">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="29">
				Around all the walls of the house he carved engraved figures of cherubim and palm trees and open flowers, in the inner and outer rooms.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11006030">
			</marker>
			<verse num="30">
				The floor of the house he overlaid with gold in the inner and outer rooms.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11006031">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="31">
				For the entrance to the inner sanctuary he made doors of olivewood; the lintel and the doorposts were five-sided.
				<note nid="n11006031.1">
				</note>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11006032">
			</marker>
			<verse num="32">
				He covered the two doors of olivewood with carvings of cherubim, palm trees, and open flowers. He overlaid them with gold and spread gold on the cherubim and on the palm trees.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11006033">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="33">
				So also he made for the entrance to the nave doorposts of olivewood, in the form of a square,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11006034">
			</marker>
			<verse num="34">
				and two doors of cypress wood. 
				<crossref let="u" cid="c11006034.1">
				</crossref>
				The two leaves of the one door were folding, and the two leaves of the other door were folding.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11006035">
			</marker>
			<verse num="35">
				On them he carved cherubim and palm trees and open flowers, and he overlaid them with gold evenly applied on the carved work.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11006036">
			</marker>
			<verse num="36">
				<crossref let="v" cid="c11006036.1">
				</crossref>
				He built the inner court with three courses of cut stone and one course of cedar beams.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11006037">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="37">
				<crossref let="w" cid="c11006037.1">
				</crossref>
				In the fourth year the foundation of the house of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 was laid, in the month of Ziv.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11006038">
			</marker>
			<verse num="38">
				And in the eleventh year, in the month of Bul, which is the eighth month, the house was finished in all its parts, and according to all its specifications. He was seven years in building it.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
		</chapter>
	</book>
</crossway-bible>


