<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> 
<crossway-bible>
	<book title="2 Kings" num="11">
		<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12016001">
		</marker>
		<chapter num="16">
			<heading
				>
				Ahaz Reigns in Judah
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="1">
				In the seventeenth year of Pekah the son of Remaliah, Ahaz the son of Jotham, king of Judah, began to reign.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12016002">
			</marker>
			<verse num="2">
				Ahaz was 
				<crossref let="y" cid="c12016002.1">
				</crossref>
				twenty years old when he began to reign, and he reigned sixteen years in Jerusalem. And he did not do what was right in the eyes of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 his God, as his father David had done,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12016003">
			</marker>
			<verse num="3">
				but he walked in the way of the kings of Israel. 
				<crossref let="z" cid="c12016003.1">
				</crossref>
				He even burned his son as an offering,
				<note nid="n12016003.1">
				</note>
				<crossref let="a" cid="c12016003.2">
				</crossref>
				according to the despicable practices of the nations whom the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 drove out before the people of Israel.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12016004">
			</marker>
			<verse num="4">
				<crossref let="b" cid="c12016004.1">
				</crossref>
				And he sacrificed and made offerings 
				<crossref let="c" cid="c12016004.2">
				</crossref>
				on the high places and on the hills and under every green tree.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12016005">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="5">
				<crossref let="d" cid="c12016005.1">
				</crossref>
				Then Rezin king of Syria and 
				<crossref let="d" cid="c12016005.2">
				</crossref>
				Pekah the son of Remaliah, king of Israel, came up to wage war on Jerusalem, and they besieged Ahaz 
				<crossref let="e" cid="c12016005.3">
				</crossref>
				but could not conquer him.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12016006">
			</marker>
			<verse num="6">
				At that time Rezin the king of Syria recovered 
				<crossref let="f" cid="c12016006.1">
				</crossref>
				Elath for Syria and drove the men of Judah from 
				<crossref let="f" cid="c12016006.2">
				</crossref>
				Elath, and the Edomites came to Elath, where they dwell to this day.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12016007">
			</marker>
			<verse num="7">
				<crossref let="g" cid="c12016007.1">
				</crossref>
				So Ahaz sent messengers to 
				<crossref let="h" cid="c12016007.2">
				</crossref>
				Tiglath-pileser king of Assyria, saying, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				I am your servant and your son. Come up and rescue me from the hand of the king of Syria and from the hand of the king of Israel, who are attacking me.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12016008">
			</marker>
			<verse num="8">
				Ahaz also 
				<crossref let="i" cid="c12016008.1">
				</crossref>
				took the silver and gold that was found in the house of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 and in the treasures of the king's house and sent a present to the king of Assyria.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12016009">
			</marker>
			<verse num="9">
				<crossref let="j" cid="c12016009.1">
				</crossref>
				And the king of Assyria listened to him. The king of Assyria marched up against Damascus 
				<crossref let="k" cid="c12016009.2">
				</crossref>
				and took it, carrying its people captive to 
				<crossref let="l" cid="c12016009.3">
				</crossref>
				Kir, and he killed Rezin.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12016010">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="10">
				When King Ahaz went to Damascus to meet 
				<crossref let="m" cid="c12016010.1">
				</crossref>
				Tiglath-pileser king of Assyria, he saw the altar that was at Damascus. And King Ahaz sent to 
				<crossref let="n" cid="c12016010.2">
				</crossref>
				Uriah the priest a model of the altar, and its pattern, exact in all its details.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12016011">
			</marker>
			<verse num="11">
				And Uriah the priest built the altar; in accordance with all that King Ahaz had sent from Damascus, so Uriah the priest made it, before King Ahaz arrived from Damascus.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12016012">
			</marker>
			<verse num="12">
				And when the king came from Damascus, the king viewed the altar. 
				<crossref let="o" cid="c12016012.1">
				</crossref>
				Then the king drew near to the altar and went up on it
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12016013">
			</marker>
			<verse num="13">
				and burned his burnt offering and his grain offering and poured his drink offering and threw the blood of his peace offerings on the altar.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12016014">
			</marker>
			<verse num="14">
				And 
				<crossref let="p" cid="c12016014.1">
				</crossref>
				the bronze altar that was before the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 he removed 
				<crossref let="q" cid="c12016014.2">
				</crossref>
				from the front of the house, from the place between 
				<crossref let="r" cid="c12016014.3">
				</crossref>
				his altar and the house of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				, and put it on the north side of 
				<crossref let="r" cid="c12016014.4">
				</crossref>
				his altar.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12016015">
			</marker>
			<verse num="15">
				And King Ahaz commanded Uriah the priest, saying, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				On the great altar burn 
				<crossref let="s" cid="c12016015.1">
				</crossref>
				the morning burnt offering and the evening grain offering and the king's burnt offering and his grain offering, with the burnt offering of all the people of the land, and their grain offering and their drink offering. And throw on it all the blood of the burnt offering and all the blood of the sacrifice, but 
				<crossref let="t" cid="c12016015.2">
				</crossref>
				the bronze altar shall be for me to inquire by.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12016016">
			</marker>
			<verse num="16">
				Uriah the priest did all this, as King Ahaz commanded.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12016017">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="17">
				And King Ahaz cut off the frames of the stands and removed the basin from them, and he took down 
				<crossref let="u" cid="c12016017.1">
				</crossref>
				the sea
				<note nid="n12016017.1">
				</note>
				 from off the bronze oxen that were under it and put it on a stone pedestal.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12016018">
			</marker>
			<verse num="18">
				And the covered way for the Sabbath that had been built inside the house and the outer entrance for the king he caused to go around the house of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				, because of the king of Assyria.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12016019">
			</marker>
			<verse num="19">
				Now the rest of the acts of Ahaz that he did, are they not written 
				<crossref let="v" cid="c12016019.1">
				</crossref>
				in the Book of the Chronicles of the Kings of Judah?
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12016020">
			</marker>
			<verse num="20">
				And Ahaz slept with his fathers and 
				<crossref let="w" cid="c12016020.1">
				</crossref>
				was buried with his fathers in the city of David, and Hezekiah his son reigned in his place.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
		</chapter>
	</book>
</crossway-bible>


