<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> 
<crossway-bible>
	<book title="1 Kings" num="10">
		<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11007001">
		</marker>
		<chapter num="7">
			<heading
				>
				Solomon Builds His Palace
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="1">
				Solomon was 
				<crossref let="x" cid="c11007001.1">
				</crossref>
				building his own house thirteen years, and he finished his entire house.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11007002">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="2">
				He built 
				<crossref let="y" cid="c11007002.1">
				</crossref>
				the House of the Forest of Lebanon. Its length was a hundred cubits
				<note nid="n11007002.1">
				</note>
				 and its breadth fifty cubits and its height thirty cubits, and it was built on four
				<note nid="n11007002.2">
				</note>
				 rows of cedar pillars, with cedar beams on the pillars.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11007003">
			</marker>
			<verse num="3">
				And it was covered with cedar above the chambers that were on the forty-five pillars, fifteen in each row.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11007004">
			</marker>
			<verse num="4">
				There were window frames in three rows, and window opposite window in three tiers.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11007005">
			</marker>
			<verse num="5">
				All the doorways and windows
				<note nid="n11007005.1">
				</note>
				 had square frames, and window was opposite window in three tiers.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11007006">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="6">
				And he made 
				<crossref let="z" cid="c11007006.1">
				</crossref>
				the Hall of Pillars; its length was fifty cubits, and its breadth thirty cubits. There was a porch in front with pillars, and 
				<crossref let="a" cid="c11007006.2">
				</crossref>
				a canopy in front of them.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11007007">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="7">
				And he made the Hall of the Throne where he was to pronounce judgment, even the Hall of Judgment. 
				<crossref let="b" cid="c11007007.1">
				</crossref>
				It was finished with cedar from floor to rafters.
				<note nid="n11007007.1">
				</note>
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11007008">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="8">
				His own house where he was to dwell, in the other court back of the hall, was of like workmanship. Solomon also made a house like this hall for Pharaoh's daughter 
				<crossref let="c" cid="c11007008.1">
				</crossref>
				whom he had taken in marriage.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11007009">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="9">
				All these were made of costly stones, cut according to measure, sawed with saws, back and front, even from the foundation to the coping, and from the outside to the great court.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11007010">
			</marker>
			<verse num="10">
				The foundation was of costly stones, huge stones, stones of eight and ten cubits.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11007011">
			</marker>
			<verse num="11">
				And above were costly stones, cut according to measurement, and cedar.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11007012">
			</marker>
			<verse num="12">
				<crossref let="d" cid="c11007012.1">
				</crossref>
				The great court had three courses of cut stone all around, and a course of cedar beams; so had the inner court of the house of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 and 
				<crossref let="e" cid="c11007012.2">
				</crossref>
				the vestibule of the house.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11007013">
			</marker>
			<heading
				>
				The Temple Furnishings
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="13">
				And King Solomon sent and brought 
				<crossref let="f" cid="c11007013.1">
				</crossref>
				Hiram from Tyre.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11007014">
			</marker>
			<verse num="14">
				He was the son of a widow of the tribe of Naphtali, and his father was a man of Tyre, a worker in bronze. And 
				<crossref let="g" cid="c11007014.1">
				</crossref>
				he was full of wisdom, understanding, and skill for making any work in bronze. He came to King Solomon and did all his work.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11007015">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="15">
				<crossref let="h" cid="c11007015.1">
				</crossref>
				He cast 
				<crossref let="i" cid="c11007015.2">
				</crossref>
				two pillars of bronze. 
				<crossref let="j" cid="c11007015.3">
				</crossref>
				Eighteen cubits was the height of one pillar, and a line of twelve cubits measured its circumference. It was hollow, and its thickness was four fingers. The second pillar was the same.
				<note nid="n11007015.1">
				</note>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11007016">
			</marker>
			<verse num="16">
				He also made two capitals of cast bronze to set on the tops of the pillars. The height of the one capital was five cubits, and 
				<crossref let="j" cid="c11007016.1">
				</crossref>
				the height of the other capital was five cubits.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11007017">
			</marker>
			<verse num="17">
				There were lattices of checker work with wreaths of chain work for the capitals on the tops of the pillars, a lattice
				<note nid="n11007017.1">
				</note>
				 for the one capital and a lattice for the other capital.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11007018">
			</marker>
			<verse num="18">
				Likewise he made pomegranates
				<note nid="n11007018.1">
				</note>
				 in two rows around the one latticework to cover the capital that was on the top of the pillar, and he did the same with the other capital.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11007019">
			</marker>
			<verse num="19">
				Now the capitals that were on the tops of the pillars in the vestibule were of lily-work, four cubits.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11007020">
			</marker>
			<verse num="20">
				The capitals were on the two pillars and also above the rounded projection which was beside the latticework. There were 
				<crossref let="k" cid="c11007020.1">
				</crossref>
				two hundred pomegranates in two rows all around, and so with the other capital.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11007021">
			</marker>
			<verse num="21">
				<crossref let="l" cid="c11007021.1">
				</crossref>
				He set up the pillars at the vestibule of the temple. He set up the pillar on the south and called its name Jachin, and he set up the pillar on the north and called its name Boaz.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11007022">
			</marker>
			<verse num="22">
				And on the tops of the pillars was lily-work. Thus the work of the pillars was finished.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11007023">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="23">
				<crossref let="m" cid="c11007023.1">
				</crossref>
				Then he made 
				<crossref let="n" cid="c11007023.2">
				</crossref>
				the sea of cast metal. It was round, ten cubits from brim to brim, and five cubits high, and a line of thirty cubits measured its circumference.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11007024">
			</marker>
			<verse num="24">
				Under its brim were 
				<crossref let="o" cid="c11007024.1">
				</crossref>
				gourds, for ten cubits, compassing the sea all around. The gourds were in two rows, cast with it when it was cast.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11007025">
			</marker>
			<verse num="25">
				It stood on 
				<crossref let="p" cid="c11007025.1">
				</crossref>
				twelve oxen, three facing north, three facing west, three facing south, and three facing east. The sea was set on them, and all their rear parts were inward.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11007026">
			</marker>
			<verse num="26">
				Its thickness was a handbreadth,
				<note nid="n11007026.1">
				</note>
				 and its brim was made like the brim of a cup, like the flower of a lily. It held two thousand baths.
				<note nid="n11007026.2">
				</note>
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11007027">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="27">
				He also made the 
				<crossref let="q" cid="c11007027.1">
				</crossref>
				ten stands of bronze. Each stand was four cubits long, four cubits wide, and three cubits high.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11007028">
			</marker>
			<verse num="28">
				This was the construction of the stands: they had panels, and the panels were set in the frames,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11007029">
			</marker>
			<verse num="29">
				and on the panels that were set in the frames were lions, oxen, and cherubim. On the frames, both above and below the lions and oxen, there were wreaths of beveled work.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11007030">
			</marker>
			<verse num="30">
				Moreover, each stand had four bronze wheels and axles of bronze, and at the four corners were supports for a basin. The supports were cast with wreaths at the side of each.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11007031">
			</marker>
			<verse num="31">
				Its opening was within a crown that projected upward one cubit. Its opening was round, as a pedestal is made, a cubit and a half deep. At its opening there were carvings, and its panels were square, not round.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11007032">
			</marker>
			<verse num="32">
				And the four wheels were underneath the panels. The axles of the wheels were of one piece with the stands, and the height of a wheel was a cubit and a half.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11007033">
			</marker>
			<verse num="33">
				The wheels were made like a chariot wheel; their axles, their rims, their spokes, and their hubs were all cast.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11007034">
			</marker>
			<verse num="34">
				There were four supports at the four corners of each stand. The supports were of one piece with the stands.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11007035">
			</marker>
			<verse num="35">
				And on the top of the stand there was a round band half a cubit high; and on the top of the stand its stays and its panels were of one piece with it.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11007036">
			</marker>
			<verse num="36">
				And on the surfaces of its stays and on its panels, he carved cherubim, lions, and palm trees, according to the space of each, with wreaths all around.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11007037">
			</marker>
			<verse num="37">
				After this manner he made 
				<crossref let="q" cid="c11007037.1">
				</crossref>
				the ten stands. All of them were cast alike, of the same measure and the same form.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11007038">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="38">
				And he made 
				<crossref let="r" cid="c11007038.1">
				</crossref>
				ten basins of bronze. Each basin held forty baths, each basin measured four cubits, and there was a basin for each of the ten stands.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11007039">
			</marker>
			<verse num="39">
				And he set the stands, five on the south side of the house, and five on the north side of the house. And he set the sea at the southeast corner of the house.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11007040">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="40">
				<crossref let="s" cid="c11007040.1">
				</crossref>
				Hiram also made 
				<crossref let="t" cid="c11007040.2">
				</crossref>
				the pots, the shovels, and the basins. So Hiram finished all the work that he did for King Solomon on the house of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				:
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11007041">
			</marker>
			<verse num="41">
				the two pillars, the two bowls of the capitals that were on the tops of the pillars, and the two 
				<crossref let="u" cid="c11007041.1">
				</crossref>
				latticeworks to cover the two bowls of the capitals that were on the tops of the pillars;
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11007042">
			</marker>
			<verse num="42">
				and the 
				<crossref let="v" cid="c11007042.1">
				</crossref>
				four hundred pomegranates for the two latticeworks, two rows of pomegranates for each latticework, to cover the two bowls of the capitals that were on the pillars;
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11007043">
			</marker>
			<verse num="43">
				the ten stands, and the ten basins on the stands;
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11007044">
			</marker>
			<verse num="44">
				and 
				<crossref let="w" cid="c11007044.1">
				</crossref>
				the one sea, and the twelve oxen underneath the sea.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11007045">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="45">
				Now 
				<crossref let="x" cid="c11007045.1">
				</crossref>
				the pots, the shovels, and the basins, all these vessels in the house of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				, which Hiram made for King Solomon, were of burnished bronze.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11007046">
			</marker>
			<verse num="46">
				In the plain of the Jordan the king cast them, in the clay ground between 
				<crossref let="y" cid="c11007046.1">
				</crossref>
				Succoth and 
				<crossref let="z" cid="c11007046.2">
				</crossref>
				Zarethan.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11007047">
			</marker>
			<verse num="47">
				And Solomon left all the vessels unweighed, because there were so many of them; 
				<crossref let="a" cid="c11007047.1">
				</crossref>
				the weight of the bronze was not ascertained.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11007048">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="48">
				So Solomon made all the vessels that were in the house of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				: 
				<crossref let="b" cid="c11007048.1">
				</crossref>
				the golden altar, 
				<crossref let="c" cid="c11007048.2">
				</crossref>
				the golden table for 
				<crossref let="d" cid="c11007048.3">
				</crossref>
				the bread of the Presence,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11007049">
			</marker>
			<verse num="49">
				<crossref let="e" cid="c11007049.1">
				</crossref>
				the lampstands of pure gold, five on the south side and five on the north, before the inner sanctuary; 
				<crossref let="f" cid="c11007049.2">
				</crossref>
				the flowers, the lamps, and the tongs, of gold;
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11007050">
			</marker>
			<verse num="50">
				the cups, snuffers, basins, dishes for incense, and 
				<crossref let="g" cid="c11007050.1">
				</crossref>
				fire pans, of pure gold; and the sockets of gold, for the doors of the innermost part of the house, 
				<crossref let="h" cid="c11007050.2">
				</crossref>
				the Most Holy Place, and for the doors of the nave of the temple.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v11007051">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="51">
				Thus all the work that King Solomon did on the house of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 was finished. And Solomon brought in 
				<crossref let="i" cid="c11007051.1">
				</crossref>
				the things that David his father had dedicated, the silver, the gold, and the vessels, and stored them in the treasuries of the house of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
		</chapter>
	</book>
</crossway-bible>


