<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> 
<crossway-bible>
	<book title="2 Kings" num="11">
		<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12025001">
		</marker>
		<chapter num="25">
			<heading
				>
				Fall and Captivity of Judah
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="1">
				<crossref let="u" cid="c12025001.1">
				</crossref>
				And in the ninth year of his reign, in the tenth month, on the tenth day of the month, 
				<crossref let="v" cid="c12025001.2">
				</crossref>
				Nebuchadnezzar king of Babylon came with all his army against Jerusalem and laid siege to it. 
				<crossref let="w" cid="c12025001.3">
				</crossref>
				And they built siegeworks all around it.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12025002">
			</marker>
			<verse num="2">
				So the city was besieged till the eleventh year of King Zedekiah.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12025003">
			</marker>
			<verse num="3">
				On the ninth day of the fourth month 
				<crossref let="x" cid="c12025003.1">
				</crossref>
				the famine was so severe in the city that there was no food for the people of the land.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12025004">
			</marker>
			<verse num="4">
				Then a breach was made in the city, and all the men of war fled by night by the way of the gate between the two walls, by 
				<crossref let="y" cid="c12025004.1">
				</crossref>
				the king's garden, though 
				<crossref let="z" cid="c12025004.2">
				</crossref>
				the Chaldeans were around the city. And they went in the direction of the 
				<crossref let="a" cid="c12025004.3">
				</crossref>
				Arabah.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12025005">
			</marker>
			<verse num="5">
				But the army of the Chaldeans pursued the king and overtook him in the plains of Jericho, and all his army was scattered from him.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12025006">
			</marker>
			<verse num="6">
				Then they captured the king 
				<crossref let="b" cid="c12025006.1">
				</crossref>
				and brought him up to the king of Babylon at 
				<crossref let="c" cid="c12025006.2">
				</crossref>
				Riblah, and they passed sentence on him.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12025007">
			</marker>
			<verse num="7">
				They slaughtered the sons of Zedekiah before his eyes, 
				<crossref let="d" cid="c12025007.1">
				</crossref>
				and put out the eyes of Zedekiah and bound him in chains and took him to Babylon.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12025008">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="8">
				<crossref let="e" cid="c12025008.1">
				</crossref>
				In the fifth month, on 
				<crossref let="f" cid="c12025008.2">
				</crossref>
				the seventh day of the monthùthat was the nineteenth year of King Nebuchadnezzar, king of BabylonùNebuzaradan, the captain of the bodyguard, a servant of the king of Babylon, came to Jerusalem.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12025009">
			</marker>
			<verse num="9">
				<crossref let="g" cid="c12025009.1">
				</crossref>
				And he burned the house of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				<crossref let="h" cid="c12025009.2">
				</crossref>
				and the king's house and all the houses of Jerusalem; every great house he burned down.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12025010">
			</marker>
			<verse num="10">
				And all the army of the Chaldeans, who were with the captain of the guard, 
				<crossref let="i" cid="c12025010.1">
				</crossref>
				broke down the walls around Jerusalem.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12025011">
			</marker>
			<verse num="11">
				<crossref let="j" cid="c12025011.1">
				</crossref>
				And the rest of the people who were left in the city and the deserters who had deserted to the king of Babylon, together with the rest of the multitude, Nebuzaradan the captain of the guard carried into exile.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12025012">
			</marker>
			<verse num="12">
				But the captain of the guard left 
				<crossref let="k" cid="c12025012.1">
				</crossref>
				some of the poorest of the land to be vinedressers and plowmen.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12025013">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="13">
				<crossref let="l" cid="c12025013.1">
				</crossref>
				And the pillars 
				<crossref let="m" cid="c12025013.2">
				</crossref>
				of bronze that were in the house of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				, and 
				<crossref let="n" cid="c12025013.3">
				</crossref>
				the stands and 
				<crossref let="o" cid="c12025013.4">
				</crossref>
				the bronze sea that were in the house of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				, the Chaldeans broke in pieces and carried the bronze to Babylon.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12025014">
			</marker>
			<verse num="14">
				<crossref let="p" cid="c12025014.1">
				</crossref>
				And they took away the pots and the shovels and the snuffers and the dishes for incense and all the vessels of bronze used in the temple service,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12025015">
			</marker>
			<verse num="15">
				the fire pans also and the bowls. What was of gold the captain of the guard took away as gold, and what was of silver, as silver.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12025016">
			</marker>
			<verse num="16">
				As for the two pillars, the one sea, and the stands that Solomon had made for the house of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				, 
				<crossref let="q" cid="c12025016.1">
				</crossref>
				the bronze of all these vessels was beyond weight.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12025017">
			</marker>
			<verse num="17">
				<crossref let="r" cid="c12025017.1">
				</crossref>
				The height of the one pillar was eighteen cubits,
				<note nid="n12025017.1">
				</note>
				 and on it was a capital of bronze. The height of the capital was three cubits. A latticework and pomegranates, all of bronze, were all around the capital. And the second pillar had the same, with the latticework.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12025018">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="18">
				<crossref let="s" cid="c12025018.1">
				</crossref>
				And the captain of the guard took 
				<crossref let="t" cid="c12025018.2">
				</crossref>
				Seraiah the chief priest and 
				<crossref let="u" cid="c12025018.3">
				</crossref>
				Zephaniah the second priest and the three keepers of the threshold,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12025019">
			</marker>
			<verse num="19">
				and from the city he took an officer who had been in command of the men of war, and 
				<crossref let="v" cid="c12025019.1">
				</crossref>
				five men of the king's council who were found in the city, and the secretary of the commander of the army who mustered the people of the land, and sixty men of the people of the land who were found in the city.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12025020">
			</marker>
			<verse num="20">
				And Nebuzaradan the captain of the guard took them and brought them to the king of Babylon at 
				<crossref let="w" cid="c12025020.1">
				</crossref>
				Riblah.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12025021">
			</marker>
			<verse num="21">
				And the king of Babylon struck them down and put them to death at 
				<crossref let="w" cid="c12025021.1">
				</crossref>
				Riblah in the land of Hamath. 
				<crossref let="x" cid="c12025021.2">
				</crossref>
				So Judah was taken into exile out of its land.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12025022">
			</marker>
			<heading
				>
				Gedaliah Made Governor of Judah
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="22">
				And over the people who remained in the land of Judah, whom Nebuchadnezzar king of Babylon had left, he appointed 
				<crossref let="y" cid="c12025022.1">
				</crossref>
				Gedaliah the son of 
				<crossref let="z" cid="c12025022.2">
				</crossref>
				Ahikam, son of Shaphan, governor.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12025023">
			</marker>
			<verse num="23">
				<crossref let="a" cid="c12025023.1">
				</crossref>
				Now when all the captains and their men heard that the king of Babylon had appointed Gedaliah governor, they came with their men to Gedaliah at 
				<crossref let="b" cid="c12025023.2">
				</crossref>
				Mizpah, namely, Ishmael the son of Nethaniah, and Johanan the son of Kareah, and Seraiah the son of Tanhumeth the Netophathite, and Jaazaniah the son of the Maacathite.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12025024">
			</marker>
			<verse num="24">
				And Gedaliah swore to them and their men, saying, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Do not be afraid because of the Chaldean officials. Live in the land and serve the king of Babylon, and it shall be well with you.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12025025">
			</marker>
			<verse num="25">
				<crossref let="c" cid="c12025025.1">
				</crossref>
				But in the seventh month, 
				<crossref let="d" cid="c12025025.2">
				</crossref>
				Ishmael the son of Nethaniah, son of Elishama, of the royal family, came with ten men and struck down Gedaliah and put him to death along with the Jews and the Chaldeans who were with him at Mizpah.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12025026">
			</marker>
			<verse num="26">
				<crossref let="e" cid="c12025026.1">
				</crossref>
				Then all the people, both small and great, and the captains of the forces arose and went to Egypt, for they were afraid of the Chaldeans.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12025027">
			</marker>
			<heading
				>
				Jehoiachin Released from Prison
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="27">
				<crossref let="f" cid="c12025027.1">
				</crossref>
				And in the thirty-seventh year of 
				<crossref let="g" cid="c12025027.2">
				</crossref>
				the exile of Jehoiachin king of Judah, in the twelfth month, on the twenty-seventh day of the month, Evil-merodach king of Babylon, in the year that he began to reign, graciously 
				<crossref let="h" cid="c12025027.3">
				</crossref>
				freed
				<note nid="n12025027.1">
				</note>
				 Jehoiachin king of Judah from prison.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12025028">
			</marker>
			<verse num="28">
				And he spoke kindly to him and gave him a seat above the seats of the kings who were with him in Babylon.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12025029">
			</marker>
			<verse num="29">
				So Jehoiachin put off his prison garments. And every day of his life 
				<crossref let="i" cid="c12025029.1">
				</crossref>
				he dined regularly at the king's table,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12025030">
			</marker>
			<verse num="30">
				and for his allowance, a regular allowance was given him by the king, according to his daily needs, as long as he lived.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
		</chapter>
	</book>
</crossway-bible>


