<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> 
<crossway-bible>
	<book title="2 Kings" num="11">
		<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12012001">
		</marker>
		<chapter num="12">
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="1">
				In the seventh year of Jehu, Jehoash
				<note nid="n12012001.1">
				</note>
				 began to reign, and he reigned forty years in Jerusalem. His mother's name was Zibiah of Beersheba.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12012002">
			</marker>
			<verse num="2">
				And Jehoash did what was right in the eyes of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 all his days, because Jehoiada the priest instructed him.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12012003">
			</marker>
			<verse num="3">
				Nevertheless, 
				<crossref let="r" cid="c12012003.1">
				</crossref>
				the high places were not taken away; the people continued to sacrifice and make offerings on the high places.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12012004">
			</marker>
			<heading
				>
				Jehoash Repairs the Temple
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="4">
				Jehoash said to the priests, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				All the money of the holy things 
				<crossref let="s" cid="c12012004.1">
				</crossref>
				that is brought into the house of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				, the money for which each man is assessedùthe money from the assessment of personsùand 
				<crossref let="t" cid="c12012004.2">
				</crossref>
				the money that a man's heart prompts him to bring into the house of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12012005">
			</marker>
			<verse num="5">
				let the priests take, each from his donor, and let them repair the house wherever any need of repairs is discovered.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12012006">
			</marker>
			<verse num="6">
				But by the twenty-third year of King Jehoash, the priests had made no repairs on the house.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12012007">
			</marker>
			<verse num="7">
				Therefore King Jehoash summoned Jehoiada the priest and the other priests and said to them, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Why are you not repairing the house? Now therefore take no more money from your donors, but hand it over for the repair of the house.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12012008">
			</marker>
			<verse num="8">
				So the priests agreed that they should take no more money from the people, and that they should not repair the house.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12012009">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="9">
				Then Jehoiada the priest took 
				<crossref let="u" cid="c12012009.1">
				</crossref>
				a chest and bored a hole in the lid of it and set it beside the altar on the right side as one entered the house of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				. And the priests who guarded the threshold put in it all the money that was brought into the house of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12012010">
			</marker>
			<verse num="10">
				And whenever they saw that there was much money in the chest, the king's secretary and the high priest came up and they bagged and counted 
				<crossref let="v" cid="c12012010.1">
				</crossref>
				the money that was found in the house of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12012011">
			</marker>
			<verse num="11">
				Then they would give the money that was weighed out into the hands of the workmen who had the oversight of the house of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				. And they paid it out to the carpenters and the builders who worked on the house of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12012012">
			</marker>
			<verse num="12">
				and 
				<crossref let="w" cid="c12012012.1">
				</crossref>
				to the masons and the stonecutters, as well as to buy timber and quarried stone for making repairs on the house of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				, and for any outlay for the repairs of the house.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12012013">
			</marker>
			<verse num="13">
				<crossref let="x" cid="c12012013.1">
				</crossref>
				But there were not made for the house of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				<crossref let="y" cid="c12012013.2">
				</crossref>
				basins of silver, snuffers, bowls, trumpets, or any vessels of gold, or of silver, from the money that was brought into the house of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12012014">
			</marker>
			<verse num="14">
				for that was given to the workmen who were repairing the house of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 with it.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12012015">
			</marker>
			<verse num="15">
				And 
				<crossref let="z" cid="c12012015.1">
				</crossref>
				they did not ask an accounting from the men into whose hand they delivered the money to pay out to the workmen, for they dealt honestly.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12012016">
			</marker>
			<verse num="16">
				The money from 
				<crossref let="a" cid="c12012016.1">
				</crossref>
				the guilt offerings and the money from the 
				<crossref let="b" cid="c12012016.2">
				</crossref>
				sin offerings was not brought into the house of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				; 
				<crossref let="c" cid="c12012016.3">
				</crossref>
				it belonged to the priests.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12012017">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="17">
				At that time 
				<crossref let="d" cid="c12012017.1">
				</crossref>
				Hazael king of Syria went up and fought against Gath and took it. But when Hazael set his face 
				<crossref let="e" cid="c12012017.2">
				</crossref>
				to go up against Jerusalem,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12012018">
			</marker>
			<verse num="18">
				Jehoash king of Judah 
				<crossref let="f" cid="c12012018.1">
				</crossref>
				took all the sacred gifts that Jehoshaphat and Jehoram and Ahaziah his fathers, the kings of Judah, had dedicated, 
				<crossref let="g" cid="c12012018.2">
				</crossref>
				and his own sacred gifts, and all the gold that was found in the treasuries of the house of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 and of the king's house, and sent these to Hazael king of Syria. Then Hazael went away from Jerusalem.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12012019">
			</marker>
			<heading
				>
				The Death of Joash
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="19">
				Now the rest of the acts of Joash and all that he did, are they not written in the Book of the Chronicles of the Kings of Judah?
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12012020">
			</marker>
			<verse num="20">
				<crossref let="h" cid="c12012020.1">
				</crossref>
				His servants arose and made a conspiracy 
				<crossref let="i" cid="c12012020.2">
				</crossref>
				and struck down Joash in the house of 
				<crossref let="j" cid="c12012020.3">
				</crossref>
				Millo, on the way that goes down to Silla.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v12012021">
			</marker>
			<verse num="21">
				It was 
				<crossref let="k" cid="c12012021.1">
				</crossref>
				Jozacar the son of Shimeath and Jehozabad the son of 
				<crossref let="k" cid="c12012021.2">
				</crossref>
				Shomer, his servants, who struck him down, so that he died. And they buried him with his fathers in the city of David, 
				<crossref let="l" cid="c12012021.3">
				</crossref>
				and Amaziah his son reigned in his place.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
		</chapter>
	</book>
</crossway-bible>


