<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> 
<crossway-bible>
	<book title="Leviticus" num="2">
		<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03004001">
		</marker>
		<chapter num="4">
			<heading
				>
				Laws for Sin Offerings
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="1">
				And the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 spoke to Moses, saying,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03004002">
			</marker>
			<verse num="2">
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Speak to the people of Israel, saying, 
				<crossref let="u" cid="c03004002.1">
				</crossref>
				If anyone sins unintentionally
				<note nid="n03004002.1">
				</note>
				 in any of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				's commandments 
				<crossref let="v" cid="c03004002.2">
				</crossref>
				about things not to be done, and does any one of them,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03004003">
			</marker>
			<verse num="3">
				if it is the anointed priest who 
				<crossref let="w" cid="c03004003.1">
				</crossref>
				sins, thus bringing guilt on the people, then he shall offer for the sin that he has committed 
				<crossref let="x" cid="c03004003.2">
				</crossref>
				a bull from the herd without blemish to the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 for a sin offering.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03004004">
			</marker>
			<verse num="4">
				He shall bring the bull to the 
				<crossref let="y" cid="c03004004.1">
				</crossref>
				entrance of the tent of meeting before the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 and lay his hand on the head of the bull and kill the bull before the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03004005">
			</marker>
			<verse num="5">
				And the anointed priest 
				<crossref let="z" cid="c03004005.1">
				</crossref>
				shall take some of the blood of the bull and bring it into the tent of meeting,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03004006">
			</marker>
			<verse num="6">
				and the priest shall dip his finger in the blood and 
				<crossref let="z" cid="c03004006.1">
				</crossref>
				sprinkle part of the blood seven times before the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 in front of the veil of the sanctuary.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03004007">
			</marker>
			<verse num="7">
				And the priest 
				<crossref let="a" cid="c03004007.1">
				</crossref>
				shall put some of the blood on the horns of the altar of fragrant incense before the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 that is in the tent of meeting, and 
				<crossref let="b" cid="c03004007.2">
				</crossref>
				all the rest of the blood of the bull he shall pour out at the base of the altar of burnt offering that is at the entrance of the tent of meeting.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03004008">
			</marker>
			<verse num="8">
				And all the fat of the bull of the sin offering he shall remove from it, 
				<crossref let="c" cid="c03004008.1">
				</crossref>
				the fat that covers the entrails and all the fat that is on the entrails
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03004009">
			</marker>
			<verse num="9">
				<crossref let="d" cid="c03004009.1">
				</crossref>
				and the two kidneys with the fat that is on them at the loins and the long lobe of the liver that he shall remove with the kidneys
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03004010">
			</marker>
			<verse num="10">
				(just as these are taken from the ox of the sacrifice of the peace offerings); and the priest shall burn them on the altar of burnt offering.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03004011">
			</marker>
			<verse num="11">
				But 
				<crossref let="e" cid="c03004011.1">
				</crossref>
				the skin of the bull and all its flesh, with its head, its legs, its entrails, and its dungù
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03004012">
			</marker>
			<verse num="12">
				all the rest of the bullùhe shall carry 
				<crossref let="f" cid="c03004012.1">
				</crossref>
				outside the camp to a clean place, to the ash heap, and shall 
				<crossref let="g" cid="c03004012.2">
				</crossref>
				burn it up on a fire of wood. On the ash heap it shall be burned up.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03004013">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="13">
				<crossref let="h" cid="c03004013.1">
				</crossref>
				<q class="continue-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				If the whole congregation of Israel sins unintentionally
				<note nid="n03004013.1">
				</note>
				 and 
				<crossref let="i" cid="c03004013.2">
				</crossref>
				the thing is hidden from the eyes of the assembly, and they do any one of the things that by the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				's commandments ought not to be done, and they realize their guilt,
				<note nid="n03004013.2">
				</note>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03004014">
			</marker>
			<verse num="14">
				<crossref let="j" cid="c03004014.1">
				</crossref>
				when the sin which they have committed becomes known, the assembly shall offer a bull from the herd for a sin offering and bring it in front of the tent of meeting.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03004015">
			</marker>
			<verse num="15">
				And the elders of the congregation 
				<crossref let="k" cid="c03004015.1">
				</crossref>
				shall lay their hands on the head of the bull before the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				, and the bull shall be killed before the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03004016">
			</marker>
			<verse num="16">
				Then 
				<crossref let="l" cid="c03004016.1">
				</crossref>
				the anointed priest shall bring some of the blood of the bull into the tent of meeting,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03004017">
			</marker>
			<verse num="17">
				and the priest shall dip his finger in the blood and sprinkle it seven times before the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 in front of the veil.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03004018">
			</marker>
			<verse num="18">
				And he shall put some of the blood on the horns of the altar that is in the tent of meeting before the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				, and the rest of the blood he shall pour out at the base of the altar of burnt offering that is at the entrance of the tent of meeting.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03004019">
			</marker>
			<verse num="19">
				And all its fat he shall take from it and burn on the altar.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03004020">
			</marker>
			<verse num="20">
				Thus shall he do with the bull. As he did 
				<crossref let="m" cid="c03004020.1">
				</crossref>
				with the bull of the sin offering, so shall he do with this. 
				<crossref let="n" cid="c03004020.2">
				</crossref>
				And the priest shall make atonement for them, and they shall be forgiven.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03004021">
			</marker>
			<verse num="21">
				And he shall carry the bull 
				<crossref let="f" cid="c03004021.1">
				</crossref>
				outside the camp and burn it up as he burned the first bull; it is the sin offering for the assembly.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03004022">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="22">
				<q class="continue-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				When a leader sins, 
				<crossref let="o" cid="c03004022.1">
				</crossref>
				doing unintentionally any one of all the things that by the commandments of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 his God ought not to be done, and realizes his guilt,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03004023">
			</marker>
			<verse num="23">
				or 
				<crossref let="p" cid="c03004023.1">
				</crossref>
				the sin which he has committed is made known to him, he shall bring as his offering a goat, a male without blemish,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03004024">
			</marker>
			<verse num="24">
				and 
				<crossref let="q" cid="c03004024.1">
				</crossref>
				shall lay his hand on the head of the goat and kill it in the place where they kill the burnt offering before the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				; it is a sin offering.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03004025">
			</marker>
			<verse num="25">
				<crossref let="r" cid="c03004025.1">
				</crossref>
				Then the priest shall take some of the blood of the sin offering with his finger and put it on the horns of the altar of burnt offering and pour out the rest of its blood at the base of the altar of burnt offering.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03004026">
			</marker>
			<verse num="26">
				And all its fat he shall burn on the altar, like 
				<crossref let="s" cid="c03004026.1">
				</crossref>
				the fat of the sacrifice of peace offerings. So 
				<crossref let="t" cid="c03004026.2">
				</crossref>
				the priest shall make atonement for him for his sin, and he shall be forgiven.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03004027">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="27">
				<q class="continue-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				If 
				<crossref let="u" cid="c03004027.1">
				</crossref>
				anyone of the common people sins unintentionally in doing any one of the things that by the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				's commandments ought not to be done, and realizes his guilt,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03004028">
			</marker>
			<verse num="28">
				<crossref let="v" cid="c03004028.1">
				</crossref>
				or the sin which he has committed is made known to him, he shall bring for his offering a goat, a female without blemish, for his sin which he has committed.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03004029">
			</marker>
			<verse num="29">
				<crossref let="w" cid="c03004029.1">
				</crossref>
				And he shall lay his hand on the head of the sin offering and kill the sin offering in the place of burnt offering.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03004030">
			</marker>
			<verse num="30">
				And the priest shall take some of its blood with his finger and put it on the horns of the altar of burnt offering and pour out all the rest of its blood at the base of the altar.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03004031">
			</marker>
			<verse num="31">
				And 
				<crossref let="x" cid="c03004031.1">
				</crossref>
				all its fat he shall remove, 
				<crossref let="y" cid="c03004031.2">
				</crossref>
				as the fat is removed from the peace offerings, and the priest shall burn it on the altar for a 
				<crossref let="z" cid="c03004031.3">
				</crossref>
				pleasing aroma to the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				. 
				<crossref let="a" cid="c03004031.4">
				</crossref>
				And the priest shall make atonement for him, and he shall be forgiven.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03004032">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="32">
				<q class="continue-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				If he brings a lamb as his offering for a sin offering, he shall bring 
				<crossref let="b" cid="c03004032.1">
				</crossref>
				a female without blemish
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03004033">
			</marker>
			<verse num="33">
				<crossref let="w" cid="c03004033.1">
				</crossref>
				and lay his hand on the head of the sin offering and kill it for a sin offering in the place where they kill the burnt offering.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03004034">
			</marker>
			<verse num="34">
				Then the priest shall take some of the blood of the sin offering with his finger and put it on the horns of the altar of burnt offering and pour out all the rest of its blood at the base of the altar.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03004035">
			</marker>
			<verse num="35">
				And all its fat he shall remove 
				<crossref let="c" cid="c03004035.1">
				</crossref>
				as the fat of the lamb is removed from the sacrifice of peace offerings, and the priest shall burn it on the altar, on top of the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				's food offerings. 
				<crossref let="d" cid="c03004035.2">
				</crossref>
				And the priest shall make atonement for him for the sin which he has committed, and he shall be forgiven.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
		</chapter>
	</book>
</crossway-bible>


