<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> 
<crossway-bible>
	<book title="Leviticus" num="2">
		<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03015001">
		</marker>
		<chapter num="15">
			<heading
				>
				Laws About Bodily Discharges
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="1">
				The 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 spoke to Moses and Aaron, saying,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03015002">
			</marker>
			<verse num="2">
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Speak to the people of Israel and say to them, 
				<crossref let="h" cid="c03015002.1">
				</crossref>
				When any man has a discharge from his body,
				<note nid="n03015002.1">
				</note>
				 his discharge is unclean.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03015003">
			</marker>
			<verse num="3">
				And this is the law of his uncleanness for a discharge: whether his body runs with his discharge, or his body is blocked up by his discharge, it is his uncleanness.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03015004">
			</marker>
			<verse num="4">
				Every bed on which the one with the discharge lies shall be unclean, and everything on which he sits shall be unclean.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03015005">
			</marker>
			<verse num="5">
				And anyone who touches his bed 
				<crossref let="i" cid="c03015005.1">
				</crossref>
				shall wash his clothes and 
				<crossref let="j" cid="c03015005.2">
				</crossref>
				bathe himself in water and be unclean until the evening.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03015006">
			</marker>
			<verse num="6">
				And whoever sits on anything on which the one with the discharge has sat shall wash his clothes and bathe himself in water and be unclean until the evening.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03015007">
			</marker>
			<verse num="7">
				And whoever touches the body of the one with the discharge shall wash his clothes and bathe himself in water and be unclean until the evening.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03015008">
			</marker>
			<verse num="8">
				And if the one with the discharge spits on someone who is clean, then he shall wash his clothes and bathe himself in water and be unclean until the evening.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03015009">
			</marker>
			<verse num="9">
				And any saddle on which the one with the discharge rides shall be unclean.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03015010">
			</marker>
			<verse num="10">
				And whoever touches anything that was under him shall be unclean until the evening. And whoever carries such things shall wash his clothes and bathe himself in water and be unclean until the evening.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03015011">
			</marker>
			<verse num="11">
				Anyone whom the one with the discharge touches without having rinsed his hands in water shall wash his clothes and bathe himself in water and be unclean until the evening.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03015012">
			</marker>
			<verse num="12">
				And an 
				<crossref let="k" cid="c03015012.1">
				</crossref>
				earthenware vessel that the one with the discharge touches shall be broken, and every vessel of wood shall be rinsed in water.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03015013">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="13">
				<q class="continue-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				And when the one with a discharge is cleansed of his discharge, then 
				<crossref let="l" cid="c03015013.1">
				</crossref>
				he shall count for himself seven days for his cleansing, and wash his clothes. And he shall bathe his body in fresh water and shall be clean.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03015014">
			</marker>
			<verse num="14">
				And on the eighth day he shall take two 
				<crossref let="m" cid="c03015014.1">
				</crossref>
				turtledoves or two pigeons and come before the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 to the entrance of the tent of meeting and give them to the priest.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03015015">
			</marker>
			<verse num="15">
				And the priest shall use them, 
				<crossref let="n" cid="c03015015.1">
				</crossref>
				one for a sin offering and the other for a burnt offering. 
				<crossref let="o" cid="c03015015.2">
				</crossref>
				And the priest shall make atonement for him before the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 for his discharge.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03015016">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="16">
				<crossref let="p" cid="c03015016.1">
				</crossref>
				<q class="continue-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				If a man has an emission of semen, he shall bathe his whole body in water and be unclean until the evening.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03015017">
			</marker>
			<verse num="17">
				And every garment and every skin on which the semen comes shall be washed with water and be unclean until the evening.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03015018">
			</marker>
			<verse num="18">
				If a man lies with a woman and has an emission of semen, both of them shall bathe themselves in water and 
				<crossref let="q" cid="c03015018.1">
				</crossref>
				be unclean until the evening.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03015019">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="19">
				<q class="continue-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				When a woman has a discharge, and the discharge in her body is blood, she shall be in her menstrual impurity for seven days, and whoever touches her shall be unclean until the evening.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03015020">
			</marker>
			<verse num="20">
				<crossref let="r" cid="c03015020.1">
				</crossref>
				And everything on which she lies during her menstrual impurity shall be unclean. Everything also on which she sits shall be unclean.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03015021">
			</marker>
			<verse num="21">
				And whoever touches her bed shall wash his clothes and bathe himself in water and be unclean until the evening.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03015022">
			</marker>
			<verse num="22">
				And whoever touches anything on which she sits shall wash his clothes and bathe himself in water and be unclean until the evening.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03015023">
			</marker>
			<verse num="23">
				Whether it is the bed or anything on which she sits, when he touches it he shall be unclean until the evening.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03015024">
			</marker>
			<verse num="24">
				And 
				<crossref let="s" cid="c03015024.1">
				</crossref>
				if any man lies with her and her menstrual impurity comes upon him, he shall be unclean seven days, and every bed on which he lies shall be unclean.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03015025">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="25">
				<q class="continue-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				If 
				<crossref let="t" cid="c03015025.1">
				</crossref>
				a woman has a discharge of blood for many days, not at the time of her menstrual impurity, or if she has a discharge beyond the time of her impurity, all the days of the discharge she shall continue in uncleanness. As in the days of her impurity, she shall be unclean.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03015026">
			</marker>
			<verse num="26">
				Every bed on which she lies, all the days of her discharge, shall be to her as the bed of her impurity. And everything on which she sits shall be unclean, as in the uncleanness of her menstrual impurity.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03015027">
			</marker>
			<verse num="27">
				And whoever touches these things shall be unclean, and shall wash his clothes and bathe himself in water and be unclean until the evening.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03015028">
			</marker>
			<verse num="28">
				But 
				<crossref let="u" cid="c03015028.1">
				</crossref>
				if she is cleansed of her discharge, she shall count for herself seven days, and after that she shall be clean.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03015029">
			</marker>
			<verse num="29">
				And on the eighth day she shall take two 
				<crossref let="v" cid="c03015029.1">
				</crossref>
				turtledoves or two pigeons and bring them to the priest, to the entrance of the tent of meeting.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03015030">
			</marker>
			<verse num="30">
				And the priest shall use one for a sin offering and the other for a burnt offering. And the priest shall make atonement for her before the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 for her unclean discharge.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03015031">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="31">
				<q class="continue-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Thus you shall keep the people of Israel separate from their uncleanness, lest they die in their uncleanness by 
				<crossref let="w" cid="c03015031.1">
				</crossref>
				defiling my tabernacle that is in their midst.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03015032">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="32">
				This is the law 
				<crossref let="x" cid="c03015032.1">
				</crossref>
				for him who has a discharge and 
				<crossref let="y" cid="c03015032.2">
				</crossref>
				for him who has an emission of semen, becoming unclean thereby;
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v03015033">
			</marker>
			<verse num="33">
				<crossref let="z" cid="c03015033.1">
				</crossref>
				also for her who is unwell with her menstrual impurity, that is, for anyone, 
				<crossref let="x" cid="c03015033.2">
				</crossref>
				male or 
				<crossref let="a" cid="c03015033.3">
				</crossref>
				female, who has a discharge, and for the 
				<crossref let="b" cid="c03015033.4">
				</crossref>
				man who lies with a woman who is unclean.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
		</chapter>
	</book>
</crossway-bible>


