<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> 
<crossway-bible>
	<book title="Nehemiah" num="15">
		<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v16004001">
		</marker>
		<chapter num="4">
			<heading
				>
				Opposition to the Work
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="1">
				<note nid="n16004001.1">
				</note>
				 Now when 
				<crossref let="q" cid="c16004001.1">
				</crossref>
				Sanballat heard that we were building the wall, he was angry and greatly enraged, and he jeered at the Jews.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v16004002">
			</marker>
			<verse num="2">
				And he said in the presence of his brothers and of the army of 
				<crossref let="r" cid="c16004002.1">
				</crossref>
				Samaria, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				What are these feeble Jews doing? Will they restore it for themselves?
				<note nid="n16004002.1">
				</note>
				 Will they sacrifice? Will they finish up in a day? Will they revive the stones out of the heaps of rubbish, and burned ones at that?
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v16004003">
			</marker>
			<verse num="3">
				<crossref let="q" cid="c16004003.1">
				</crossref>
				Tobiah the Ammonite was beside him, and he said, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Yes, what they are buildingù
				<crossref let="s" cid="c16004003.2">
				</crossref>
				if a fox goes up on it he will break down their stone wall!
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v16004004">
			</marker>
			<verse num="4">
				<crossref let="t" cid="c16004004.1">
				</crossref>
				Hear, O our God, for we are despised. 
				<crossref let="u" cid="c16004004.2">
				</crossref>
				Turn back their taunt on their own heads and give them up to be plundered in a land where they are captives.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v16004005">
			</marker>
			<verse num="5">
				<crossref let="v" cid="c16004005.1">
				</crossref>
				Do not cover their guilt, and let not their sin be blotted out from your sight, for they have provoked you to anger in the presence of the builders.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v16004006">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="6">
				So we built the wall. And all the wall was joined together to half its height, for the people had a mind to work.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v16004007">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="7">
				<note nid="n16004007.1">
				</note>
				 But when 
				<crossref let="q" cid="c16004007.1">
				</crossref>
				Sanballat and Tobiah and the Arabs and the Ammonites and the Ashdodites heard that the repairing of the walls of Jerusalem was going forward and that the breaches were beginning to be closed, they were very angry.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v16004008">
			</marker>
			<verse num="8">
				<crossref let="w" cid="c16004008.1">
				</crossref>
				And they all plotted together to come and fight against Jerusalem and to cause confusion in it.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v16004009">
			</marker>
			<verse num="9">
				And we prayed to our God and set a guard as a protection against them day and night.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v16004010">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="10">
				In Judah it was said,
				<note nid="n16004010.1">
				</note>
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				The strength of those who bear the burdens is failing. There is too much rubble. By ourselves we will not be able to rebuild the wall.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v16004011">
			</marker>
			<verse num="11">
				And our enemies said, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				They will not know or see till we come among them and kill them and stop the work.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v16004012">
			</marker>
			<verse num="12">
				At that time the Jews who lived near them came from all directions and said to us ten times, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				You must return to us.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				<note nid="n16004012.1">
				</note>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v16004013">
			</marker>
			<verse num="13">
				So in the lowest parts of the space behind the wall, in open places, I stationed the people by their clans, with their swords, their spears, and their bows.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v16004014">
			</marker>
			<verse num="14">
				And I looked and arose and said to the nobles and to the officials and to the rest of the people, 
				<crossref let="x" cid="c16004014.1">
				</crossref>
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Do not be afraid of them. Remember the Lord, 
				<crossref let="y" cid="c16004014.2">
				</crossref>
				who is great and awesome, 
				<crossref let="z" cid="c16004014.3">
				</crossref>
				and fight for your brothers, your sons, your daughters, your wives, and your homes.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v16004015">
			</marker>
			<heading
				>
				The Work Resumes
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="15">
				When our enemies heard that it was known to us 
				<crossref let="a" cid="c16004015.1">
				</crossref>
				and that God had frustrated their plan, we all returned to the wall, each to his work.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v16004016">
			</marker>
			<verse num="16">
				From that day on, half of my servants worked on construction, and half held the spears, shields, bows, and 
				<crossref let="b" cid="c16004016.1">
				</crossref>
				coats of mail. And the leaders stood behind the whole house of Judah,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v16004017">
			</marker>
			<verse num="17">
				who were building on the wall. Those who carried burdens were loaded in such a way that each labored on the work with one hand and held his weapon with the other.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v16004018">
			</marker>
			<verse num="18">
				And each of the builders had his sword strapped at his side while he built. The man who sounded the trumpet was beside me.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v16004019">
			</marker>
			<verse num="19">
				And I said to 
				<crossref let="c" cid="c16004019.1">
				</crossref>
				the nobles and to the officials and to the rest of the people, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				The work is great and widely spread, and we are separated on the wall, far from one another.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v16004020">
			</marker>
			<verse num="20">
				In the place where you hear the sound of the trumpet, rally to us there. 
				<crossref let="d" cid="c16004020.1">
				</crossref>
				Our God will fight for us.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v16004021">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="21">
				So we labored at the work, and half of them held the spears from the break of dawn until the stars came out.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v16004022">
			</marker>
			<verse num="22">
				I also said to the people at that time, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Let every man and his servant pass the night within Jerusalem, that they may be a guard for us by night and may labor by day.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v16004023">
			</marker>
			<verse num="23">
				So neither I nor my brothers nor my servants nor the men of the guard who followed me, none of us took off our clothes; 
				<crossref let="e" cid="c16004023.1">
				</crossref>
				each kept his weapon at his right hand.
				<note nid="n16004023.1">
				</note>
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
		</chapter>
	</book>
</crossway-bible>


