<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> 
<crossway-bible>
	<book title="Nehemiah" num="15">
		<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v16013001">
		</marker>
		<chapter num="13">
			<heading
				>
				Nehemiah's Final Reforms
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="1">
				On that day 
				<crossref let="r" cid="c16013001.1">
				</crossref>
				they read from the Book of Moses in the hearing of the people. And in it was found written 
				<crossref let="s" cid="c16013001.2">
				</crossref>
				that no Ammonite or Moabite should ever enter the assembly of God,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v16013002">
			</marker>
			<verse num="2">
				for they did not meet the people of Israel with bread and water, but hired Balaam against them to curse themùyet our God turned the curse into a blessing.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v16013003">
			</marker>
			<verse num="3">
				As soon as the people heard the law, 
				<crossref let="t" cid="c16013003.1">
				</crossref>
				they separated from Israel all 
				<crossref let="u" cid="c16013003.2">
				</crossref>
				those of foreign descent.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v16013004">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="4">
				Now before this, 
				<crossref let="v" cid="c16013004.1">
				</crossref>
				Eliashib the priest, who 
				<crossref let="w" cid="c16013004.2">
				</crossref>
				was appointed over the chambers of the house of our God, and who was related to 
				<crossref let="x" cid="c16013004.3">
				</crossref>
				Tobiah,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v16013005">
			</marker>
			<verse num="5">
				prepared for Tobiah a large chamber where they had previously put the grain offering, the frankincense, the vessels, and the tithes of grain, wine, and oil, 
				<crossref let="y" cid="c16013005.1">
				</crossref>
				which were given by commandment to the Levites, singers, and gatekeepers, and the contributions for the priests.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v16013006">
			</marker>
			<verse num="6">
				While this was taking place, I was not in Jerusalem, for 
				<crossref let="z" cid="c16013006.1">
				</crossref>
				in the thirty-second year of Artaxerxes 
				<crossref let="a" cid="c16013006.2">
				</crossref>
				king of Babylon I went to the king. And after some time I asked leave of the king
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v16013007">
			</marker>
			<verse num="7">
				and came to Jerusalem, and I then discovered the evil that Eliashib had done for Tobiah, 
				<crossref let="b" cid="c16013007.1">
				</crossref>
				preparing for him a chamber in the courts of the house of God.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v16013008">
			</marker>
			<verse num="8">
				And I was very angry, and I threw all the household furniture of Tobiah out of the chamber.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v16013009">
			</marker>
			<verse num="9">
				Then I gave orders, and they 
				<crossref let="c" cid="c16013009.1">
				</crossref>
				cleansed the chambers, and I brought back there the vessels of the house of God, with the grain offering and the frankincense.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v16013010">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="10">
				I also found out that 
				<crossref let="d" cid="c16013010.1">
				</crossref>
				the portions of the Levites had not been given to them, so that the Levites and the singers, who did the work, had fled each 
				<crossref let="e" cid="c16013010.2">
				</crossref>
				to his field.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v16013011">
			</marker>
			<verse num="11">
				<crossref let="f" cid="c16013011.1">
				</crossref>
				So I confronted the officials and said, 
				<crossref let="g" cid="c16013011.2">
				</crossref>
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Why is the house of God forsaken?
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				 And I gathered them together and set them in their stations.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v16013012">
			</marker>
			<verse num="12">
				Then all Judah brought 
				<crossref let="h" cid="c16013012.1">
				</crossref>
				the tithe of the grain, wine, and oil into the storehouses.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v16013013">
			</marker>
			<verse num="13">
				And 
				<crossref let="i" cid="c16013013.1">
				</crossref>
				I appointed as treasurers over the storehouses Shelemiah the priest, Zadok the scribe, and Pedaiah of the Levites, and as their assistant Hanan the son of Zaccur, son of Mattaniah, 
				<crossref let="j" cid="c16013013.2">
				</crossref>
				for they were considered reliable, and their duty was to distribute to their brothers.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v16013014">
			</marker>
			<verse num="14">
				<crossref let="k" cid="c16013014.1">
				</crossref>
				Remember me, O my God, concerning this, and do not wipe out my good deeds that I have done for the house of my God and for his service.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v16013015">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="15">
				In those days I saw in Judah people treading winepresses 
				<crossref let="l" cid="c16013015.1">
				</crossref>
				on the Sabbath, and bringing in heaps of grain and loading them on donkeys, and also wine, grapes, figs, and all kinds of loads, 
				<crossref let="m" cid="c16013015.2">
				</crossref>
				which they brought into Jerusalem on the Sabbath day. And 
				<crossref let="n" cid="c16013015.3">
				</crossref>
				I warned them on the day when they sold food.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v16013016">
			</marker>
			<verse num="16">
				Tyrians also, who lived in the city, brought in fish and all kinds of goods and sold them on the Sabbath to the people of Judah, in Jerusalem itself!
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v16013017">
			</marker>
			<verse num="17">
				<crossref let="o" cid="c16013017.1">
				</crossref>
				Then I confronted the nobles of Judah and said to them, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				What is this evil thing that you are doing, 
				<crossref let="p" cid="c16013017.2">
				</crossref>
				profaning the Sabbath day?
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v16013018">
			</marker>
			<verse num="18">
				<crossref let="q" cid="c16013018.1">
				</crossref>
				Did not your fathers act in this way, and did not our God bring all this disaster
				<note nid="n16013018.1">
				</note>
				 on us and on this city? Now you are bringing more wrath on Israel by profaning the Sabbath.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v16013019">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="19">
				As soon as it 
				<crossref let="r" cid="c16013019.1">
				</crossref>
				began to grow dark at the gates of Jerusalem before the Sabbath, I commanded that the doors should be shut and gave orders that they should not be opened until after the Sabbath. And I stationed some of my servants at the gates, that no load might be brought in on the Sabbath day.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v16013020">
			</marker>
			<verse num="20">
				Then the merchants and sellers of all kinds of wares lodged outside Jerusalem once or twice.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v16013021">
			</marker>
			<verse num="21">
				<crossref let="s" cid="c16013021.1">
				</crossref>
				But I warned them and said to them, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Why do you lodge outside the wall? If you do so again, I will lay hands on you.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				 From that time on they did not come on the Sabbath.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v16013022">
			</marker>
			<verse num="22">
				Then I commanded the Levites 
				<crossref let="t" cid="c16013022.1">
				</crossref>
				that they should purify themselves and come and guard the gates, to keep the Sabbath day holy. 
				<crossref let="u" cid="c16013022.2">
				</crossref>
				Remember this also in my favor, O my God, and spare me according to the greatness of your steadfast love.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v16013023">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="23">
				In those days also I saw the Jews 
				<crossref let="v" cid="c16013023.1">
				</crossref>
				who had married women 
				<crossref let="w" cid="c16013023.2">
				</crossref>
				of Ashdod, 
				<crossref let="x" cid="c16013023.3">
				</crossref>
				Ammon, and 
				<crossref let="x" cid="c16013023.4">
				</crossref>
				Moab.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v16013024">
			</marker>
			<verse num="24">
				And half of their children spoke the language of Ashdod, and they could not speak the language of Judah, but only the language of each people.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v16013025">
			</marker>
			<verse num="25">
				<crossref let="o" cid="c16013025.1">
				</crossref>
				And I confronted them and cursed them and beat some of them and pulled out their hair. 
				<crossref let="y" cid="c16013025.2">
				</crossref>
				And I made them take oath in the name of God, saying, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				You shall not give your daughters to their sons, or take their daughters for your sons or for yourselves.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v16013026">
			</marker>
			<verse num="26">
				<crossref let="z" cid="c16013026.1">
				</crossref>
				Did not Solomon king of Israel sin on account of such women? 
				<crossref let="a" cid="c16013026.2">
				</crossref>
				Among the many nations there was no king like him, and he was 
				<crossref let="b" cid="c16013026.3">
				</crossref>
				beloved by his God, and God made him king over all Israel. Nevertheless, foreign women made even him to sin.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v16013027">
			</marker>
			<verse num="27">
				Shall we then listen to you and do all this great evil and 
				<crossref let="c" cid="c16013027.1">
				</crossref>
				act treacherously against our God by marrying foreign women?
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v16013028">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="28">
				And one of the sons of 
				<crossref let="d" cid="c16013028.1">
				</crossref>
				Jehoiada, the son of 
				<crossref let="e" cid="c16013028.2">
				</crossref>
				Eliashib the high priest, was the son-in-law of 
				<crossref let="f" cid="c16013028.3">
				</crossref>
				Sanballat the Horonite. Therefore I chased him from me.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v16013029">
			</marker>
			<verse num="29">
				<crossref let="g" cid="c16013029.1">
				</crossref>
				Remember them, O my God, because they have desecrated the priesthood 
				<crossref let="h" cid="c16013029.2">
				</crossref>
				and the covenant of the priesthood and the Levites.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v16013030">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="30">
				<crossref let="i" cid="c16013030.1">
				</crossref>
				Thus I cleansed them from everything foreign, and I established the duties of the priests and Levites, each in his work;
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v16013031">
			</marker>
			<verse num="31">
				and I provided 
				<crossref let="j" cid="c16013031.1">
				</crossref>
				for the wood offering 
				<crossref let="k" cid="c16013031.2">
				</crossref>
				at appointed times, and for the firstfruits.

				<end-paragraph
					>
				</end-paragraph>
				<begin-paragraph
					>
				</begin-paragraph>
				<crossref let="l" cid="c16013031.3">
				</crossref>
				Remember me, O my God, for good.

			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
		</chapter>
	</book>
</crossway-bible>


