<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> 
<crossway-bible>
	<book title="Numbers" num="3">
		<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v04030001">
		</marker>
		<chapter num="30">
			<heading
				>
				Men and Vows
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="1">
				Moses spoke to 
				<crossref let="f" cid="c04030001.1">
				</crossref>
				the heads of the tribes of the people of Israel, saying, 
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				This is what the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 has commanded.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v04030002">
			</marker>
			<verse num="2">
				<crossref let="g" cid="c04030002.1">
				</crossref>
				If a man vows a vow to the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				, or 
				<crossref let="h" cid="c04030002.2">
				</crossref>
				swears an oath to bind himself by a pledge, he shall not break his word. 
				<crossref let="i" cid="c04030002.3">
				</crossref>
				He shall do according to all that proceeds out of his mouth.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v04030003">
			</marker>
			<heading
				>
				Women and Vows
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="3">
				<q class="continue-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				If a woman vows a vow to the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 and binds herself by a pledge, while within her father's house in her youth,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v04030004">
			</marker>
			<verse num="4">
				and her father hears of her vow and of her pledge by which she has bound herself and says nothing to her, then all her vows shall stand, and every pledge by which she has bound herself shall stand.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v04030005">
			</marker>
			<verse num="5">
				But if her father opposes her on the day that he hears of it, no vow of hers, no pledge by which she has bound herself shall stand. And the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 will forgive her, because her father opposed her.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v04030006">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="6">
				<q class="continue-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				If she marries a husband, while under her 
				<crossref let="j" cid="c04030006.1">
				</crossref>
				vows or any thoughtless utterance of her lips by which she has bound herself,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v04030007">
			</marker>
			<verse num="7">
				and her husband hears of it and says nothing to her on the day that he hears, then her vows shall stand, and her pledges by which she has bound herself shall stand.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v04030008">
			</marker>
			<verse num="8">
				But if, on the day that her husband comes to hear of it, he opposes her, then he makes void her 
				<crossref let="j" cid="c04030008.1">
				</crossref>
				vow that was on her, and the thoughtless utterance of her lips by which she bound herself. 
				<crossref let="k" cid="c04030008.2">
				</crossref>
				And the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 will forgive her.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v04030009">
			</marker>
			<verse num="9">
				(But any vow of a widow or of a divorced woman, anything by which she has bound herself, shall stand against her.)
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v04030010">
			</marker>
			<verse num="10">
				And if she vowed in her husband's house or bound herself by a pledge with an oath,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v04030011">
			</marker>
			<verse num="11">
				and her husband heard of it and said nothing to her and did not oppose her, then all her vows shall stand, and every pledge by which she bound herself shall stand.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v04030012">
			</marker>
			<verse num="12">
				But if her husband makes them null and void on the day that he hears them, then whatever proceeds out of her lips concerning her vows or concerning her pledge of herself shall not stand. Her husband has made them void, and 
				<crossref let="l" cid="c04030012.1">
				</crossref>
				the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 will forgive her.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v04030013">
			</marker>
			<verse num="13">
				Any vow and any binding oath to afflict herself, her husband may establish,
				<note nid="n04030013.1">
				</note>
				 or her husband may make void.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v04030014">
			</marker>
			<verse num="14">
				But if her husband says nothing to her from day to day, then he establishes all her vows or all her pledges that are upon her. He has established them, because he said nothing to her on the day that he heard of them.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v04030015">
			</marker>
			<verse num="15">
				But if he makes them null and void after he has heard of them, then 
				<crossref let="m" cid="c04030015.1">
				</crossref>
				he shall bear her iniquity.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v04030016">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="16">
				These are the statutes that the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 commanded Moses about a man and his wife and about a father and his daughter while she is in her youth within her father's house.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
		</chapter>
	</book>
</crossway-bible>


