<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> 
<crossway-bible>
	<book title="Numbers" num="3">
		<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v04035001">
		</marker>
		<chapter num="35">
			<heading
				>
				Cities for the Levites
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="1">
				The 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 spoke to Moses in 
				<crossref let="s" cid="c04035001.1">
				</crossref>
				the plains of Moab by the Jordan at Jericho, saying,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v04035002">
			</marker>
			<verse num="2">
				<crossref let="t" cid="c04035002.1">
				</crossref>
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Command the people of Israel to give to the Levites some of the inheritance of their possession as cities for them to dwell in. And you shall give to the Levites pasturelands around the cities.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v04035003">
			</marker>
			<verse num="3">
				The cities shall be theirs to dwell in, and their pasturelands shall be for their cattle and for their livestock and for all their beasts.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v04035004">
			</marker>
			<verse num="4">
				The pasturelands of the cities, which you shall give to the Levites, shall reach from the wall of the city outward a thousand cubits
				<note nid="n04035004.1">
				</note>
				 all around.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v04035005">
			</marker>
			<verse num="5">
				And you shall measure, outside the city, on the east side two thousand cubits, and on the south side two thousand cubits, and on the west side two thousand cubits, and on the north side two thousand cubits, the city being in the middle. This shall belong to them as pastureland for their cities.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v04035006">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="6">
				<q class="continue-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				The cities that you give to the Levites shall be 
				<crossref let="u" cid="c04035006.1">
				</crossref>
				the six cities of refuge, where you shall permit the manslayer to flee, and in addition to them you shall give forty-two cities.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v04035007">
			</marker>
			<verse num="7">
				All the cities that you give to the Levites shall be 
				<crossref let="v" cid="c04035007.1">
				</crossref>
				forty-eight, with their pasturelands.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v04035008">
			</marker>
			<verse num="8">
				And as for the cities that you shall give 
				<crossref let="w" cid="c04035008.1">
				</crossref>
				from the possession of the people of Israel, 
				<crossref let="x" cid="c04035008.2">
				</crossref>
				from the larger tribes you shall take many, and from the smaller tribes you shall take few; each, in proportion to the inheritance that it inherits, shall give of its cities to the Levites.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v04035009">
			</marker>
			<heading
				>
				Cities of Refuge
			</heading>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="9">
				And the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 spoke to Moses, saying,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v04035010">
			</marker>
			<verse num="10">
				<q class="begin-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				Speak to the people of Israel and say to them, 
				<crossref let="y" cid="c04035010.1">
				</crossref>
				When you cross the Jordan into the land of Canaan,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v04035011">
			</marker>
			<verse num="11">
				<crossref let="z" cid="c04035011.1">
				</crossref>
				then you shall select cities to be cities of refuge for you, that the manslayer who kills any person without intent may flee there.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v04035012">
			</marker>
			<verse num="12">
				The cities shall be for you a refuge from the avenger, that the manslayer may not die until he stands before the congregation for judgment.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v04035013">
			</marker>
			<verse num="13">
				And the cities that you give shall be your 
				<crossref let="a" cid="c04035013.1">
				</crossref>
				six cities of refuge.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v04035014">
			</marker>
			<verse num="14">
				<crossref let="b" cid="c04035014.1">
				</crossref>
				You shall give three cities beyond the Jordan, and three cities in the land of Canaan, to be cities of refuge.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v04035015">
			</marker>
			<verse num="15">
				These six cities shall be for refuge for the people of Israel, and 
				<crossref let="c" cid="c04035015.1">
				</crossref>
				for the stranger and for the sojourner among them, that anyone who kills any person without intent may flee there.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v04035016">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="16">
				<crossref let="d" cid="c04035016.1">
				</crossref>
				<q class="continue-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				But if he struck him down with an iron object, so that he died, he is a murderer. The murderer shall be put to death.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v04035017">
			</marker>
			<verse num="17">
				And if he struck him down with a stone tool that could cause death, and he died, he is a murderer. The murderer shall be put to death.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v04035018">
			</marker>
			<verse num="18">
				Or if he struck him down with a wooden tool that could cause death, and he died, he is a murderer. The murderer shall be put to death.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v04035019">
			</marker>
			<verse num="19">
				<crossref let="e" cid="c04035019.1">
				</crossref>
				The avenger of blood shall himself put the murderer to death; when he meets him, he shall put him to death.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v04035020">
			</marker>
			<verse num="20">
				And if he pushed him out of hatred or hurled something at him, 
				<crossref let="f" cid="c04035020.1">
				</crossref>
				lying in wait, so that he died,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v04035021">
			</marker>
			<verse num="21">
				or in enmity struck him down with his hand, so that he died, then he who struck the blow shall be put to death. He is a murderer. 
				<crossref let="e" cid="c04035021.1">
				</crossref>
				The avenger of blood shall put the murderer to death when he meets him.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v04035022">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="22">
				<q class="continue-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				But if he pushed him suddenly without enmity, or hurled anything on him 
				<crossref let="g" cid="c04035022.1">
				</crossref>
				without lying in wait
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v04035023">
			</marker>
			<verse num="23">
				or used a stone that could cause death, and without seeing him dropped it on him, so that he died, though he was not his enemy and did not seek his harm,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v04035024">
			</marker>
			<verse num="24">
				then 
				<crossref let="h" cid="c04035024.1">
				</crossref>
				the congregation shall judge between the manslayer and 
				<crossref let="e" cid="c04035024.2">
				</crossref>
				the avenger of blood, in accordance with these rules.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v04035025">
			</marker>
			<verse num="25">
				And the congregation shall rescue the manslayer from the hand of the avenger of blood, and the congregation shall restore him to his city of refuge to which he had fled, and he shall live in it 
				<crossref let="i" cid="c04035025.1">
				</crossref>
				until the death of the high priest 
				<crossref let="j" cid="c04035025.2">
				</crossref>
				who was anointed with the holy oil.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v04035026">
			</marker>
			<verse num="26">
				But if the manslayer shall at any time go beyond the boundaries of his city of refuge to which he fled,
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v04035027">
			</marker>
			<verse num="27">
				and 
				<crossref let="e" cid="c04035027.1">
				</crossref>
				the avenger of blood finds him outside the boundaries of his city of refuge, and the avenger of blood kills the manslayer, he shall not be guilty of blood.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v04035028">
			</marker>
			<verse num="28">
				For he must remain in his city of refuge 
				<crossref let="i" cid="c04035028.1">
				</crossref>
				until the death of the high priest, but after the death of the high priest the manslayer may return to the land of his possession.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v04035029">
			</marker>
			<verse num="29">
				And these things shall be for 
				<crossref let="k" cid="c04035029.1">
				</crossref>
				a statute and rule for you throughout your generations in all your dwelling places.
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v04035030">
			</marker>
			<begin-paragraph
				>
			</begin-paragraph>
			<verse num="30">
				<q class="continue-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
				If anyone kills a person, the murderer shall be put to death on the 
				<crossref let="l" cid="c04035030.1">
				</crossref>
				evidence of witnesses. But no person shall be put to death on the testimony of one witness.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v04035031">
			</marker>
			<verse num="31">
				Moreover, you shall accept no ransom for the life of a murderer, who is guilty of death, but he shall be put to death.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v04035032">
			</marker>
			<verse num="32">
				And you shall accept no ransom for him who has fled to his city of refuge, that he may return to dwell in the land before the death of the high priest.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v04035033">
			</marker>
			<verse num="33">
				You shall not 
				<crossref let="m" cid="c04035033.1">
				</crossref>
				pollute the land in which you live, for blood 
				<crossref let="m" cid="c04035033.2">
				</crossref>
				pollutes the land, and no atonement can be made for the land for the blood that is shed in it, except 
				<crossref let="n" cid="c04035033.3">
				</crossref>
				by the blood of the one who shed it.
			</verse>
			<marker class="begin-verse" mid="v04035034">
			</marker>
			<verse num="34">
				<crossref let="o" cid="c04035034.1">
				</crossref>
				You shall not defile the land in which you live, in the midst of which I dwell, 
				<crossref let="p" cid="c04035034.2">
				</crossref>
				for I the 
				<span class="divine-name">
					Lord
				</span>
				 dwell in the midst of the people of Israel.
				<q class="end-double" qid="" from="" to="">
				</q>
			</verse>
			<end-paragraph
				>
			</end-paragraph>
		</chapter>
	</book>
</crossway-bible>


